<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Epidemiology | mesothelioma</title>
    <link>/mesothelioma/syntax_summary/epidemiology/</link>
      <atom:link href="/mesothelioma/syntax_summary/epidemiology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Epidemiology</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>BioHub - UFPE</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/mesothelioma/images/icon_hu3365e08ad5ef6cb6d886bc511b9ad2b3_313689_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Epidemiology</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/syntax_summary/epidemiology/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epidemiology Sentence Context</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/syntax_summary/epidemiology/info/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/mesothelioma/syntax_summary/epidemiology/info/</guid>
      <description> 

&lt;script src=&#34;/mesothelioma/mesotheliomarmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;font-size:12px&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Table 1.&lt;/strong&gt; Analysis of context sentence of 112 absracts clustered as Epidemiology.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;table table-striped&#34; style=&#34;width: auto !important; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
Title
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
Gene Context Sentence
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
ePubDate
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10441898&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The hazards of chrysotile asbestos: a critical review.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Clinical and epidemiologic studies have established incontrovertibly that chrysotile causes cancer of the lung, malignant mesothelioma of the pleura and peritoneum, cancer of the larynx and certain gastrointestinal cancers.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1999-09-23
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11273069&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Genetic-susceptibility factor and malignant mesothelioma in the Cappadocian region of Turkey.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We constructed genetic epidemiology maps to test whether some villagers were genetically predisposed to mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2001-03-29
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11836665&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The epidemiology of mesothelioma.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
This review will deal with the epidemiology of mesothelioma with particular attention to the studies that elucidate the impact of various asbestos fiber types on the etiology of the disease.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2002-03-05
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11847028&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;[Current insights in malignant pleural mesothelioma].&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
This article tries to summarize current insights concerning epidemiology, diagnosis and treatment of MPM.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2002-03-21
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1226507&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The epidermiologic relationship between pleural mesothelioma and asbestos exposure.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The investigation covers characteristic epidemiologic features and the possibility of the mesothelioma being connected with occupational or other exposure to asbestos.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1976-08-02
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12475867&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Malignant mesothelioma due to environmental exposure to asbestos: follow-up of a Turkish cohort living in a rural area.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
A field-based epidemiologic study.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2003-01-29
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12581569&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Serum anti-p53 autoantibodies in pleural malignant mesothelioma, lung cancer and non-neoplastic lung diseases.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In order to evaluate the association of p53-Abs with pleuropulmonary diseases, four groups of subjects were analyzed by ELISA for serum p53-Abs, in the framework of a molecular epidemiologic study.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2003-10-06
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12765873&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Exposure to brake dust and malignant mesothelioma: a study of 10 cases with mineral fiber analyses.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Epidemiologic and industrial hygiene studies have failed to demonstrate an increased risk of MM in brake workers.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2003-08-27
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/14644341&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Implementation of a molecular epidemiology approach to human pleural malignant mesothelioma.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
This approach, known as molecular epidemiology has a great potential in the study of MM, contributing to the understanding of susceptibility factors, to the evaluation of cancer risk in people occupationally or environmentally exposed to carcinogens, and to the enhancement of diagnosis and therapy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2004-01-21
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15087673&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Well-differentiated papillary mesothelioma of the pleura: a series of 24 cases.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We report 24 cases of pleural WDPM and compared their histologic, epidemiologic, and clinical features with those of classic mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2004-05-05
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15117424&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pathogenesis of malignant mesothelioma.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The link between asbestos and MM has been firmly established through numerous epidemiologic studies conducted during the past 40 years.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2004-09-02
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15654178&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Malignant pleural mesothelioma.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Since then, the incidence has appeared to increase, and numerous epidemiologic studies have confirmed that exposure to asbestos in a variety of settings and occupations is the most significant risk factor for the development of malignant pleural mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2005-02-25
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15724226&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;[Management of malignant pleural effusions].&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
A special emphasis is put on the epidemiology, diagnosis, treatment, and prognosis of malignant effusions in patients with lung and breast carcinomas, and with lymphomas.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2005-04-11
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1580261&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pleural malignant mesothelioma in Tuscany, Italy (1970-1988): I. Anatomo-pathologic aspects.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Therefore, epidemiologic investigations which exclude an accurate and rigorous reevaluation of the histologic slides have to be considered unreliable, unless the data come from a specialized medical center experienced in this type of pathology.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1992-06-10
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15941656&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Malignant mesothelioma in Hong Kong.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We conducted the first systematic study of the epidemiology of mesothelioma in Hong Kong from 1988 to May 2002 by reviewing medical records. […] Restricting analysis to 48 patients with accessible medical records and using 67 occupational asbestosis patients for comparison, the epidemiology of mesothelioma in Hong Kong shares similarities with the literature: mean age of 63 years upon diagnosis, mean latency of 46 years, median survival of 9.5 months, male predominance, selective presentation among women, high prevalence among workers in ships and dockyards, predominantly epithelioid type, lower prevalence of asbestos bodies, and negative association with pleural plaques.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2006-06-19
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1643319&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Chemotherapy for intrathoracic cancer in dogs and cats.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
This article reviews the epidemiology, clinical features, and diagnosis of pulmonary neoplasia; mediastinal neoplasia, particularly thymoma; and pleural neoplasia, with emphasis on mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1992-09-04
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16457428&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Malignant mesothelioma and the working environment: the viewpoint of the occupational physician.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The main outcomes of OP activity are the high percentage of direct interviews, individual case management, expert exposure assessment, etiological diagnosis, counselling, medico-legal assistance, better knowledge of occupational risks, enhanced cooperation among health professionals (oncologists, pathologists, surgeons, pneumologists, general practitioners and OP), important contribution to Registries and to epidemiology (estimates of attributable risks, incidence, survival rates), with positive social and scientific consequences (insurance agencies, trade union organizations, public events, teaching opportunities).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2006-03-23
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16806404&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Nature and extent of the exposure to fibrous amphiboles in Biancavilla.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Epidemiology suggested an environmental contamination by amphibole fibres rather than risks related to a specific occupational activity.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2006-11-13
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1712750&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Atypical mesothelial hyperplasia associated with bronchogenic carcinoma.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
This combination of reactive and malignant processes should be appreciated, since pleural carcinomatosis and diffuse malignant mesothelioma must be separated for clinical and epidemiologic reasons.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1991-08-20
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17393666&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Non-occupational malignant pleural mesothelioma due to asbestos and non-asbestos fibres.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Non occupational MPM in subjects living in areas contaminated by a variety of asbestos and non asbestos fibres has been well documented through a number of epidemiologic studies including cases series, case-control studies, and a cohort study.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2007-07-18
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17534182&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The risk of mesothelioma from exposure to chrysotile asbestos.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
New analyses of occupational epidemiologic studies for highly exposed workers show a substantially lower potency and suggest an empiric threshold for chrysotile compared with amphibole asbestos.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2007-09-27
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18197921&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Epidemiology of pleural mesothelioma in a population with non-occupational asbestos exposure.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
This study describes the epidemiology of malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM) in a rural population with environmental asbestos exposure.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2008-05-07
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18235408&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;[Pleural mesothelioma: impact of the staging for the therapeutic strategy].&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Besides new findings for the epidemiology of the disease, medico-social impact for patients, the knowledge of biological parameters for diagnosis, prognosis and future therapeutic targets as well, the early diagnosis of the disease mainly based on more extended practice of thoracoscopy allows in association with new imaging techniques a careful staging of the disease and consequently new therapeutic implications.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2008-05-21
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18409881&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;[Malignant pleuric mesothelioma in Sicily. Epidemiologic observations during the time 1998-2005].&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We have examined the epidemiologic data of the period 1988-1997 and 1998-2005 through the consultation of the Mesothelioma Sicilian Register; Mesothelioma Italian Register and of the available documentation in the Health Superior Institute.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2008-07-25
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18506411&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;[Erionite-induced pleural plaques. Exposition to urban pollution in a female Turkish migrant in Germany].&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
For epidemiologic considerations discussed referring to current literature, a growing incidence of this type of disease in migrants from high-risk areas must be reckoned with in Germany, even without exposition to asbestos.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2008-11-04
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18520266&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mesothelioma due to environmental exposure to erionite in Turkey.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The data obtained recently on the epidemiology, etiology, and pathogenesis of the mesothelioma due to erionite exposure in Turkey are described.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2008-09-04
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18709470&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mesothelioma epidemiology, carcinogenesis, and pathogenesis.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
This estimate is an extrapolation based on information available from the Surveillance, Epidemiology and End Results (SEER) Program that collects information on approximately 12% of the US population.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2009-04-24
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18990743&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The CREST biorepository: a tool for molecular epidemiology and translational studies on malignant mesothelioma, lung cancer, and other respiratory tract diseases.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Demographic, clinical, and epidemiologic information is collected for each subject and processed in a dedicated database. […] The CREST biorepository is a valuable tool for molecular epidemiology and translational studies. […] The CREST experience suggests that the presence of limited resources can be overcome by the biorepository specialization, the high quality of the epidemiologic information, and the variety of samples.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2009-02-10
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19535165&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Impact of malignant mesothelioma in Taiwan: a 27-year review of population-based cancer registry data.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
To describe the epidemiologic characteristics of malignant mesothelioma (MM) in Taiwan; to evaluate the impact of the condition.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2010-09-01
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1990961&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cellular and molecular basis of the asbestos-related diseases.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Yet epidemiologic studies point toward long amphiboles as having greater mesothelioma risk.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1991-03-07
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2019171&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Metsovo lung outside Metsovo. Endemic pleural calcifications in the ophiolite belts of Greece.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
These findings suggest that “Metsovo lung” occurs in several areas of Greece and has similar etiology and epidemiology.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1991-05-30
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20466560&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Malignant pleural mesothelioma: the standard of care and challenges for future management.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In an introductory section, the etiology, epidemiology, presentation, diagnosis and staging of MPM will be reviewed.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2011-07-19
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20798014&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Incidence of extrapleural malignant mesothelioma and asbestos exposure, from the Italian national register.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The epidemiology of extrapleural malignant mesothelioma is rarely discussed and the risk of misdiagnosis and the very low incidence complicate the picture.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2011-06-06
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20871264&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Frequency of use and predictors of cancer-directed surgery in the management of malignant pleural mesothelioma in a community-based (Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results [SEER]) population.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results database was searched from 1990 to 2004.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2011-02-03
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20975379&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Malignant pleural mesothelioma: a population-based study of survival.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
A total of 9701 patients with malignant pleural mesothelioma, diagnosed from 1973 to 2006, were retrospectively analyzed using the population-based surveillance, epidemiology, and end results database.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2011-02-17
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21141345&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mesothelioma and asbestos, fifty years of evidence: Chris Wagner and the contribution of the Italian occupational medicine community.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In particular, his article clearly demonstrated the existence of a typical cancer of the mesothelium, expressing three fundamental principles of the epidemiology of occupational cancer: association with the carcinogen, latency and individual susceptibility. […] Wagner’s 1960 paper can be considered as a milestone not only in the history of occupational and environmental health, but also in the evolution of other medical disciplines such as epidemiology, pathology and oncology.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2011-02-03
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21309996&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Asbestos-related disease.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
This review provides insight into the history and epidemiology of asbestos-related disease in Australia and discusses relevant clinical aspects in their diagnosis and management.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2011-09-20
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2139623&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;[Occupational morbidity and mortality in malignant neoplasms among persons professionally exposed to asbestos dust].&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
This has been confirmed through occupational diseases’ analysis and new data on malignant neoplasms epidemiology among workers engaged in machine processing of asbestos-moulded machine parts. […] This necessitates further epidemiologic studies to be performed at similar plants.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1990-06-07
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21739769&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Malignant pleural mesothelioma: clinicopathologic and survival characteristic in a consecutive series of 40 patients.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In this study, 40 patients with a definitive diagnosis, who had been followed up for at least 3 years were studied according to these: epidemiologic factors, stage and pathological types, treatment method and complications, and by using factors that influence patients survival, we evaluated them statistically.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2011-09-15
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22166295&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;[Mortality results in SENTIERI Project].&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The procedures and results of the evidence evaluation are presented in a 2010 Supplement of Epidemiology &amp;amp; Prevention devoted to SENTIERI.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2012-04-30
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22644294&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Prognosis and prognostic factors of patients with mesothelioma: a population-based study.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
It is important to regularly update survival estimates of patients with malignant mesothelioma as prognosis may vary according to epidemiologic factors and diagnostic and therapeutic management.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2012-09-07
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22666659&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Investigational approaches for mesothelioma.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In an introductory section, the etiology, epidemiology, natural history, and standard of care treatment for MPM will be discussed.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2012-08-23
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22668748&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Malignant pleural mesothelioma in US automotive mechanics: reported vs expected number of cases from 1975 to 2007.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Our findings are consistent with the numerous epidemiology studies that have found no increased risk of MPM in auto mechanics.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2013-01-08
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2272325&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Human epidemiology: a review of fiber type and characteristics in the development of malignant and nonmalignant disease.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Consideration of the human epidemiology of diseases arising from exposure to naturally occurring and man-made mineral fibers encompasses the several forms of asbestos (chrysotile, crocidolite, amosite, anthophyllite, tremolite-actinolite), other naturally occurring silicates (talc, sepiolite, erionite, attapulgite, vermiculite, and wollastonite), and man-made mineral fibers (glass continuous filament, glass/rock/slag insulation wools, ceramic and other refractory fibers, and glass microfibers).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1991-02-28
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22969926&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CREST biorepository for translational studies on malignant mesothelioma, lung cancer and other respiratory tract diseases: Informatics infrastructure and standardized annotation.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Advances in molecular epidemiology and translational research have led to the need for biospecimen collection.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2019-11-20
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23126055&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;[Pleural mesothelioma–case report].&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Clinical presentation also included metabolic disorders and deep vein thrombosis, and the patient’s epidemiologic history was negative, so diagnostic procedures including pleurocentesis were directed towards detection of the possible malignant disease.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2012-11-20
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23244069&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Malignant mesothelioma in Eastern Asia.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The cancer epidemiology in Eastern Asia differs deeply from that seen in Western countries, an indication of differences in etiologic factors of cancer as well as in co-factors.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2013-06-04
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23580457&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;[Epidemiological and occupational medicine aspects of pleural mesothelioma].&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Of particular interest is the development of mesothelioma epidemiology.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2013-11-22
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23711077&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Asbestos and the lung in the 21st century: an update.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Over recent years, there have been changes in the epidemiology of mesothelioma, in clinical management of ARDs and developments in new techniques for early detection of malignancy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2014-09-29
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23879063&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pleural mesothelioma: epidemiological and public health issues. Report from the Second Italian Consensus Conference on Pleural Mesothelioma.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Italy shows one of the highest incidence of MM and developed a network of specialized cancer registries in order to monitor disease occurrence and describe its epidemiology in details. […] Besides the main consensus report summarizing the contribution of the different expertises, that was published elsewhere, the participants in ‘Public Health and Epidemiology’ section decided to report in major details the evidence and the conclusions regarding epidemiology, causative mechanisms and the public health impact of the disease.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2013-09-03
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24225007&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;[Malignant pleural mesothelioma: 2013 state of the art].&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
MPM epidemiology shows a rising incidence among females, whereas an incidence plateau has been reached for males in France.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2014-02-18
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24448702&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The diagnosis of thoracic malignant mesothelioma: practical considerations and recent developments.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We review the epidemiology, clinical presentation, and imaging studies in patients with malignant mesothelioma, and then present a practical approach to the diagnosis using the cytologic features for malignancy and whether there is an epithelioid or spindled morphology; four main scenarios are discussed.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2014-07-08
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24868221&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pleural mesothelioma: an institutional experience of 66 cases.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Epidemiologic information was not available in most cases, and only one patient was confirmed to have a history of asbestos exposure.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2014-05-28
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24928677&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Women with malignant pleural mesothelioma have a threefold better survival rate than men.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
All pathologically confirmed cases of MPM in the Surveillance, Epidemiology and End Results database from 1973 to 2009 were evaluated.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2014-11-03
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2531313&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;[The carcinogenic effect of asbestos].&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
After a brief outline of the epidemiology of these diseases the carcinogenic effects of asbestos on the cellular and subcellular level are described.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1989-12-27
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25331029&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Advances in malignant peritoneal mesothelioma.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The present study is a review of literatures focusing on the advances in epidemiology, clinical presentations, radiological features, diagnosis, misdiagnosis, management, and prognostic factors of malignant peritoneal mesothelioma (MPM) occurred in the past decades.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2015-09-02
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25380601&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mesothelioma patients with germline BAP1 mutations have 7-fold improved long-term survival.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We compared survival among germline BAP1 mutation MM patients with that of all MM (N = 10 556) recorded in the United States Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results (SEER) data from 1973 to 2010.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2015-03-17
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25726562&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Malignant pleural mesothelioma: history, controversy and future of a manmade epidemic.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Industrialisation demanded increased mining and refining in the 20th century, and in 1960, Wagner, Sleggs and Marchand from South Africa linked asbestos to mesothelioma, paving the way to the current knowledge of the aetiology, epidemiology and biology of malignant pleural mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2015-12-04
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25791825&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Impact of mesothelioma histologic subtype on outcomes in the Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results database.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Overall survival of patients with stage I-III epithelioid, sarcomatoid, and biphasic MPM in the Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results database from 2004-2010 was evaluated using multivariate Cox proportional hazards models.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2015-08-12
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25863904&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Demographics, management and survival of patients with malignant pleural mesothelioma in the National Lung Cancer Audit in England and Wales.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Our data provide a large scale, detailed assessment of MPM epidemiology, treatment choices and outcomes.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2016-02-03
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25988069&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Localized malignant pleural mesothelioma with renal metastasis.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Its epidemiology, biology, natural history and optimal treatment are poorly understood.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2015-05-19
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26063951&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Frequency of Surgery in Black Patients with Malignant Pleural Mesothelioma.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
All cases of pathologically proven MPM were identified in the Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results (SEER) database.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2016-02-23
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26202904&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Distinctive clinical characteristics of malignant mesothelioma in young patients.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results (SEER) database was used to extract mesothelioma cases (1990-2010).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2016-04-29
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26384258&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;III Italian Consensus Conference on Malignant Mesothelioma of the Pleura. Epidemiology, Public Health and Occupational Medicine related issues.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
This report presents the conclusions of the ‘Epidemiology, Public Health and Occupational Medicine’ section.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2016-02-04
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2687807&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Malignant pleural mesothelioma.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
This article explores the epidemiology and etiology of the disease, offers a summary of current treatment options, and discusses nursing strategies.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1990-01-25
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26900461&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Peritoneal mesothelioma metastasis to the tongue - Comparison with 8 pleural mesothelioma reports with tongue metastases.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We briefly surveyed the American Surveillance Epidemiology and End Results (SEER) database, and the British Cancer Research UK database for the latest trends in MM incidence.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2016-02-22
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27236386&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Impact of Age on Long-Term Outcomes of Surgery for Malignant Pleural Mesothelioma.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Overall survival (OS) of patients younger than 70 and 70 years or older with Stage I to III MPM who underwent cancer-directed surgery or nonoperative management in the Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results database (2004-2010) was evaluated using multivariable Cox proportional hazard models and propensity score-matched analysis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2017-07-31
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27325080&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Comments on the Causation of Malignant Mesothelioma: Rebutting the False Concept That Recent Exposures to Asbestos Do Not Contribute to Causation of Mesothelioma.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The Collegium Ramazzini examined this claim and compared it with the findings of the Epidemiology and Public Health Working Group of the Second Italian Consensus Conference on Pleural Mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2018-01-12
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27325621&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Malignant Mesothelioma in a Motor Vehicle Mechanic.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
While there remains a body of negative epidemiology that fails to find an increased risk of disease among auto workers, those data must be approached with caution.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2018-05-09
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27644679&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mesotheliomas in Lebanon: Witnessing a Change in Epidemiology.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Compared to the previous study (1991-2000), substantial changes in the epidemiology of mesothelioma in Lebanon were observed, such as an increase in peritoneal localizations and a lower correlation with Chekka region asbestos contamination.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2017-01-24
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27705546&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Five years update on relationships between malignant pleural mesothelioma and exposure to asbestos and other elongated mineral particles.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
During the past 5 years, new findings have been published on the etiology, epidemiology, molecular changes, and innovative treatments of malignant pleural mesothelioma. […] This review aims to update the findings of recent investigations on etiology, epidemiology, and molecular changes with a focus on (1) attributable risk of asbestos exposure in men and women and (2) coexposure to other minerals and other elongated mineral particles or high aspect ratio nanoparticles.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2017-05-26
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27822122&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mesothelioma in the United States: a Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results (SEER)-Medicare investigation of treatment patterns and overall survival.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The purpose of this investigation was to describe mesothelioma patient characteristics, treatment patterns, and overall survival (OS) utilizing the National Cancer Institute’s Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results-Medicare database.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2019-11-20
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27903668&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Malignant pleural mesothelioma: an update on investigation, diagnosis and treatment.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
There is a global epidemic of malignant pleural mesothelioma underway, and incidence rates are predicted to peak in the next few years.This article summarises the epidemiology and pathogenesis of malignant pleural mesothelioma, before describing some key factors in the patient experience and outlining common symptoms.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2017-04-12
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2792062&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Lung asbestos burden in shipyard and construction workers with mesothelioma: comparison with burdens in subjects with asbestosis or lung cancer.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Although mesothelioma is generally considered to be caused by asbestos, epidemiologic studies indicate that some cases have another cause.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1989-11-07
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28044200&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Role of postoperative radiotherapy in the management of malignant pleural mesothelioma : A propensity score matching of the SEER database.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
MPM patients diagnosed between 2000 and 2013 were identified from the SEER (Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results) database.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2017-04-10
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28527639&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Epidemiology of mesothelioma of the pericardium and tunica vaginalis testis.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
This review provides a better understanding of the epidemiology of mesothelioma of these extrapleural sites. […] We conducted a systematic review of the epidemiologic and clinical literature on pericardial mesothelioma and mesothelioma of the TVT. […] Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results cancer registry data to describe incidence patterns of these malignancies. […] An etiologic role of asbestos exposure has been hypothesized for pericardial and TVT mesotheliomas, but no analytical case-control epidemiologic studies exist to test this relationship. […] In the absence of analytic epidemiologic studies, the etiologic role of environmental risk factors for mesothelioma of the pericardium and TVT remains elusive.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2018-03-21
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28660871&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Increase of exposure and event acceleration.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
This paper suggests that the concept of anticipation measurable through epidemiologic data has to do exclusively with the anticipation of a frequency indicator (more occurrencies and anticipated occurrencies are indistinguishable and alternative concepts) but not with the acceleration of the biological process in individual cases. […] In causal terms, without a biological support it is not possible to infer from the epidemiologic results if a causal model is in action with no, all, or some of cases anticipated.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2018-08-07
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/286826&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Malignant mesotheliomas in a small village in the Anatolian region of Turkey: an epidemiologic study.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
An epidemiologic and cause-related study was done in Tuzköy, a small village in the city of Nevşehir, in the Anatolian region of Turkey.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1979-09-01
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28706904&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Malignant peritoneal mesothelioma: a review.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We will review the epidemiology of MPM and discuss diagnostic and treatment strategies.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2019-11-20
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28713670&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;i&gt;In vitro&lt;/i&gt; experimental models of mesothelioma revisited.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Epidemiologic data suggest that this malignancy has not abated despite increasingly strict environmental regulations on asbestos, the putative causative agent for sporadic cases.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2019-11-20
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28884745&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Clinicopathologic and genetic characteristics of young patients with pleural diffuse malignant mesothelioma.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Recent epidemiologic studies have shown differences between young and older mesothelioma patients, but the biology of pleural mesothelioma in young patients is poorly understood.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2019-01-07
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29050965&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The revised staging system for malignant pleural mesothelioma based on surveillance, epidemiology, and end results database.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We retrieved MPM data from Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results database (1973-2014).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2018-06-20
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29110839&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Challenging a dogma; AJCC 8th staging system is not sufficient to predict outcomes of patients with malignant pleural mesothelioma.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The current analysis aims to evaluate its performance in a population-based setting among patients recorded within the surveillance, epidemiology and end results (SEER) database.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2018-06-25
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29191582&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Patterns of care and survival among patients with malignant mesothelioma in the United States.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
A random sample of patients diagnosed with histologically confirmed mesothelioma in 2011, as reported to the National Cancer Institute’s Surveillance Epidemiology and End Results program, were included.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2018-07-05
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29206890&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Validation of the diagnosis of mesothelioma and BAP1 protein expression in a cohort of asbestos textile workers from Northern Italy.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Diagnosis of mesothelioma based on death certificate is subject to misclassification, which may bias the results of epidemiology studies.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2019-04-01
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29223422&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;National Trends in the Epidemiology of Malignant Pleural Mesothelioma: A National Cancer Data Base Study.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
This study examined the national trends in the epidemiology, national treatment patterns, and survival of patients with this disease.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2018-10-26
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29269563&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The epidemiology of malignant mesothelioma in women: gender differences and modalities of asbestos exposure.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The epidemiology of gender differences for mesothelioma incidence has been rarely discussed in national case lists.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2019-07-29
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29282508&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A Nomogram to Predict Prognosis in Malignant Pleural Mesothelioma.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Data from Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results database (1973-2014) on MPM were screened and retrieved.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2018-09-26
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29303291&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;[Malign pleural mesothelioma - so far an undefeated tumor].&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
However even the combined therapy with adjuvant or neoadjuvant chemotherapy or radiotherapy has not considerably extended survival.Key words: diagnostics - epidemiology - malign pleural mesothelioma - therapy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2018-04-17
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29480760&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Malignant Mesothelioma and Its Non-Asbestos Causes.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Carbon nanotubes can also induce mesotheliomas in animals but there are no human epidemiologic data that shed light on this issue. […] Although SV40 can induce mesotheliomas in animals, in humans the epidemiologic data are against a causative role.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2019-06-24
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29707353&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Prospective registry database of patients with malignant mesothelioma: directions for a future Japanese registry-based lung cancer study.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The Japanese Joint Committee of Lung Cancer Registry (JJCLCR) employs a project of prospective registry database of patients in Japan with MPM in order to clarify MPM’s epidemiology, current management practices, and prognosis and also to investigate the potential capabilities to target the best patients for therapy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2019-11-20
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29719805&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Malignant mesothelioma presenting as recurrent hydro-pneumothorax: An atypical case presentation and literature review.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
While this corresponds with the examined case, and suggests that the presence of hydro-pneumothorax implies a high-grade tumor and significant tissue invasion, and therefore poor prognosis similar to that of stage 4 disease, it differs from more generalized case reviews of MPM, most importantly in their anatomical descriptions, prognostic indicators, and epidemiologic tendencies.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2019-11-20
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29916419&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mesothelioma in Italy: the Casale Monferrato model to a national epidemiological surveillance system.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The purpose of the present paper is to review the origin and development of the epidemiology of mesothelioma in Italy, starting with the detection and investigation of the major outbreak of the disease observed in Casale Monferrato, Piedmont Region.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2018-11-14
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30375909&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Malignant pleural mesothelioma in Finland: regional and gender variation.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Aim of this study is to identify modern epidemiology and assess equality in care.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2019-06-11
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30951250&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Survival analysis via nomogram of surgical patients with malignant pleural mesothelioma in the Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results database.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We retrospectively analyzed data from the Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results database from 2004 to 2014 to identify the key factors affecting the prognosis of surgically treated MPM patients.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2020-06-29
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31403031&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Association Between Simian Virus 40 and Human Tumors.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The main data on (i) the biology and genetics of SV40; (ii) the epidemiology of SV40 in the general population, (iii) the mechanisms of SV40 transformation; (iv) the putative role of SV40 in the onset/progression of specific human tumors, and (v) its association with other human diseases are reported in this review.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2020-02-25
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32626907&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Comments on a recent case-control study of malignant mesothelioma of the pericardium and the tunica vaginalis testis.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
As the first case-control study of malignant mesothelioma of the pericardium and the tunica vaginalis testis (mTVT), the paper by Marinaccio et al (1) is potentially an important epidemiologic contribution. […] In an earlier study, Marinaccio et al (10) remarked on the absence of pericardial mesothelioma and mTVT in industries with the highest exposures to asbestos, saying, “[t]he absence of exposures in the shipbuilding, railway and asbestos-cement industries … for all the 67 pericardial and testicular cases is noteworthy but not easy to interpret.” By contrast, Marinaccio et al (1) stated, “[t]he economic sectors more frequently associated with asbestos exposure were construction, steel mills, metal-working industry, textile industry and agriculture.” The possibility of exposure in the “agriculture economic sector” was not mentioned in Marinaccio et al (10) and appears not to have been considered in previous epidemiologic studies in Italy. […] In general, epidemiologic studies indicate that farmers and agricultural workers are not at increased risk of developing mesothelioma (eg, 11-17). […] Modern Epidemiology. […] Mesothelioma trends in the United States: an update based on Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results Program data for 1973 through 2003. […] Epidemiology of mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2020-07-06
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32682189&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Malignant pleural mesothelioma: Treatment patterns and outcomes from the Spanish Lung Cancer Group.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Patients diagnosed with malignant mesothelioma of the pleura were recorded in an anonymous online database (BEMME, Epidemiologic Spanish Malignant Mesothelioma Database) from June 2008 through May 2013.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2020-07-31
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/3303386&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The pleural manifestations of asbestos exposure.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Pleural abnormalities are the most common disease manifestations of asbestos exposure and have both clinical and epidemiologic implications. […] The presence of typical pleural changes can serve as a reliable marker for asbestos exposure in epidemiologic studies.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1987-08-28
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/3689066&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Malignant mesothelioma with occupational and environmental asbestos exposure in an Illinois community hospital.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Clinical, radiologic, pathologic, and epidemiologic data on 32 patients with diffuse malignant mesothelioma (DMM) diagnosed between 1968 and 1984 at a 427-bed community hospital in Berwyn, Ill, were reviewed.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1988-01-04
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/6316591&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;First report of asbestos-related diseases in Hong Kong.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The problem of asbestos related diseases has however been little considered and further epidemiologic studies are warranted.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1984-01-07
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/6329002&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fiber size and number in amphibole asbestos-induced mesothelioma.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Comparison of these data with epidemiologic and experimental predictions of carcinogenic size ranges for mesothelioma induction implies that either the carcinogenic size range is much broader than has been claimed (in particular, fibers considerably shorter than 8 mu and broader than 0.05 mu can produce mesothelioma), or, alternately, that extraordinarily small absolute numbers of fibers in certain size ranges can induce tumors in humans.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1984-07-12
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/6331632&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Non-asbestos-related malignant mesothelioma. A review.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
It is believed that sufficient evidence exists to suggest that non-asbestos agents can induce malignant mesotheliomas in man, and additional epidemiologic studies in this area are needed.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1984-09-06
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/697191&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Malignant mesothelioma arising after direct application of asbestos and fiber glass to the pericardium.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Development of mesothelioma in laboratory animals has been reported after intrapleural deposition of asbestos and other fibers, but in humans, the link between exposure to asbestos and mesothelioma has always been based on epidemiologic data and the retrospective finding of asbestos in tissues.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1978-11-18
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/6993202&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mesothelioma in man and experimental animals.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Animal experimentation has supported epidemiologic conclusions and revealed the phenomenon of fiber carcinogenesis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1980-09-23
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/7559738&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Lack of apparent excess of malignant mesothelioma but increased overall malignancies of peritoneal cavity in Japanese autopsies with Thorotrast injection into blood vessels.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Recently, however, German and Danish epidemiologic studies have shown excess mesotheliomas in the pleura and peritoneum that are unlikely to have been heavily irradiated by alpha particles.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1995-11-22
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8497827&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Malignant mesothelioma in women.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Malignant mesothelioma reportedly shows different epidemiology and pathology in females, and a proportion are believed to arise spontaneously.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1993-06-23
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8542156&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Black spots concentrate oncogenic asbestos fibers in the parietal pleura. Thoracoscopic and mineralogic study.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Epidemiologic and pathologic data demonstrate that malignant mesothelioma occurs preferentially after exposure to long amphibole asbestos fibers.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1996-02-13
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8608519&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Post-irradiation malignant mesothelioma.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Data from the National Cancer Institute’s Surveillance, Epidemiology and End Results Program and the Connecticut Tumor Registry were evaluated for cases of malignant mesothelioma of the pleura occurring in patients with a previous cancer. […] One hundred forty-two patients were identified in the epidemiologic survey.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1996-05-28
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8966273&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;[Malignant mesothelioma of the pleura: correlations between thoracoscopy and radiology].&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The frequency of malignant pleural mesothelioma has increased greatly in the past three decades; it is a tumor of great clinical, epidemiologic and therapeutical interest.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1996-11-29
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9307196&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Incidence of malignant pleural mesothelioma after thoracic radiotherapy.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The authors performed a retrospective cohort study utilizing 251,750 women registered with breast carcinoma in the Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results Program of the U.S.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1997-10-08
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9497555&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;[Malignant mesothelioma of the pleura with etiological association to asbestos: report of 3 clinical cases].&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
These three cases seem to confirm the existence of the epidemiologic association with asbestos exposure in our country.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1998-05-11
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terms to cluster Epidemiology Abstract</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/syntax_summary/epidemiology/terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/mesothelioma/syntax_summary/epidemiology/terms/</guid>
      <description> 

&lt;script src=&#34;/mesothelioma/mesotheliomarmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;font-size:12px&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Table 2.&lt;/strong&gt; 4 terms used to create the Epidemiology Category and its counts.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;table table-striped&#34; style=&#34;width: auto !important; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
Term
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
Count
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Epidemiologic
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
148
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Epidemiology
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
73
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Health Services Research
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
NA
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Pharmacoepidemiology
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
NA
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
