<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mesothelioma</title>
    <link>/mesothelioma/drugpanel/turkey/</link>
      <atom:link href="/mesothelioma/drugpanel/turkey/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>mesothelioma</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>BioHub - UFPE</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/mesothelioma/images/icon_hu3365e08ad5ef6cb6d886bc511b9ad2b3_313689_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>mesothelioma</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/drugpanel/turkey/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>TURKEY</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/drugpanel/turkey/info/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/mesothelioma/drugpanel/turkey/info/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/mesothelioma/mesotheliomarmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;font-size:16px&#34;&gt;
DrugBank ID: &lt;a href=&#39;https://www.drugbank.ca/drugs/db10575&#39; target=&#39;_blank&#39;&gt;db10575&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
DrugCentral: &lt;a href=&#34;http://drugcentral.org/?q=turkey&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;turkey&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
Synonymous : &lt;em&gt;None&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;drug-sentece-context&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Drug Sentece Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;font-size:12px&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Table 1.&lt;/strong&gt; Analysis of context sentence of &lt;em&gt;turkey&lt;/em&gt; gene in 60 abstracts.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;table table-striped&#34; style=&#34;width: auto !important; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
pmid
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
sentence
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10232420&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;10232420&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
However, since epidemiological studies are difficult to perform in Turkey, the incidence and the dose-response curve have not been thoroughly examined.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10464903&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;10464903&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Asbestos-related benign and malignant pleural diseases are endemic in some rural parts of central Turkey because of environmental exposure to asbestos fibres. […] We report here epidemiological data on 113 patients with diffuse malignant pleural mesothelioma (DMPM) diagnosed in our clinic in Eskişehir, located in central Turkey.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10810372&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;10810372&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM) continues to be a public health problem in Turkey, where exposure to environmental asbestos and fibrous zeolite (erionite) is the main cause of the disease. […] To determine if SV40 plays a role in the development of MPM in Turkey, we used PCR analysis to investigate if SV40 DNA sequences were present in 29 mesothelioma specimens from patients previously exposed to asbestos or erionite. […] Our results indicate that inorganic fibers, asbestos, and erionite remain the only known causal factors of mesothelioma in Turkey. […] The absence of SV40 in Turkish specimens and its presence in Italian specimens may be related to the fact that SV40-contaminated vaccines were not administered in Turkey.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10949869&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;10949869&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Malignant mesothelioma continues to be a public health problem in rural parts of Anatolia, Turkey. […] From the present study, it was concluded that human herpes virus 8 does not seem to be associated with environmentally induced malignant mesothelioma in Turkey.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11102295&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;11102295&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Fifty cases of malignant mesothelioma (MM) from southern Turkey with no occupational history of asbestos exposure were reviewed regarding pathologic and clinical features. […] The clinical and pathologic features of our cases support that the environmental inhalation of asbestos is still a major health problem in some parts of Turkey.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11124642&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;11124642&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Inhabitants of the southeast of Turkey (ST) have been exposed since childhood to inhalation of asbestos, from a material containing tremolite, used for whitewashing.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11124643&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;11124643&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM) is reported to be common in the southeast of Turkey, as a result of environmental asbestos exposure.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11245743&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;11245743&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The high incidence of malignant mesothelioma in some villages of Cappadocia (Turkey) is due to environmental exposure to erionite fibres.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11273069&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;11273069&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Erionite present in stones used to build the villages of Karain and Tuzköy, Turkey, mined from nearby caves, is purported to cause mesothelioma in half of the villagers.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11386383&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;11386383&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Four patients had breast cancer; 2 had lung cancer; 1 had non-Hodgkin’s lymphoma; and 3 had malignant pleural mesothelioma, which is commonly seen in Central Anatolian region of Turkey.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11551405&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;11551405&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM) due to environmental exposure to asbestos and erionite is a relatively common cancer in Turkey.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11836664&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;11836664&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Recent studies revealed the existence of a genetic factor that predisposes affected individuals to mesothelioma in the villages of Karain and Tuzkoy, in Anatolia, Turkey.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12052665&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;12052665&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Asbestos and erionite exposure are the main causes of malignant mesotheliomas in Turkey. […] A recent study showed that simian virus 40 is not a cofactor in the pathogenesis of environmental malignant mesothelioma in Turkey.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12475867&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;12475867&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
This study examines the incidence of malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM) in a rural population of Turkey with environmental exposure to asbestos-contaminated soil mixtures (white soil).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1325339&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;1325339&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We reviewed data from 135 patients with environment-associated malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM) from the Central Anatolian region of Turkey.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/14725101&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;14725101&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The exposure is generally occupational, an environmental inhalation of asbestos and asbestiform fibers in areas in Turkey has been observed and presents a major health problem.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15117424&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15117424&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Finally, a genetic factor identified in 3 villages in Cappadocia, Turkey, where 50% of individuals die of MM, appears to be the cause of a high incidence of the disease.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15254610&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15254610&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
MM is a major public health problem in parts of Turkey and compulsory environmental control of fibrous mineral should be considered.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15261427&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15261427&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Both asbestos and erionite related malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM) is a serious health problem in Turkey.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15486399&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15486399&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Other mineral fibers such as erionite, a naturally occurring fibrous zeolite crystal, are associated with mesothelioma in volcanic tuffs of the Cappadocia region of central Anatolia in Turkey.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16043260&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16043260&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Environmentally exposed erionite is a potent and unique inducer of malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM) in Central Anatolia in Turkey.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16457426&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16457426&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The role of genetic and familial susceptibility is suggested by studies in Turkey.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16925806&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16925806&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We found no other study on this subject at molecular level in pleural effusion either in Turkey or in the Med-line literature.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17044196&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;17044196&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Genetic susceptibility to the mineral fiber erionite has been demonstrated in some Turkish families and causes a MM epidemic in Cappadocia, Turkey.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17539854&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;17539854&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Environmental asbestos exposure is reportedly common in some districts of Turkey. […] The aim of this study was to investigate the presence and effect of environmental asbestos exposure in a village in Gaziantep, Turkey, with reported cases of mesothelioma. […] The current findings suggest that environmental asbestos exposure continue to be a serious health concern in the Gaziantep region of Turkey.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18171598&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18171598&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Mediterranean regions such as Greece, Turkey, Cyprus, Corsica and New Caledonia have experienced epidemics of malignant mesothelioma as a result of non-occupational, “domestic” exposure to tremolite asbestos and fibrous erionite.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18347916&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18347916&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Erionite deposits have been reported in many countries; however, it is only in the area of three villages of Cappadocia, Turkey, that environmental exposure to erionite has been demonstrated to be the cause of an epidemic of the disease mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1848247&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;1848247&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Endemic malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM) in Turkey is related to two mineral fibers, tremolite asbestos and fibrous zeolite (erionite).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18506411&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18506411&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
It is found in different regions of the world, including southeast Turkey in ash and dust, from which it can cause inflammatory pleural plaques or malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18520266&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18520266&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The data obtained recently on the epidemiology, etiology, and pathogenesis of the mesothelioma due to erionite exposure in Turkey are described.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19383114&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;19383114&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In Turkey, one of the most important sources of asbestos exposure is dust originating from the walls of homes whitewashed with white stucco. […] This study investigated the presence and effect of environmental asbestos exposure in a small village in Isparta, Turkey. […] While tremolite asbestos is the asbestos found in most white soil in Turkey, in this village chrysotile asbestos was found in the white soil.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20068227&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;20068227&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Our study was the first to suggest that the aberrant induction of signaling responses by crocidolite asbestos and erionite, a fibrous zeolite mineral associated with the development of malignant mesotheliomas (MMs) in areas of Turkey, led to altered gene expression.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21479896&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;21479896&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Exposure to erionite leads to higher incidences of mesothelioma and play an important role in environmental exposure (Turkey).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2178276&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2178276&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Ninety-four persons from the village of Karain, Turkey, now residing in Stockholm, were investigated clinically and radiologically.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22275923&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;22275923&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
To investigate the variations in incidence of MPM in Southeast region of Turkey.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22372902&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;22372902&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Erionite has emerged as the most important example of nonasbestos-mediated cause of mesothelioma in regions such as Turkey where exposure to this type of fiber is highly prevalent.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22622048&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;22622048&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
A mesothelioma epidemic in Turkey has demonstrated a probable genetic predisposition to mineral fibre carcinogenesis and studies of human tissues and animal models of mesothelioma have demonstrated genetic and epigenetic events that contribute to the multistep process of mineral fibre carcinogenesis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22722923&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;22722923&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The present study retrospectively evaluated the data pertinent to 282 patients who were examined and treated in 11 different medical oncology centers in Turkey.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22814683&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;22814683&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The aim of this study was to test whether the occurrence of malignant mesothelioma (MM) or pleural plaques (PPs) in the province of Sivas, Turkey, is determined by the proximity of the patient’s birthplace to ophiolites and, if so, to establish the magnitude of the risk.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23407863&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;23407863&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
MPM occurs more frequently in patients born or living in certain villages of Turkey.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24842043&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;24842043&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
It is more frequently seen in certain regions in Turkey.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25208819&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;25208819&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
It is relatively more common in Turkey.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25231672&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;25231672&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
These results indicate that environmental exposure to erionite is the main cause of the high rates of MM mortality in the Village of Tierra Blanca, supporting previous similar reports for people exposed to erionite fibres in villages in Turkey.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/286826&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;286826&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
An epidemiologic and cause-related study was done in Tuzköy, a small village in the city of Nevşehir, in the Anatolian region of Turkey.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29068368&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;29068368&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Environmental asbestos exposure leads to a high risk of MM in Turkey. […] The Turkish Mesothelioma Working Group and the Turkish Public Health Institute designed and performed the Turkey National Mesothelioma Surveillance and Environmental Asbestos Exposure Control Program (TUNMES-EAECP). […] As such, the incidence of MM in Turkey is as high as in industrialized countries. […] Asbestos exposure in rural areas continues to be a serious problem in Turkey, which obviates the necessity for effective preventive measures.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30140749&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30140749&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
To the best of our knowledge, this is the first case report of pseudomesotheliomatous primary squamous cell lung cancer in Turkey, and also the seventh case worldwide.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/3025107&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;3025107&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
An environmental and epidemiological study has been carried out in Central Cappadocia, Turkey, aiming at investigating the relationship between exposure to naturally occurring erionite fibres and the reported high incidence of malignant mesotheliomas.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32282287&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;32282287&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The study aimed to calculate years of life lost (YLL) and years of potential life lost (YPLL) due to malignant mesothelioma (MM) in Turkey.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32568137&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;32568137&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We retrospectively retrieved patients’ clinical data collected by Dicle University, Turkey and applied multilayered perceptron (MLP), voted perceptron (VP), Clojure classifier (CC), kernel logistic regression (KLR), stochastic gradient decent (SGD), adaptive boosting (AdaBoost), Hoeffding tree (VFDT), and primal estimated sub-gradient solver for support vector machine (s-Pegasos).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/6112395&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;6112395&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
A comparative epidemiological and environmental study in two neighbouring villages, Karain and Karlin, in Central Turkey showed an excess adult mortality, shortening of life expectancy, and an excess of pleural radiological abnormalities in Karain.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/6262566&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;6262566&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
To document the zeolite exposure in this area of Turkey, it is suggested that a biologic monitoring study be performed in villages in which mesotheliomas occur and in control villages, by testing for the presence of zeolite bodies in sputum.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/6291146&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;6291146&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The endemic occurrence of this disease in two villages in central Turkey has raised the question of whether the inhalation of naturally occurring zeolite dust may also be a factor in the development of mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/6474389&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;6474389&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In Central Europe and in Finland no connection with malignant mesotheliomas has been found, whereas this tumour is often encountered in areas in Turkey where endemic plaques also occur. […] The prevalence of sequelae of pleurisy is statistically very highly significantly lower than in people with pleural plaques in Turkey.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/6879497&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;6879497&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In some villages in central Turkey pleural changes occur as a result of environmental exposure to mineral fibres.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/7228346&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;7228346&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
This can be explained by the fact that exposure to mineral fibres in Turkey begins immediately after birth.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8394641&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;8394641&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Malignant pleural mesothelioma in rural Turkey frequently results from environmental exposure to tremolite asbestos or fibrous zeolite (erionite).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9216803&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;9216803&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
After several cases of malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM) were detected in the village of Kureyşler in the Kütahya district of western Turkey, an epidemiological study was conducted.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9657657&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;9657657&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
It is endemically present in some regions of Turkey due to its aetiological relationship to exposure to environmental fibrous minerals.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9869119&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;9869119&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
A large university hospital in Ankara, Turkey. […] To investigate the potential links, if any, between the occurrence of malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM) and the presence and distribution of human leukocyte antigens (HLA) in patients environmentally exposed to asbestos and erionite in rural Anatolia, Turkey.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9987816&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;9987816&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Both patients had spent their childhood in central Anatolia, Turkey, where the presence of tremolite asbestos in the environment has been described.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
