<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mesothelioma</title>
    <link>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/secretory/</link>
      <atom:link href="/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/secretory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>mesothelioma</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>BioHub - UFPE</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/mesothelioma/images/icon_hu7e12209333f22d741aca7d462871821f_9877_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>mesothelioma</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/secretory/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>secretory</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/secretory/info/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/secretory/info/</guid>
      <description> 

&lt;script src=&#34;/mesothelioma/mesotheliomarmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;div id=&#34;cell-sentence-context&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cell Sentence Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;font-size:12px&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Table 1.&lt;/strong&gt; Analysis of context sentence of &lt;em&gt;secretory&lt;/em&gt; tissue in 16 abstracts.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;table table-striped&#34; style=&#34;width: auto !important; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
PMID
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
Senteces
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10759883&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;10759883&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Levels of TNFalpha, interleukin-6 (IL-6), interleukin-8 (IL-8), C-reactive protein (CRP) and secretory phospholipase A2 (sPLA2) were measured using enzyme-linked immunosorbent assays (ELISAs).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16021506&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16021506&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
These findings show that myxoid mesotheliomas represent a group of epithelioid mesotheliomas that have retained the secretory activity of normal mesothelium.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1609155&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;1609155&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Mesothelial cells are recognized by (1) their main ultrastructural features: slender and elongated microvilli, abundant intermediate filaments, and lacking secretory granules; and (2) their characteristic immunocytochemical reactivity: positivity for cytokeratin, EMA, and vimentin, and negativity for carcinoembryonic antigen (CEA), B72-3, Leu-M1, and other gland-cell markers.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19095601&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;19095601&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Immunohistochemistry and electron microscopy demonstrated corticotropin and secretory granules in the tumor tissue.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22020330&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;22020330&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
This is characterized by the secretion of proinflammatory and mitogenic cytokines, reminiscent of an SASP (senescence-associated secretory phenotype).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22729037&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;22729037&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The aim of this study was to compare the diagnostic value of the chemokine chemokine (C-C motif) ligand 2 (CCL2), galectin-3, and the secretory leukocyte peptidase inhibitor (SLPI) with soluble mesothelin-related peptides (SMRP), and to evaluate the diagnostic performance of marker combinations.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2328062&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2328062&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
To evaluate the usefulness of immunohistochemistry in the diagnostic distinction between pleural mesothelioma and metastatic adenocarcinoma to the pleura, the authors studied formalin-fixed paraffin-embedded tissue sections from 14 pleural mesotheliomas and 20 primary adenocarcinomas of the lung, stomach, ovary and breast by using 16 commercially available antibodies to cytokeratin (KL1), vimentin, EMA, CEA, CA19.9, CA125, Egp 34 (detected by HEA 125), secretory component, S100 protein, SP1-béta 1, Leu M1, alpha-1-AT, alpha-1-ACT, lysozyme, desmin and factor VIII.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23412101&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;23412101&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
When faced with elevated levels of secretory protein load, cells are said to experience ER stress, which has been implicated in the pathogenesis of many human diseases including cancer.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2648877&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2648877&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Well-characterized, commercially available antibodies to carcinoembryonic antigen (CEA), a high- and low-molecular-weight keratin, vimentin, epithelial membrane antigen, human milk fat globule, Leu-M1, TAG-72 (identified by monoclonal antibody B72.3), beta 1 pregnancy-specific glycoprotein (SP1), human placental lactogen, secretory component (SC), CA19-9, and S-100 protein were used.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29311642&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;29311642&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Here, by using the highly chemoresistant malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM) as an experimental model, we unveiled a key contribution of the chaperone HSP90 at assisting a chemotherapy-instigated Senescence-Associated-Secretory-Phenotype (SASP). […] We unveiled here a key contribution of the chaperone HSP90 at assisting the secretory stress in chemotherapy-treated cells, which may warrant further investigation in combinatorial therapeutic settings.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/3817763&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;3817763&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The distribution of secretory component was examined by an immunoperoxidase method in 40 pulmonary adenocarcinomas, 11 malignant pleural mesotheliomas and areas of normal lung adjacent to the tumours. […] Secretory component was demonstrated in tumour cells in 25 (67%) adenocarcinomas. […] In the normal lung secretory component can be demonstrated in bronchial ciliated cells, bronchial gland serous cells, bronchiolar epithelium and hyperplastic alveolar epithelium. […] None of the mesotheliomas examined contained secretory component and this may be an additional useful feature in the differential diagnosis between mesothelioma and adenocarcinoma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/573917&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;573917&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Cilia or secretory granules were found only in metastatic cells.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/6083969&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;6083969&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Paraffin sections from fifteen cases of malignant diffuse mesothelioma of the pleura and five cases of bronchial adenocarcinoma infiltrating the pleura were examined with an antiserum specific for factor VIII related antigen and with antisera against various epithelial markers: keratin, carcinoembryonic antigen (CEA), fat globule membrane antigen and secretory component. […] The distribution of the fat globule membrane antigens, keratin, secretory component and factor VIII related antigen varied from one mesothelioma to another.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/6654530&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;6654530&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Scantiness of dark secretory granules together with free and membrane-bound polyribosomes were seen in the cytoplasm.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/7281500&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;7281500&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The ultrastructural study provided evidence for the production and accumulation of secretory products (mucolipids) by the tumor cells. […] This case appears to be an example of secretory peritoneal mesothelioma with a bad prognosis, not withstanding the well-differentiated appearance of the tumor cells.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/7684019&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;7684019&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The study involved staining a series of malignant epithelial mesotheliomas (n = 34) and pulmonary adenocarcinomas (n = 103) with eight markers that were selected on the basis of previous reports of their relatively restricted specificities for one or the other of these lesions (and included carcinoembryonic antigen [CEA], tumor-associated glycoprotein 72 [B72.3], Leu-M1, vimentin, thrombomodulin, secretory component, carcinoma antigen-125, and periodic-acid-Schiff with diastase [for mucin].
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
