<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mesothelioma</title>
    <link>/mesothelioma/drugpanel/nivolumab/</link>
      <atom:link href="/mesothelioma/drugpanel/nivolumab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>mesothelioma</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>BioHub - UFPE</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/mesothelioma/images/icon_hu7e12209333f22d741aca7d462871821f_9877_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>mesothelioma</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/drugpanel/nivolumab/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>NIVOLUMAB</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/drugpanel/nivolumab/info/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/mesothelioma/drugpanel/nivolumab/info/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/mesothelioma/mesotheliomarmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;font-size:16px&#34;&gt;
DrugBank ID: &lt;a href=&#39;https://www.drugbank.ca/drugs/db09035&#39; target=&#39;_blank&#39;&gt;db09035&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
DrugCentral: &lt;a href=&#34;http://drugcentral.org/?q=nivolumab&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;nivolumab&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
Synonymous :nivolumab
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;drug-sentece-context&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Drug Sentece Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;font-size:12px&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Table 1.&lt;/strong&gt; Analysis of context sentence of &lt;em&gt;nivolumab&lt;/em&gt; gene in 19 abstracts.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;table table-striped&#34; style=&#34;width: auto !important; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
pmid
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
sentence
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29742520&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;29742520&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Ipilimumab and nivolumab are immune-checkpoint inhibitors commonly used for melanoma. […] We describe a 74-year-old male with malignant pleural mesothelioma who presented with opsoclonus and marked truncal ataxia ∼10 weeks following immunotherapy with ipilimumab and nivolumab. […] A variant of opsoclonus-myoclonus-ataxia syndrome may occur following treatment with ipilimumab and nivolumab.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29853412&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;29853412&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The purpose of this study is to assess the efficacy and safety of combination chemotherapy with cisplatin, pemetrexed, and nivolumab for unresectable malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM). […] Combination chemotherapy with cisplatin (75 mg/m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;), pemetrexed (500 mg/m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;), and nivolumab (360 mg/person) is administered every 3 weeks for a total of 4 to 6 cycles. […] Then, maintenance therapy with nivolumab will be administered until disease progression, unacceptable toxicities, or the patient’s condition meets the withdrawal criteria.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29908324&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;29908324&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Nivolumab is a fully humanized monoclonal antibody against programmed death 1 with a favorable toxicity profile. […] We therefore tested nivolumab in recurrent MPM. […] In this single-center trial, patients with MPM received nivolumab 3 mg/kg intravenously every 2 weeks. […] Single-agent nivolumab has meaningful clinical efficacy and a manageable safety profile in pre-treated patients with mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29970876&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;29970876&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Herein, we present a patient with MPM who experienced rapid disease progression after standard therapy but who had an exceptional and sustained response to immune checkpoint inhibition with single agent nivolumab. […] When chemotherapy failed, he was switched to immunotherapy with nivolumab and achieved an exceptional response. […] CONCLUSIONS We report the first case of a patient with MPM who experienced rapid disease progression after standard therapy but had an exceptional and sustained response to immune checkpoint inhibition with single agent nivolumab.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30595194&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30595194&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In France, approvals have been pronounced for nivolumab and pembrolizumab (anti-PD-1 antibodies) as second-line treatments after chemotherapy in patients with advanced NSCLC, and pembrolizumab has been approved as a first-line treatment in patients with advanced NSCLC, without EGFR mutation or ALK rearrangement, with strong (≥50%) PD-L1 (Programmed Death Ligand 1) expression.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30660511&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30660511&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Here, we assessed the safety and efficacy of the combination of nivolumab, an anti-programmed cell death 1 antibody, plus ipilimumab, an anti-cytotoxic T-lymphocyte protein 4 antibody, in patients with previously treated and relapsed malignant pleural mesothelioma. […] Patients received intravenous nivolumab (240 mg every 2 weeks) plus intravenous ipilimumab (1 mg/kg every 6 weeks up to four times). […] In this single-centre phase 2 trial, the combination of nivolumab plus ipilimumab showed marked efficacy in patients with recurrent malignant pleural mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30660609&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30660609&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Patients were randomly allocated (1:1) to receive intravenous nivolumab (3 mg/kg bodyweight) every 2 weeks, or intravenous nivolumab (3 mg/kg every 2 weeks) plus intravenous ipilimumab (1 mg/kg every 6 weeks), given until progression or unacceptable toxicity. […] Between March 24 and August 25, 2016, 125 eligible patients were recruited and assigned to either nivolumab (n=63) or nivolumab plus ipilimumab (n=62). […] In the first 108 eligible patients, 12-week disease control was achieved by 24 (44%; 95% CI 31-58) of 54 patients in the nivolumab group and 27 (50%; 37-63) of 54 patients in the nivolumab plus ipilimumab group. […] In the intention-to-treat population, 12-week disease control was achieved by 25 (40%; 28-52) of 63 patients in the nivolumab group and 32 (52%; 39-64) of 62 patients in the combination group. […] Nine (14%) of 63 patients in the nivolumab group and 16 (26%) of 61 patients in the combination group had grade 3-4 toxicities. […] The most frequent grade 3 adverse events were asthenia (one [2%] in the nivolumab group vs three [5%] in the combination group), asymptomatic increase in aspartate aminotransferase or alanine aminotransferase (none vs four [7%] of each), and asymptomatic lipase increase (two [3%] vs one [2%]). […] No patients had toxicities leading to death in the nivolumab group, whereas three (5%) of 62 in the combination group did (one fulminant hepatitis, one encephalitis, and one acute kidney failure). […] Anti-PD-1 nivolumab monotherapy or nivolumab plus anti-CTLA-4 ipilimumab combination therapy both showed promising activity in relapsed patients with malignant pleural mesothelioma, without unexpected toxicity.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30762130&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30762130&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
To date, only Japan has given regulatory approval to salvage nivolumab in chemo-refractory mesothelioma patients. […] The USA has included in the NCCN guidelines that pembrolizumab (in programmed death ligand 1 (PD-L1) immunohistochemistry (IHC)-positive patients) and nivolumab with or without ipilimumab (whatever the PD-L1 status is) are accepted salvage therapies.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30788836&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30788836&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We analyzed the United States Food and Drug Administration (FDA) Adverse Event Reporting System (FAERS) database for pembrolizumab, atezolizumab, nivolumab, ipilimumab, avelumab, and durvalumab 2 years prior their FDA approval until December 31, 2017, to include all cases with confirmed diagnosis/relapse of MS.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30794891&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30794891&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The Dako PD-L1 22C3 and 28-8 pharmDx assays are approved by the US Food and Drug Administration (FDA) as companion and complementary diagnostics for the anti-PD-1 drugs pembrolizumab and nivolumab, respectively.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31164373&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;31164373&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We evaluated the efficacy and safety of nivolumab, an immune checkpoint inhibitor, for the treatment of advanced or metastatic MPM. […] Patients received nivolumab 240 mg intravenously every 2 weeks until progressive disease or unacceptable toxicity. […] Nivolumab met the primary endpoint as second- or third-line treatment for patients with MPM and showed promising efficacy with manageable toxicity.&lt;i&gt;See related commentary by Mansfield and Zauderer, p. 5438&lt;/i&gt;.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31315884&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;31315884&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The MERIT study was a single-arm, phase II clinical trial of nivolumab for the second- or third-line treatment of patients with malignant pleural mesothelioma in Japan. […] MERIT confirmed that PD-1 inhibition has activity in mesothelioma and led to the regulatory approval of nivolumab for the treatment of mesothelioma in Japan.&lt;i&gt;See related article by Okada et al., p. 5485&lt;/i&gt;.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31825692&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;31825692&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Nivolumab, an anti-programmed cell death (PD)-1 agent, was one of the first drugs used and is representative of available ICIs.&lt;b&gt;Areas covered&lt;/b&gt;: This review discusses previous relevant reports and current ongoing trials of nivolumab. […] The efficacy and safety of nivolumab have been investigated mostly in second-line or later treatment settings as both monotherapy and in combination with other ICIs. […] Particularly, nivolumab monotherapy yielded promising efficacy with an objective response rate of 29% and median overall survival of 17.3 months in salvage settings in the single-arm, Japanese phase 2 trial (MERIT). […] Notably, the study led to Japanese approval of nivolumab for unresectable recurrent MPM. […] Several trials with monotherapy or cotherapy with nivolumab have commenced, including randomized trials of nivolumab monotherapy vs. placebo in the salvage setting, and cotherapy with nivolumab and ipilimumab vs. the platinum doublet in the frontline setting.&lt;b&gt;Expert opinion&lt;/b&gt;: Nivolumab seems like a reasonable option for unresectable, relapsed MPM despite the lack of randomized trial data.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32042427&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;32042427&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Immunotherapy with nivolumab resulted in prolongation of survival with good quality of life.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32148838&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;32148838&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We report herein a case of sarcomatoid malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM) with high PD-L1 expression who was refractory to standard chemotherapy but had a remarkable and sustained response to nivolumab. […] Although his performance status decreased with advancing of symptoms and adverse events, nivolumab was administered. […] After the nivolumab treatment, CT showed a significant reduction in pleural tumours with a marked improvement in symptoms.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32420076&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;32420076&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
An MPM patient from our institute developed myocarditis and myositis after 2 cycles of second-line nivolumab. […] The patient developed an impressive but brief response following cessation of nivolumab.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32463095&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;32463095&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
This study aimed to evaluate the efficacy and feasibility of nivolumab in patients with post-operative recurrence of MPM in a real-world setting. […] Treatment consisted of 240-mg intravenous nivolumab administration every 2 weeks until progressive disease (PD) or serious adverse events (AEs). […] Of the 35 patients who received nivolumab, median follow-up was 6 months. […] Nivolumab treatment in patients with post-operative recurrence of MPM seems safe and clinical efficacy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32481365&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;32481365&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We herein report the case of a 75-year-old man with peritoneal mesothelioma treated with cisplatin plus pemetrexed and subsequent nivolumab. […] Nivolumab was then administered as the second-line therapy. […] After 3 cycles of biweekly nivolumab administration, he developed severe abdominal distention. […] CT revealed an intraperitoneal mass growing much more rapidly than ever, indicating hyperprogressive disease after nivolumab treatment. […] He ultimately died 51 days after the initial nivolumab administration. […] To our knowledge, this is the first report of hyperprogressive disease in a case of peritoneal mesothelioma after nivolumab treatment.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32714828&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;32714828&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Nivolumab showed durable antitumor effect in patients with recurrent MPM and was approved for those patients in Japan in 2018. […] Immune related adverse event (irAE) is occurred in various organs and is suggestive to be related to better outcome of nivolumab. […] Frequency of hematological irAE is low and there are few reports about hematological irAE and association between irAE and outcome of nivolumab in patients with MPM. […] We present a case of recurrent MPM who responded to nivolumab treatment and experienced nivolumab-induced immune thrombocytopenia (ITP). […] This is the first report about nivolumab-induced ITP and association with response to nivolumab in MPM.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
