<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mesothelioma</title>
    <link>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/macrophages/</link>
      <atom:link href="/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/macrophages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>mesothelioma</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>BioHub - UFPE</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/mesothelioma/images/icon_hu7e12209333f22d741aca7d462871821f_9877_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>mesothelioma</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/macrophages/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>macrophages</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/macrophages/info/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/macrophages/info/</guid>
      <description> 

&lt;script src=&#34;/mesothelioma/mesotheliomarmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;div id=&#34;cell-sentence-context&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cell Sentence Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;font-size:12px&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Table 1.&lt;/strong&gt; Analysis of context sentence of &lt;em&gt;macrophages&lt;/em&gt; tissue in 56 abstracts.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;table table-striped&#34; style=&#34;width: auto !important; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
PMID
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
Senteces
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10705260&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;10705260&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Furthermore, expression of flt-1 was detected in tumor cells, macrophages and microvessels adjacent to tumor cells.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11796462&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;11796462&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
This study further separates two groups of Metsovites with different reaction to asbestos, possibly as a result of different activation of alveolar macrophages.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12065358&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;12065358&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We conducted a multicentric pilot phase II study to evaluate the tolerance and the activity of intrapleurally infused autologous human activated macrophages (AM Phi) in patients with stage IA, IB, and IIA malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1379511&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;1379511&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In this respect, macrophages constitute a major part of the inflammatory cell infiltration and can exert cytotoxic activity against tumor cells. […] The accumulation of macrophages in the vicinity of the tumor suggests their recruitment from circulating blood monocytes through the local release of chemotactic factors for monocytes.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16540497&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16540497&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
There was a massive influx of CD4+ and CD8+ T-lymphocytes and macrophages, but not of dendritic cells, in human mesothelioma biopsies.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17038662&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;17038662&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
When injected intrapleurally in mice, APMS-TEG were taken up by both CD45-positive and -negative cells of the diaphragm, lung, and spleen, whereas APMS administered by the intranasal route were predominantly in lung epithelial cells and alveolar macrophages.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17044196&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;17044196&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Recent results revealed that asbestos carcinogenesis in humans and in rodents is linked to the activation of the AP-1 pathway, which induces cell division, and to the secretion of TNF-alpha (and the expression of its receptor) by mesothelial cells and by nearby macrophages exposed to asbestos. […] In addition, mutagenic oxygen radicals released mainly by lung macrophages may contribute to asbestos carcinogenesis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18709470&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18709470&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The capacity of asbestos to induce mesothelioma has been linked to its ability to cause the release of TNF-alpha (that promotes mesothelial cells survival), other cytokines and growth factors, and of mutagenic oxygen radicals from exposed mesothelial cells and nearby macrophages.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1990961&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;1990961&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Asbestosis is an inflammatory and fibrotic process of the alveolar structures mediated, at least in part, by cytokines released by “activated” alveolar macrophages. […] The process of phagocytosis and “activation” of alveolar macrophages is poorly understood. […] Are all macrophages activated or only subpopulations? […] For example, proto-oncogenes such as c-sis (PDGF B-chain) are up-regulated in activated alveolar macrophages from fibrotic lungs; these and possibly others may play an important role in asbestos carcinogenesis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20049814&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;20049814&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Fibers can be cleared by several mechanisms, including the mucociliary escalator, engulfment, and removal by macrophages, or through splitting and chemical modification.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20616036&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;20616036&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The release of HMGB1 induces macrophages to secrete TNF-alpha, which protects HM from asbestos-induced cell death and triggers a chronic inflammatory response; both favor HM transformation.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20853778&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;20853778&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Inhaled asbestos fibres deposit in the distal regions of the respiratory system where they interact with epithelial cells and alveolar macrophages, and trigger active immunological response which leads to a slowly progressing lung fibrosis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21412769&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;21412769&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Asbestos induces DNA alterations mostly by inducing mesothelial cells and reactive macrophages to secrete mutagenic oxygen and nitrogen species. […] In addition, asbestos carcinogenesis is linked to the chronic inflammatory process caused by the deposition of a sufficient number of asbestos fibers and the consequent release of pro-inflammatory molecules, especially HMGB-1, the master switch that starts the inflammatory process, and TNF-alpha by macrophages and mesothelial cells.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21523763&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;21523763&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The current study examined the prognostic significance of circulating monocytes and tumor-infiltrating macrophages on overall survival in patients with MPM. […] The phenotype of circulating monocytes and tumor-infiltrating macrophages in 7 additional patients was determined by flow cytometry. […] Within MPM tumors, macrophages comprised 27% ± 9% of the tumor area and demonstrated an immunosuppressive phenotype with high expression of CD163, CD206, and interleukin-4 receptor α. […] Higher numbers of circulating monocytes are associated with poor survival in all patients with MPM and higher densities of tumor-infiltrating macrophages are associated with poor survival in patients with nonepithelial MPM.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24450537&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;24450537&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
MPM contains a variable degree of infiltrating T-regulatory cells and M2 macrophages, which are believed to facilitate tumor evasion from the host immune system.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25192022&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;25192022&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
M1 skewed macrophages possess anti-tumoral capacities, while the M2 polarized macrophages have pro-tumoral capacities. […] The total number of macrophages in tumor tissue did not correlate with OS in both groups, however, the CD163/CD68 ratio correlates with OS in the total patient group.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25361002&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;25361002&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Nine MPM cell lines and primary mesothelial cells (PMC), co-cultured or not with M2 macrophages present in MPM microenvironment, were used to assess PEITC and cisplatin anti-tumor properties. […] Finally, we showed that M2 macrophages did not alter the anti-tumor properties of the combination.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26155428&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;26155428&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Analysis of single immune cell infiltration for CD163&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; tumor-associated macrophages did not correlate with survival. […] However, analysis of immunologically relevant cell combinations identified that: (1) high CD163&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; tumor-associated macrophages and low CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; lymphocyte infiltration had worse prognosis than other groups and (2) low CD163&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; tumor associated macrophages and high CD20&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; lymphocyte infiltration had better prognosis than other groups. […] With a recent increase in immunotherapy investigations and clinical trials for malignant pleural mesothelioma patients, our observations that CD20&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; B lymphocytes and tumor-associated macrophages are prognostic markers provide important information about the tumor microenvironment of malignant pleural mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26938529&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;26938529&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The interaction of asbestos fibers with macrophages generates harmful reactive oxygen species (ROS) and subsequent oxidative cell damage that are key processes linked to malignancy. […] We thus evaluated synthetic SDG (LGM2605) in asbestos-exposed, elicited murine peritoneal macrophages as an in vitro model of tissue phagocytic response to the presence of asbestos in the pleural space. […] Murine peritoneal macrophages (MFs) were exposed to crocidolite asbestos fibers (20 µg/cm²) and evaluated at various times post exposure for cytotoxicity, ROS generation, malondialdehyde (MDA), and levels of 8-iso Prostaglandin F2α (8-isoP). […] LGM2605 boosted antioxidant defenses, as well as reduced asbestos-induced ROS generation and markers of oxidative stress in murine peritoneal macrophages, supporting its possible use as a chemoprevention agent in the development of asbestos-induced malignant mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26959120&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;26959120&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Cysmethynil also promoted M1 anti-tumor macrophage homing in the pleural space in vivo, and inhibited tumor-induced polarization of macrophages towards a M2 phenotype in vitro.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27168021&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;27168021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Immunohistochemistry was performed to quantify immune cell composition (T cells, macrophages) and tumor cells in PE derived cytospins and tumor biopsies. […] In addition, the presence of T cells and macrophages in PE did not necessarily mirror the infiltration of these immune cells within tumor biopsies in 4 out of 5 patients.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27349291&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;27349291&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In this study, we have investigated the expression of CD68-positive macrophages, tryptase-positive mast cells and CD31 positive areas, as expression of microvascular density, in lung tissue of sheeps exposed to fluoro-edenite fibers vs controls, by immunohistochemical, morphometric and Western blot analysis. […] The result have evidenced a significant increase in the expression of CD68-positive macrophages, tryptase-positive mast cells as well as a significant increase in microvascular density evaluated as CD31 positive areas in lung tissue of of sheeps exposed to fluoro-edenite fibers vs controls. […] These data confirmed the important role played by tumor microenvironment components, including macrophages and mast cells, in favour of angiogenesis in pleural mesothelioma induced by fluoro-edenite exposure.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27418105&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;27418105&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The phenotype of macrophages was determined by flow cytometry and enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay. […] Cocultures of macrophages with mesothelioma cells were performed to study cancer cell proliferation and resistance to treatment. […] Macrophages obtained in MPM samples were M2 macrophages (high CD14, high CD163, and interleukin-10 secretion after activation). […] Immunohistochemical analysis confirmed the presence of M2 macrophages in pleural and peritoneal mesothelioma. […] Finally, we showed that M2 macrophages increased mesothelioma cell proliferation and resistance to treatment.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27418106&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;27418106&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Macrophages are abundantly present within the mesothelioma microenvironment. […] This study investigates the influence of the macrophage phenotype, macrophages’ capacity to inhibit local immune responses, and the decisive role of pleural effusion (PE) in this regard. […] We cultured macrophages in the presence of PEs and investigated their phenotype. […] Macrophages and T cells were cocultured in the presence of PEs and tumor cell line supernatants. […] The presence and phenotype of macrophages and T cell subsets was measured in the PE of patients with mesothelioma. […] PE induced a tumor-promoting M2 phenotype in macrophages, which was confirmed by the suppressive activity of macrophages on T cell proliferation during coculture. […] Prostanoid prostaglandin E2 was identified as a potential inducer of the suppressive capacity of macrophages in PE. […] Macrophages isolated from PEs displayed an M2 phenotype and were negatively correlated with T cells in vivo. […] The current study demonstrates that macrophages in PE can play a pivotal role in directly hampering the antitumor T cell immune response. […] This emphasizes the potential of macrophages as a therapeutic target in mesothelioma and indicates that the presence and phenotype of macrophages in PE should be taken into consideration in the application of (intrapleural) immunotherapies.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27819788&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;27819788&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Its carcinogenicity is caused as the inhaled asbestos fibers cannot be eliminated by macrophages and, thus, they travel to the pleura through lymphatic pathways, producing a persistent inflammatory response.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27833109&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;27833109&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Ad.EPCR treatment elicited recruitment of macrophages and NK cells into the tumor microenvironment and increased IFNγ and TNFα levels in the pleural space.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28922567&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;28922567&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The presence of MM cells was confirmed with CK5/6, calretinin, and EMA and the admixture of macrophages was assessed with CD68.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29039588&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;29039588&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In non-malignant samples (n=28), growth of mesothelial cells, macrophages and of both cell types was identified in 82.14, 10.71 and 7.14%, respectively. […] In the remaining 35.29% of malignant samples, the only cells in growth were mesothelial and/or macrophages instead of malignant epithelial cells. […] Besides, mesothelial cells and macrophages may be the only cells identified in malignant effusion culture. […] The ideal malignant effusion sample to obtain culture of neoplastic cells should be that without the presence of mesothelial cells and macrophages.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29046510&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;29046510&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Phagocytosis of MWCNT fibers by macrophages was very likely to be a principle factor in MWCNT lung carcinogenesis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29163783&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;29163783&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We found CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; and CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells, B cells, macrophages, natural killer cells, dendritic cells and tumor cells in the fluids.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29419731&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;29419731&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Overall, asbestos-induced chronic inflammation in the lung as well as the pleural cavity may facilitate the onset of asbestos-induced cancers due to alterations in the interactions among fibers, immune cells such as T and B cells and macrophages, and mesothelial and lung epithelial cells.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29514216&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;29514216&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Higher CD8+ T lymphocytes, CD68+ macrophages, and PD-L1 expression were associated with pathological features of aggressiveness (necrosis, grading, Ki-67). […] TME enriched with cytotoxic T lymphocytes is associated with higher levels of macrophages and PD-L1 expression on tumor cells and with aggressive histopathological features, lower response to chemotherapy and shorter survival.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29601534&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;29601534&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Generally, immune-suppressive cells such as M2 macrophages, myeloid-derived suppressor cells and regulatory T cells are present within the TME, with extensive heterogeneity in cell numbers.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29949929&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;29949929&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Interestingly, the proportion of myeloid-derived suppressor cell and macrophage (especially CD206⁺ M2 macrophages) populations increased in the pleural fluid of mice with large mesothelioma development, as previously observed in immunocompetent mice.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30312759&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30312759&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The major pathogenic mechanisms include oxidative stress either via catalytic reactions against the asbestos surface or frustrated phagocytosis of macrophages, and specific adsorption of hemoglobin and histones by asbestos fibers in the presence of phagocytic activity of mesothelial cells.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30642542&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30642542&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In addition, targeting mesothelioma stem cells by depleting M2-polarized macrophages in tumor microenvironment or blocking Tnfsf18 (GITRL)-GITR signalling might be translated into therapeutic modalities in mesothelioma treatment.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30885349&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30885349&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Expression of markers of tumor-infiltrating lymphocytes (TILs) and macrophages ranged from 0% to more than 50%. […] The majority of patients had immune inflamed tumors (77%) and there was a significant association between TILs and BIN1 (p = 0 &amp;lt; 0.01), PD-L1 (p=0.04) and CD68+ macrophages in the tumor (p &amp;lt; 0.01).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31078776&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;31078776&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The cutoffs of intratumor T-regulatory (&amp;gt;1.1%) cells, M2-macrophages (&amp;gt;36%), granulocytic and monocytic myeloid-derived suppressor cells (MDSC; &amp;gt;5.1% and 4.2%, respectively), CD4 molecule-positive (CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;) programmed death 1-positive (PD-1&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;) (&amp;gt;5.2%) and CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;PD-1&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; (6.4%) cells, CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; lymphocyte activating 3-positive (LAG-3&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;) (&amp;gt;2.8% ) and CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;LAG-3&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; (&amp;gt;2.8%) cells, CD4&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cell immunoglobulin and mucin domain 3-positive (TIM-3&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;) (&amp;gt;2.5%), and CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;TIM-3&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; (&amp;gt;2.6%) cells discriminated MPM from pleuritis with 100% sensitivity and 89% specificity.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31263030&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;31263030&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
IHC analysis of pre- and post-CRS-207 treatment tumor biopsies revealed possible reinvigoration and proliferation of T cells, increased infiltration of dendritic and natural killer cells, increased CD8:T&lt;sub&gt;reg&lt;/sub&gt; ratio, and a shift from immunosuppressive M2-like to proinflammatory M1-like macrophages following CRS-207 administration.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31388672&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;31388672&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
As GGT is expressed in macrophages and is released upon their activation, the present study was aimed at verifying the hypothesis that GSH/GGT-dependent redox reactions may participate in the oxidative stress following the activation of macrophages induced by crocidolite asbestos. […] Cultured THP-1 macrophagic cells, as well as isolated monocytes obtained from healthy donors and differentiated to macrophages in vitro, were investigated as to their expression of GGT and the effects of exposure to crocidolite.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31413910&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;31413910&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Furthermore, the P4D2 mAb reduced tumor-associated macrophages differentiation toward a protumor phenotype. […] In syngeneic murine models of MM, P4D2 mAb treatment inhibited tumor growth and improved survival, with tumors from P4D2-treated mice exhibited reduced infiltration of tumor-associated M2 macrophages.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31428531&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;31428531&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The degree of TIL hypofunction did not correlate with the presence of co-existing macrophages or neutrophils, nor with expression of the inhibitory receptors PD-1, CD39 and CTLA-4.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31534051&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;31534051&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The roles of macrophages in orchestrating innate immunity through phagocytosis and T lymphocyte activation have been extensively investigated. […] Much less understood is the unexpected role of macrophages in direct tumor regression. […] Tumoricidal macrophages can indeed manifest cancer immunoediting activity in the absence of adaptive immunity. […] In particular, we analyzed the cytotoxic activity of mouse RAW264.7 macrophages upon cell-cell contact with autologous AB1/AB12 mesothelioma cells. […] We show that macrophages killed mesothelioma cells by oxeiptosis via a mechanism involving enhancer of zeste homolog 2 (EZH2), a histone H3 lysine 27-specific (H3K27-specific) methyltransferase of the polycomb repressive complex 2 (PRC2). […] In the immunocompetent BALB/c model, RAW264.7 macrophages pretreated with the EZH2 inhibitor failed to control tumor growth of AB1 and AB12 mesothelioma cells. […] We conclude that macrophages can be directly cytotoxic for mesothelioma cells independent of phagocytosis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31819191&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;31819191&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Inhaled asbestos fibres accumulate in the lungs and induce the generation of reactive oxygen species (ROS) due to the presence of iron associated with the fibrous silicates and to the activation of macrophages and inflammation.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31823764&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;31823764&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Macrophages are a key component of asbestos-associated inflammation and play essential roles in the etiology of a variety of cancers. […] Macrophages are also a source of C-C motif chemokine ligand 2 (CCL2), and a variety of tumor-types express CCL2.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32312030&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;32312030&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In exposed sheep lungs, MIF and HO-1 immunoexpression were spread involving the intraparenchymal stroma around bronchioles, interstitium between alveoli, alveolar epithelium and macrophages. […] High MIF immunoexpression prevails in macrophages.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32372095&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;32372095&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
This correlated with increased CD8+ T cells and activated antigen-presenting cells (CD11b+ dendritic cells and macrophages) infiltration in MPM.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32530527&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;32530527&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We also identified tumor-associated macrophages (TAMs) as the major source of IL-1β in the MPM microenvironment.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32574520&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;32574520&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Here, we established an &lt;i&gt;in vitro&lt;/i&gt; system by co-culturing macrophages and mesothelial cells and exposing these cells to high aspect ratio MWCNTs (0.1 μg/mL) for three months. […] Results indicated that IL-1β, secreted by macrophages stimulated by MWCNTs, may significantly enhance the release of inflammatory cytokines, such as IL-8, TNF-α, and IL-6, from mesothelial cells.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32581053&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;32581053&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The tumor microenvironment content, particularly the presence of macrophages, was described as crucial for the development of the disease. […] This work aimed at studying the involvement of the M-CSF (CSF-1)/IL-34/CSF-1R pathway in the formation of macrophages in MPM, using samples from patients. […] In tumors, expression of &lt;i&gt;CSF1&lt;/i&gt; was correlated with ‘M2-like macrophages’ markers, whereas this was not the case with &lt;i&gt;IL34&lt;/i&gt; expression, suggesting two distinct modes of action of these cytokines. […] Finally, using 3D coculture model, we demonstrated the direct involvement of MPM cells in the formation of immunosuppressive macrophages, through activation of the colony stimulating factor-1 receptor (CSF1-R) pathway, causing the inhibition of cytotoxicity of tumor antigen-specific CD8&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; T cells.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8044791&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;8044791&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
This treatment was associated with in situ activation of macrophages and cytotoxic T-lymphocytes, as indicated by increased intrapleural neopterin and soluble CD8 concentrations.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8135583&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;8135583&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The most reliable histochemical technique is the iron stain which labels macrophages. […] A minimum immunolabelling panel (including one or two epithelial markers and vimentin), applied to the identification of the usual phenotypes of reactive fluids with mesothelial cells or with macrophages, to adenocarcinomatous fluids and to malignant mesothelioma fluids, is proposed.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8293414&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;8293414&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Of the monoclonal preparations, those staining granulocytes and macrophages also showed varying reactivity to some of these 13 mesotheliomas.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8725724&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;8725724&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
ICAM-1 is expressed by mesothelioma cells and CD 11b by macrophages in the fibrinous mesothelioma tumor stroma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9367490&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;9367490&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Light microscopic examination of a left visceral pleural biopsy specimen revealed markedly thickened pleura with fibrosis and macrophages containing birefringent silica and silicates.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9842634&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;9842634&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Non-specific positive reactions for Ber-EP4 in single mesothelial cells were observed in 16% of all cases and, moreover, frequently with macrophages or neutrophilic granulocytes.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
