<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Transmission | mesothelioma</title>
    <link>/mesothelioma/syntax_summary/transmission/</link>
      <atom:link href="/mesothelioma/syntax_summary/transmission/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Transmission</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>BioHub - UFPE</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/mesothelioma/images/icon_hu7e12209333f22d741aca7d462871821f_9877_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Transmission</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/syntax_summary/transmission/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transmission Sentence Context</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/syntax_summary/transmission/info/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/mesothelioma/syntax_summary/transmission/info/</guid>
      <description> 

&lt;script src=&#34;/mesothelioma/mesotheliomarmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;font-size:12px&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Table 1.&lt;/strong&gt; Analysis of context sentence of 31 absracts clustered as Transmission.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;table table-striped&#34; style=&#34;width: auto !important; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
Title
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
Gene Context Sentence
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
ePubDate
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11100950&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Role of occupational asbestos exposure in Hungarian lung cancer patients.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Additionally, results of the lung tissue fibre counts by scanning transmission electron microscopy were available for 25 of the lung cancer patients.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2001-02-15
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11112207&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Prognostic significance of presence and reduplication of basal lamina in malignant pleural mesothelioma.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
To investigate whether RBL is important for predicting the survival of patients with MM, transmission electron microscopy was used to identify the presence of basal lamina or RBL in biopsy specimens obtained by thoracoscopy from 35 patients.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2001-01-04
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11216913&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pleural mesothelioma associated with indoor pollution of asbestos.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
By use of scanning transmission electron microscopy, clearly increased concentrations of amphibole fibres (8.6 x 10(6) fibres longer than 1 microm and 0.6 x 10(6) fibres longer than &amp;gt; or =5 microm per gram dry tissue), mainly classified as crocidolite, were observed.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2001-03-08
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11245743&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Erionite bodies and fibres in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid (BALF) of residents from Tuzköy, Cappadocia, Turkey.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Ferruginous bodies (FBs) and fibres were measured and analyzed by light and transmission electron microscopy (TEM) in the BALF of 16 subjects originating from Tuzköy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2001-03-29
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11936818&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Reappraisal of the strong association between simian virus 40 and human malignant mesothelioma of the pleura (Belgium).&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The frequent association of a monkey oncogenic virus, simian virus 40 (SV40), with pleural mesothelioma and the proposed transmission of the virus from contaminated polio vaccines to humans has received considerable scientific and public attention.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2002-09-10
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12878934&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Positron emission tomography defines metastatic disease but not locoregional disease in patients with malignant pleural mesothelioma.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Whole-body emission studies were acquired, followed by whole-body transmission studies, allowing iterative reconstruction.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2003-09-17
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/14511258&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Synchronous diffuse malignant mesothelioma and carcinomas in asbestos-exposed individuals.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In each case transmission electron microscopic mineral analysis revealed an asbestos fibre burden within the background population range for control subjects and well below that seen in cases of established asbestosis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2004-05-11
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1484440&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;[Two cases of malignant mesothelioma controlled by pleurectomy].&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The tumor was diagnosed as malignant pleural mesothelioma on the basis of histochemical staining and transmission electron microscopy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1993-02-12
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15469478&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The pathology associated with therapeutic procedures in malignant mesothelioma.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Talc could be identified by transmission electron microscopic mineral analysis in 5/15 (33%) cases examined.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2005-03-03
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16251370&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mortality of UK electricity generation and transmission workers, 1973-2002.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
To examine mortality from cancer and non-malignant causes among a large cohort of UK electricity generation and transmission workers. […] Standardized mortality ratios (SMRs) were used to assess mortality in the total cohort and in three sub-cohorts: power station workers, substation and transmission workers and workers at non-operational locations.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2006-04-13
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1646682&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Lung asbestos fiber content and mesothelioma cell type, site, and survival.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Lung fiber content analyses by light microscopy and analytic transmission electron microscopy with energy-dispersive x-ray analysis were done on 226 cases in which postmortem material was available, using the method of Rogers.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1991-07-23
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17000285&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Positron emission tomography predicts survival in malignant pleural mesothelioma.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Whole-body emission studies were acquired, followed by whole-body transmission scans with iterative reconstruction.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2006-10-19
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1801838&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;[Asbestos content in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid].&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The concentration and size distribution of bronchoalveolar lavage (BAL) asbestos fibers (AF) longer than 2 microns was determined by analytical transmission electron microscopy (TEM).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1992-04-29
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1809139&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Analysis of asbestos fibers in lung parenchyma, pleural plaques, and mesothelioma tissues of North American insulation workers.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Asbestos fibers and ferruginous bodies (FBs) in lung parenchyma, lung cancer tissues, pleural plaques, and pleural and peritoneal mesothelioma tissues from 13 North American insulation workers were analyzed and quantified using an analytical transmission electron microscope and a polarized microscope.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1992-05-15
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18383846&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Establishment of three novel human malignant pleural mesothelioma cell lines: morphological and cytogenetical studies and EGFR mutation status.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Established pleural effusion fluid cell lines were observed using phase-contrast microscopy and transmission electron microscopy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2008-04-10
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23060969&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tunneling Nanotubes: A new paradigm for studying intercellular communication and therapeutics in cancer.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
These structures have not, until recently, been scrutinized as a unique and previously unrecognized form of direct cell-to-cell transmission of cellular cargo in the context of human cancer.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2012-10-15
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23516439&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Phenotypes and karyotypes of human malignant mesothelioma cell lines.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Mesothelial origin was assessed by standard morphology, Transmission Electron Microscopy (TEM) and immunocytochemistry.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2013-09-12
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24815466&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Inhibitory effects of 3-bromopyruvate on human gastric cancer implant tumors in nude mice.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The TUNEL method was used to detect apoptosis, and cell morphology and structural changes of tumor tissue were observed under transmission electron microscopy (TEM).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2015-01-10
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25683976&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Clinical and prognostic features of erionite-induced malignant mesothelioma.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Erionite has a higher degree of carcinogenicity with possible genetic transmission of erionite susceptibility in an autosomal dominant fashion.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2015-07-06
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26715106&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pleural mesothelioma and lung cancer risks in relation to occupational history and asbestos lung burden.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Following personal interview asbestos fibres longer than 5 µm were counted by transmission electron microscopy in lung samples obtained from 133 patients with mesothelioma and 262 patients with lung cancer.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2016-08-25
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31562297&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PFKFB3 inhibition reprograms malignant pleural mesothelioma to nutrient stress-induced macropinocytosis and ER stress as independent binary adaptive responses.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Transmission electron microscopy (TEM) analysis showed the formation of nascent macropinocytotic vesicles, which rapidly coalesced to form large vacuoles with compromised lysosomal function.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
2020-03-30
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/3859122&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ultrastructural studies of cells in body cavity effusions.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Transmission electron microscopic examination of benign (16 cases) and malignant (2 cases) mesothelial cells and metastatic carcinoma (10 cases) was performed.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1985-07-12
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/6262566&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Zeolite bodies in human lungs from Turkey.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Mineral fibers were assessed in lung samples from two cases of malignant pleural mesothelioma in Tusköy, using the light microscope and the analytical transmission electron microscope.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1981-07-09
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/6648341&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Scope of scanning electron microscopy, transmission electron microscopy and freeze fracture technique in diagnostic cytology of effusions.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
A review of the literature on the application of scanning electron microscopy (SEM) and transmission electron microscopy (TEM) to cytodiagnosis of neoplastic cells in effusion fluid reveals a lack of consensus as to which of the techniques is most beneficial to a cytologist for a satisfactory diagnosis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1984-01-27
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/7239661&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The use of electron microscopy in the diagnosis of diffuse mesotheliomas using human pleural effusions.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Transmission electron microscopy has been found to be of greater value than scanning electron microscopy in the differential diagnosis of mesothelial reaction, malignant mesothelioma and metastatic carcinoma. […] It is possible to remove identified cells from slides for transmission electron microscopy, and this is particularly valuable when an urgent diagnosis is required.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1981-08-27
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8137206&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Asbestos and nonasbestos fiber content in lung tissue of Japanese patients with malignant mesothelioma.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Pulmonary fiber content was analyzed in 16 patients and 16 case-matched control subjects by transmission electron microscopy with energy-dispersive X-ray analysis using a low-temperature ashing procedure.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1994-04-22
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8497827&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Malignant mesothelioma in women.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
One hundred and seventy seven cases of malignant mesothelioma in females were reviewed, examined by histochemistry and immunohistochemistry, assessed for asbestosis and lung fibre burden by transmission electron microscopy with energy dispersive x ray analysis, and compared with 31 female controls.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1993-06-23
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8542156&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Black spots concentrate oncogenic asbestos fibers in the parietal pleura. Thoracoscopic and mineralogic study.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Asbestos content was determined by transmission electron microscopy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1996-02-13
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8901239&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Inorganic particles in the lungs of five aluminum smelter workers with pleuro-pulmonary cancer.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Retained fibrous and nonfibrous particles were evaluated by transmission electron microscopy and energy dispersive spectroscopy after lung digestion.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1996-12-27
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9891926&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Basal lamina reduplication in malignant epithelioid pleural mesothelioma.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In this study, transmission electron microscopic observations of EMM were compared with those of peripheral adenocarcinoma of the lung (PAL).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1999-03-18
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9987816&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Environmental exposure to tremolite asbestos: pleural mesothelioma in two Turkish workers in Germany.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In both patients, the lung-dust burden showed a high concentration of amphibole fibers (186 x 10(6) resp. 59 x 10(6) per gram dry tissue), mainly classified as actionolite/tremolite fibers in scanning transmission electron microscopy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
1999-04-13
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terms to cluster Transmission Abstract</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/syntax_summary/transmission/terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/mesothelioma/syntax_summary/transmission/terms/</guid>
      <description> 

&lt;script src=&#34;/mesothelioma/mesotheliomarmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;font-size:12px&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Table 2.&lt;/strong&gt; 6 terms used to create the Transmission Category and its counts.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;table table-striped&#34; style=&#34;width: auto !important; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
Term
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
Count
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
All (sum)
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
32
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Transmission
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
31
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Disease Transmission
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
NA
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Infection Transmission
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
NA
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Infectious Disease Transmission
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
NA
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Sexually Transmitted Diseases
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
NA
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
