<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mesothelioma</title>
    <link>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/stomach/</link>
      <atom:link href="/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/stomach/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>mesothelioma</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>BioHub - UFPE</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/mesothelioma/images/icon_hu7e12209333f22d741aca7d462871821f_9877_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>mesothelioma</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/stomach/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>stomach</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/stomach/info/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/stomach/info/</guid>
      <description> 

&lt;script src=&#34;/mesothelioma/mesotheliomarmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;div id=&#34;tissue-sentence-context&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tissue Sentence Context&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;font-size:12px&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Table 1.&lt;/strong&gt; Analysis of context sentence of &lt;em&gt;stomach&lt;/em&gt; tissue in 40 abstracts.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;table table-striped&#34; style=&#34;width: auto !important; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
PMID
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
Senteces
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10783675&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;10783675&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The underlying malignancies in these patients were as follows: bronchogenic carcinoma (51.5%), breast carcinoma (29.1%), hepatocellular carcinoma (1.9%), carcinoma of the stomach (1.9%), malignant mesothelioma, nasopharyngeal carcinoma, renal cell carcinoma, carcinoma of the oesophagus, lymphoma, carcinoma of the colon (1% each), unknown (9.7%).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12662014&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;12662014&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Certain cancers such as cancers of the breast, ovary, lung, and stomach have a predilection for the pleural mesothelium.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12795187&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;12795187&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The histological types were adenocarcinoma of the stomach, squamous cell carcinoma of the lung and sarcomatous malignant pleural mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12873676&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;12873676&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
As shown by axial and sagittal isodose distributions, we were able to deliver adequate doses to the target volume while limiting dose to critical structures such as heart, spinal cord, liver, and stomach.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16174857&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16174857&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Cancers of the lung (RR = 1.5, 95% CI = 1.2 to 1.7), colon (RR = 2.0, 95% CI = 1.7 to 2.5), bladder (RR = 2.7, 95% CI = 2.2 to 3.1), pancreas (RR = 3.6, 95% CI = 2.8 to 4.6), and stomach (RR = 4.0, 95% CI = 3.2 to 4.8) accounted for almost 60% of the total excess.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16612848&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16612848&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The primary tumor was: lung-63 (46%), breast-26 (19%), mesothelioma-21 (15.5%), stomach-3, ovarian-3, prostate-3, colon-2, lymphoma-1, leukemia-2, plasmocytoma-1 and unknown primary tumor in 11 cases (8%).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17916095&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;17916095&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The adenocarcinomas included metastatic carcinomas from the breast (12), lung (19), stomach (3), colon (1), pancreas (2), ovary (6) endometrium (1) and 23 histologically confirmed metastases from unknown primary sites.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19160697&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;19160697&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Tissue samples studied include colon, lung, breast, pleura, stomach and thyroid.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19254909&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;19254909&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The SMRs for cancers of the stomach (166), lung (187), peritoneum (3730) and pleura (968), mesothelioma (513), cerebrovascular disease (164) and asbestosis (5594) were statistically significantly elevated, as were the corresponding PMRs. […] Known associations between asbestos exposure and mortality from lung, peritoneal and pleural cancers, mesothelioma and asbestosis were confirmed, and evidence of associations with stroke and stomach cancer mortality was observed.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1958874&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;1958874&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
There were sixty-one deaths in the cohort–4 tuberculosis, 12 malignant neoplasms (4 stomach cancers, 8 respiratory cancers including one case of pleural mesothelioma), 18 circulatory diseases, 24 respiratory diseases, and 3 other causes of death. […] SMR for all causes of death, stomach cancer, respiratory cancer, circulatory diseases, and respiratory diseases were 1.15, 3.29, 0.75, 3.88, 0.93 and 8.63 respectively.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19883435&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;19883435&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The number of asbestos fibers in the stomach was 53,000/g, which was higher than that in a control asbestosis subject.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19921706&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;19921706&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Standardized incidence ratios (SIR) were calculated for malignant mesothelioma, lung cancer, and laryngeal, pharyngeal, stomach, and colorectal cancers according to service aboard between 1950 and 1987 and in other Navy personnel. […] No elevated risk of laryngeal, pharyngeal, or stomach cancers was seen.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20104527&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;20104527&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In contrast, several platinum sensitive tumours, including primary ovarian, stomach and colorectal cancer, are characterised by ASS1 overexpression, which is regulated by proinflammatory cytokines.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20122610&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;20122610&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The significant factors of the EM in the univariate analysis were the presence of high-risk tumors (lung, stomach, soft tissue, bladder, esophagus, prostate, cervix, and lymphoma), the low Karnofsky performance score (KPS) (p&amp;lt;0.0001), the low pH value of the fluid (p=0.05), and the low concentration of glucose (p=0.01), total protein (p&amp;lt;0.0001), and albumin (p&amp;lt;0.0001) in the fluid.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20371957&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;20371957&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Tumor recurrence was detected in the stomach due to vomiting of blood, and also spread to the mediastinal lymph node, and bone 3 months postoperatively. […] In the previously reported cases, all of the localized malignant mesothelioma arose in the pleural space and there was no metastasis of localized malignant mesothelioma to the stomach.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2051987&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2051987&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The variety of the neoplasms in these cases were carcinomas of the stomach, pancreas, esophagus, renal pelvis, bile duct, colon and urinary bladder, and pleural mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21173562&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;21173562&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The 6x6 cm sized huge mass was seen on the body of stomach adjacent to the peritoneum.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2328062&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2328062&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
To evaluate the usefulness of immunohistochemistry in the diagnostic distinction between pleural mesothelioma and metastatic adenocarcinoma to the pleura, the authors studied formalin-fixed paraffin-embedded tissue sections from 14 pleural mesotheliomas and 20 primary adenocarcinomas of the lung, stomach, ovary and breast by using 16 commercially available antibodies to cytokeratin (KL1), vimentin, EMA, CEA, CA19.9, CA125, Egp 34 (detected by HEA 125), secretory component, S100 protein, SP1-béta 1, Leu M1, alpha-1-AT, alpha-1-ACT, lysozyme, desmin and factor VIII. […] Interestingly, two adenocarcinomas (of the ovary and the stomach) that failed to stain for CEA, were immunoreactive to anti-CA 19.9 antibody.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23673453&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;23673453&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Sixty-three patients (mean age 58 years, range 19-86 years; 23 women, 40 men) referred for either staging or restaging/follow-up of various malignant tumours (malignant melanoma, lung cancer, breast cancer, Hodgkin’s lymphoma, non-Hodgkin’s lymphoma, CUP, gynaecology tumours, pleural mesothelioma, oesophageal cancer, colorectal cancer, stomach cancer) were prospectively included.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2423390&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2423390&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We have found that metastatic adenocarcinoma cells from breast, ovary, endometrium, cervix, colon and stomach, as well as squamous cell carcinomas and malignant mesothelioma stain specifically with antibodies to cytokeratin while mesenchymally derived tumors such as malignant lymphomas, malignant melanomas, and fibrosarcomas, are positive for vimentin only.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24966978&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;24966978&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In this article, we report a case of a Localized malignant mesothelioma that was developed in the stomach of a 6-year-old boy. […] Partial resection of the stomach was performed for this boy and no nodules were found on the liver, peritoneum, and other abdominal sites in surgery. […] This is the first case report of localized malignant mesothelioma arising in the stomach of a child.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2550048&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2550048&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The separate and combined effects of duration and intensity of exposure to crocidolite on mortality from lung cancer, malignant mesothelioma, and stomach cancer were examined in 6506 male former crocidolite miners and millers at Wittenoom Gorge, Western Australia. […] Each subject who had died from lung cancer (92), mesothelioma (31), or stomach cancer (17) was matched with up to 20 control subjects of the same age who were not known to have died before the index subject. […] There was no consistent effect of any measure of exposure to crocidolite on death from stomach cancer.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25599121&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;25599121&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Compared with native Swedes, the highest risk of cancer was observed for nasopharyngeal carcinoma in Southeast Asian men (standardized incidence ratio=35.6) and women (24.6), for hypopharyngeal carcinoma in Indian men (5.4), for squamous-cell carcinoma of the esophagus in Iranian women (3.8), for cardia of the stomach in East Asian women (4.2), for signet-ring cell carcinoma of the stomach in Southeast Asian women (6.7), for the liver in East Asian men (6.8), for the gall bladder in Indian women (3.8), for the pancreas in North African men (2.2), for large cell carcinoma of the lung in former Yugoslavian men (4.2), for pleural mesothelioma in Turkish women (23.8), for the cervix in Danes (1.6), for seminoma in Chileans (2.1), for transitional-cell carcinoma of the bladder in Asian Arab men (2.3), for meningioma in former Yugoslavians (1.3), and for papillary carcinoma of the thyroid in East and Southeast Asian men (3.6). […] In conclusion, environmental and behavioral factors, early-childhood exposures, and infections may play a major role in the risk of esophageal, stomach, liver, nasopharyngeal and hypopharyngeal cancers, malignant pleural mesothelioma, breast, gynecological, testicular, urinary bladder, and thyroid cancers.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25731566&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;25731566&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Partial resection of the stomach and liver was performed in December 2006, followed by chemotherapy with adriamycin and interferon; resection of a recurrent tumor in the left subphrenic space was performed in December 2007. […] In June 2011, recurrent tumors were detected in the lesser curvature of the stomach body and left inferior quadrant of the abdomen (12 mm [SUVmax 7.9] and 23 mm [SUVmax 10.5], respectively)by using 18F-fluorodeoxyglucose-positron emission tomography (FDG-PET).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2829959&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2829959&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Statistically significant excess death rates were observed in men for neoplasms, particularly malignant mesothelioma (32 deaths), neoplasms of the trachea, bronchus, and lung (SMR 2.64), and neoplasms of the stomach (SMR 1.90); respiratory diseases, particularly pneumoconiosis (SMR 25.5); infections, particularly tuberculosis (SMR 4.09); mental disorders particularly alcoholism (SMR 4.87); digestive diseases, particularly peptic ulceration (SMR 2.46) and cirrhosis of the liver (SMR 3.94); and injuries and poisonings, particularly non-transport accidents (SMR 2.36). […] The excess mortality from pneumoconiosis, malignant mesothelioma, and respiratory cancers, but not stomach neoplasms, was dependent on time since first exposure and cumulative exposure.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28517082&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;28517082&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Planning objectives were: Lyman model NTCP for both lungs &amp;lt; 25%; contralateral lung, mean dose &amp;lt; 8 Gy; heart, V30 Gy &amp;lt; 50%, mean &amp;lt; 30 Gy; Each Kidney, V18 Gy &amp;lt; 33%; liver_not_GTV, mean &amp;lt; 30 Gy, V30 Gy &amp;lt; 50%; stomach not PTV, mean &amp;lt; 30 Gy; cord maximum &amp;lt; 45 Gy; bowel maximum &amp;lt; 55 Gy, D05 &amp;lt; 45 Gy; PTV D95 = 94%, V95 = 94%, D05 = 115%.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29235141&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;29235141&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Autopsy showed solid tumor with hemorrhage, measuring 6 cm in diameter, in the pancreatic tail, with wide invasion to the stomach, left adrenal gland, spleen, and diaphragm.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30847193&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30847193&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We describe a case of complete intrathoracic stomach and intestinal herniation after pleurectomy/decortication due to diaphragm reconstruction without mesh.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30944296&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30944296&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We performed an autopsy and found that ESCC had invaded the lung, pleura, peritoneum, liver, stomach, ureter, bladder, spine, and lymph nodes.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32562788&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;32562788&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
For similar target coverage and plan inhomogeneity, RP significantly improved the sparing of the contralateral lung, heart, stomach, esophagus and ipsilateral kidney. […] Mean dose to the stomach and esophagus were both reduced by 5 Gy (p&amp;lt;0.001) and the ipsilateral kidney V18 Gy by 4.1% (p&amp;lt;0.001).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/3499174&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;3499174&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
During the follow up from 1980 to 1985, three cases of lung cancer, two of pleural malignant mesothelioma, and one of stomach cancer were found among the cohort members.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/3606968&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;3606968&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
A more detailed examination of causes of death shows that the excess in gastrointestinal cancer was largely due to a statistically significant excess in stomach cancer.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/4067615&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;4067615&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The primary malignancy included lung in 15 patients, breast in two patients, and carcinoma of the stomach, ovary, pleural mesothelioma, chronic granulocytic leukemia, and adenocarcinoma of unknown primary in one patient each.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/7115133&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;7115133&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The tumor overgrew the liver, spleen, pancreatic gland, stomach, and intestinal loops forming a single conglomerate.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8328242&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;8328242&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In males, cancer of the gastrointestinal tract, pancreas and liver were the most frequently observed forms, whereas in females tumors at gynecologic sites far outnumbered other neoplasms, such as stomach, bowel, pancreas, gallbladder and liver cancer.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8341471&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;8341471&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Stomach cancer mortality risk was raised for machine tool operators (SMR = 357; 95% CI: 128-782).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8508751&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;8508751&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Thirty-eight horses with confirmed thoracic neoplasia included 28 (37.7%) with lymphosarcoma, 4 (10.5%) with metastatic renal cell carcinoma, 2 (5.3%) with primary lung carcinoma, 2 (5.3%) with secondary squamous cell carcinoma from the stomach, 1 (2.6%) with pleural mesothelioma, and 1 (2.6%) with malignant melanoma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8536224&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;8536224&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Pleural and ascitic fluids (PAF) are complications of both nonmalignant and malignant conditions, such as congestive heart failure and chronic infections, as well as neoplasias, such as mesothelioma, lymphoma, and adenocarcinomas of the lung, ovary, endometrium, breast, colon, stomach, and pancreas.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8821355&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;8821355&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In some studies an increased risk for stomach cancer has been found. […] However, the socioeconomic status of the workers is strongly related to stomach cancer, and factors, such as dietary habits, have not been taken into account in any of the reviewed studies.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9290688&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;9290688&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The primary malignancies included carcinoma of the colon (n = 17), stomach (n = 6), appendix (n = 6), pseudomyxoma peritonei (n = 3), mesothelium (n = 2), ovaries (n = 2), jejunum (n = 2), gallbladder (n = 1), urachus (n = 1), and peritoneal carcinomatosis (n = 2).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
