<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mesothelioma</title>
    <link>/mesothelioma/drugpanel/gemcitabine/</link>
      <atom:link href="/mesothelioma/drugpanel/gemcitabine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>mesothelioma</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>BioHub - UFPE</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/mesothelioma/images/icon_hu7e12209333f22d741aca7d462871821f_9877_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>mesothelioma</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/drugpanel/gemcitabine/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>GEMCITABINE</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/drugpanel/gemcitabine/info/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/mesothelioma/drugpanel/gemcitabine/info/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/mesothelioma/mesotheliomarmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;font-size:16px&#34;&gt;
DrugBank ID: &lt;a href=&#39;https://www.drugbank.ca/drugs/db00441&#39; target=&#39;_blank&#39;&gt;db00441&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
DrugCentral: &lt;a href=&#34;http://drugcentral.org/?q=gemcitabine&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;gemcitabine&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
Synonymous :2’-deoxy-2’,2’-difluorocytidine | 2’,2’-difluorodeoxycytidine | 4-amino-1-((2r,4r,5r)-3,3-difluoro-4-hydroxy-5-(hydroxymethyl)-tetrahydrofuran-2-yl)pyrimidin-2(1h)-one | gemcitabin | gemcitabina | gemcitabine | gemcitabinum
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;drug-sentece-context&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Drug Sentece Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;font-size:12px&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Table 1.&lt;/strong&gt; Analysis of context sentence of &lt;em&gt;gemcitabine&lt;/em&gt; gene in 147 abstracts.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;table table-striped&#34; style=&#34;width: auto !important; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
pmid
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
sentence
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10194545&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;10194545&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We report about a patient with locally advanced, unresectable pleural mesothelioma treated with the nucleoside analog gemcitabine (2,2-difluorodeoxycytidine). […] A 54-year-old male patient with unresectable pleural mesothelioma confirmed by thoracoscopic biopsy was treated with seven cycles of gemcitabine (1000 mg/m2 on day 1, 8 and 15) over a period of 36 weeks. […] Gemcitabine seems to be an active drug for the treatment of pleural mesothelioma. […] Because of these characteristics gemcitabine seems a suitable antineoplastic substance, especially in palliative settings.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10375105&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;10375105&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Gemcitabine has shown activity in patients with less chemosensitive solid tumors. […] Twenty-seven chemotherapy-naive patients with histologically proven malignant mesothelioma were treated with gemcitabine as a 30-minute intravenous administration of 1250 mg/m2 on Days 1, 8, and 15 of a 28-day cycle. […] One case of hemolytic-uremic syndrome, most likely related to gemcitabine use, was observed. […] At the prescribed dosage and schedule, single agent gemcitabine appears to have limited activity in chemotherapy-naive patients with malignant pleural mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10458214&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;10458214&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We performed a phase II study of combined cisplatin 100 mg/m2, given intravenously on day 1, and gemcitabine 1,000 mg/m2, given intravenously on days 1, 8, and 15 of a 28-day cycle for six cycles among patients with advanced measurable pleural mesothelioma. […] Ninety-four cycles were given (median, six; mean, 4.5 per patient), with a mean relative dose intensity of cisplatin 96.7% and gemcitabine 82.5%. […] Combined cisplatin and gemcitabine is an active combination in malignant mesothelioma and produces symptomatic benefit in responding patients.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11224994&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;11224994&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Current chemotherapy is severely lacking in producing objective responses and improved survival although gemcitabine and IL-2 may be active agents to be combined with radiation and/or other agents.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11875695&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;11875695&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
However, a recent single institution study showed an impressive activity of gemcitabine and cisplatin. […] Our aim is to investigate the efficacy and toxicity of a gemcitabine and cisplatin combination in selected and chemo-naive patients with histologically proven malignant pleural mesothelioma. […] Gemcitabine 1250 mg m(-2) was administered on day 1 and day 8 and cisplatin 80 mg m(-2) was administered on day 1 in a 3-week cycle with a maximum of six cycles. […] In conclusion this trial excludes with 90% power a response rate of greater than 30% in patients with malignant pleural mesothelioma using a combination of gemcitabine and cisplatin at the proposed dose and schedule.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12023790&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;12023790&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Recently, a renewed interest in MPM led to clinical trials with promising preliminary results for several agents alone or in combination, including gemcitabine, raltitrexed, vinorelbine, and pemetrexed.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12057157&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;12057157&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The most active commercially available drug for mesothelioma so far appears to be gemcitabine. […] Although gemcitabine has a limited role as a single agent, it is quite active in combination with a platinating agent. […] The impressive 48% response rate reported for the combination of gemcitabine with cisplatin in a single phase II study has made this regimen the new standard of care for off-protocol treatment of this disease, although this trial still requires validation.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12189542&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;12189542&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Our previous phase II study of cisplatin and gemcitabine in malignant mesothelioma showed a 47.6% (95% CI 26.2-69.0%) response rate with symptom improvement in responding patients. […] Fifty-three patients with pleural malignant mesothelioma received cisplatin 100 mg m(-2) i.v. day 1 and gemcitabine 1000 mg m(-2) i.v. days 1, 8, and 15 of a 28 day cycle for a maximum of six cycles. […] Major toxicities were haematological, limiting the mean relative dose intensity of gemcitabine to 75%. […] This schedule of cisplatin and gemcitabine is active in malignant mesothelioma in a multicentre setting. […] Investigation of alternative scheduling is needed to decrease haematological toxicity and increase the relative dose intensity of gemcitabine whilst maintaining response rate and quality of life.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12601280&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;12601280&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Furthermore, raltitrexed-oxaliplatin has shown promising activity and gemcitabine was found to improve quality of life in patients with malignant pleural mesothelioma when applied as a single agent or in combination with cisplatin.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12610498&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;12610498&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Raltitrexed combined with oxaliplatin has also been shown to be effective, and gemcitabine-applied as a single agent or in combination with cisplatin-as well as vinorelbine appear to improve the quality of life in patients presenting with MPM.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12722691&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;12722691&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Recently, some reports revealed that gemcitabine (GEM), which has been demonstrated to be effective for the treatment of non-small cell lung carcinoma, was effective in cases of diffuse malignant pleural mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12767092&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;12767092&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Chemotherapy was comprised of carboplatin area under the concentration-time curve 5 on Day 1 and gemcitabine 1000 mg/m(2) on Days 1, 8, and 15. […] The delivered dose intensity of gemcitabine was 617 mg/m(2) per week, which was 82% of the planned dose (750 mg/m(2) per week). […] The gemcitabine/carboplatin combination is a valid option in the treatment of MPM due to its acceptable toxicity profile, the good response rate, and the clinical benefit to patients.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12795087&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;12795087&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The combination of gemcitabine plus cisplatin has become a standard regimen, although there has been significant variability in response rates between studies.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12800189&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;12800189&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In addition to the direct induction of apoptosis, antisense treatment sensitized ZL34 cells to the cytostatic effect of cisplatin and gemcitabine, with the combination of 4625 and cisplatin being the most effective. […] Our results demonstrate that Bcl-2 and Bcl-xL antisense treatment facilitates apoptosis in mesothelioma cells and suggest the use of Bcl-2/Bcl-xL bispecific antisense treatment in combination with cisplatin or gemcitabine for therapy of malignant pleural mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12892825&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;12892825&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The purpose of this study was to examine the antiproliferative potentialities of a pool of new generation compounds (Paclitaxel, Docetaxel, Gemcitabine, Topotecan, SN-38) together with fenretinide, a synthetic derivative of retinoic acid, in comparison with the current first choice treatment cisplatin molecule, on a pool of human malignant pleural mesothelioma cell lines derived from either bioptic and pleural effusions samples.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12917819&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;12917819&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Regimens with antimetabolites such as gemcitabine administered alone or in combination with cisplatin have shown promising phase II study data.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/14609447&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;14609447&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We conducted a phase II multicenter trial to evaluate the activity of combined gemcitabine and oxaliplatin in malignant pleural mesothelioma. […] Twenty-five patients were recruited between May 1999 and December 2001 and received gemcitabine 1000 mg/m2 intravenously over 30 minutes and oxaliplatin 80 mg/m2 intravenously over 3 hours on days 1 and 8 of a 21-day cycle for a maximum of 6 cycles. […] The combination of gemcitabine and oxaliplatin was shown to be active in malignant pleural mesothelioma and to exhibit tolerable toxicity in an outpatient setting.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/14725755&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;14725755&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
This study describes the therapeutic effect of carboplatin and gemcitabine in combination for malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/14760119&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;14760119&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We evaluated 73 patients from two clinical trials of cisplatin/gemcitabine chemotherapy in malignant pleural mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15255294&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15255294&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We conducted a phase II study of OK-432 intrapleural administration followed by systemic chemotherapy using cisplatin with gemcitabine to determine their combined effects on non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) with pleuritis carcinomatosa. […] They were then treated every three weeks with chemotherapy consisting of 80 mg/m2 cisplatin on day 1 and 1000 mg/m2 gemcitabine on days 1 and 8. […] In conclusion, OK-432 intrapleural administration followed by cisplatin and gemcitabine systemic chemotherapy did not reduce patients’ tumors but did prolong their survival time.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15261443&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15261443&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Raltitrexed combined with oxaliplatin has also been shown to be effective, and gemcitabine–applied as a single agent or in combination with cisplatin–as well as vinorelbine appear to improve quality of life in patients presenting with MPM.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15337794&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15337794&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
To investigate neoadjuvant chemotherapy with cisplatin and gemcitabine followed by extrapleural pneumonectomy with or without radiation therapy in patients with potentially resectable malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM). […] Neoadjuvant chemotherapy consisted of three cycles of cisplatin 80 mg/m2 on day 1 and gemcitabine 1,000 mg/m2 on days 1, 8, and 15, given every 28 days.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15510816&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15510816&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The patient received 2 courses of postoperative chemotherapy using cisplatin and gemcitabine.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15545953&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15545953&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The second patient (age 30 years) was alive 40 months after 15 chemotherapy cycles using a platinim-gemcitabine combination.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15559059&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15559059&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
New chemotherapy agents, including gemcitabine (Eli Lilly and Company; Indianapolis, Indiana) and pemtrexed (Eli Lilly and Company) show promise against mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15559064&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15559064&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Other chemotherapy regimens with encouraging activity in mesothelioma include the combination of cisplatin and gemcitabine, with response rates ranging from 16% to 48%. […] Kestenholz et al currently are performing a phase II clinical trial of neoadjuvant cisplatin and gemcitabine administered for three cycles followed by EPP and adjuvant radiation therapy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15677623&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15677623&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Other combinations, including cisplatin and gemcitabine, have also shown encouraging response rates and clinical activity.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15724224&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15724224&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
After a first line therapy with Gemcitabine/Oxaliplatin, partial remission was assessed. 15 months later a distinct progress was detected.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15849999&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15849999&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
They were treated with epirubicin (100 mg/m2 iv on day 1) plus gemcitabine (1000 mg/m2 iv on days 1 and 8) every 4 weeks for 6 cycles. […] A total of 124 epirubicin-gemcitabine cycles were administered (median, 6/patient; range, 2-6). […] This multi-center phase II clinical trial showed that epirubicin plus gemcitabine, as a first-line treatment in malignant pleural mesothelioma, has promising activity with a good tolerability profile and symptom palliation.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15923792&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15923792&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Aims of this study were to evaluate the activity and toxicity of gemcitabine and cisplatin combination in malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM). […] Patients received gemcitabine 1250 mg/m intravenously on days 1 and 8 and cisplatin 75 mg/m on day 2, every 21 days, for a maximum of 6 cycles. […] In conclusion, gemcitabine-cisplatin combination seems to be moderately active in MPM.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15950791&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15950791&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Among chemotherapeutic agents only vinorelbine, edatrexate, gemcitabine and raltitrexed have demonstrated response rates &amp;gt;20%.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15950805&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15950805&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Induction therapy was: gemcitabine (1250 mg/m2 days 1, 8) and cisplatin (75 mg/m2 day 8)x2-4 cycles.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16006571&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16006571&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We investigated the use of triplet combination chemotherapy with cisplatin (CDDP), gemcitabine (GEM) and vinorelbine (VNR) for the treatment of Japanese patients with MPM.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16101199&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16101199&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Combination chemotherapy included cisplatin-gemcitabine, cisplatin (or carboplatin) with premetrexed and doxorubicin-cyclophosphamide.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16143373&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16143373&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Two such agents, gemcitabine and pemetrexed, underwent clinical development and are now among Lilly’s portfolio of approved anticancer drugs. […] Gemcitabine, a pyrimidine nucleoside that has a profound effect on DNA synthesis, has been approved for the treatment of pancreatic, non-small cell lung, bladder, and most recently, breast, and ovarian cancer.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16291410&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16291410&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Results of an international, multicenter Phase III trial of pemetrexed in combination with gemcitabine conducted in patients with pancreatic cancer indicate that the combination is no more efficacious than single-agent gemcitabine.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16291426&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16291426&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Pemetrexed also has promising activity and acceptable toxicity when combined with platinum compounds or gemcitabine.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16343925&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16343925&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Cisplatin and gemcitabine regimen as well as cisplatin/pemetrexed followed by 54 Gy of adjuvant hemithorax radiation have been reported to improve the outcome.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16475242&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16475242&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The infectivity, selective replication, vector spread and cytotoxic ability of three oncolytic HSV: G207, NV1020 and NV1066, were tested against eleven pathological types of MPM cell lines including those that are resistant to radiation therapy, gemcitabine or cisplatin. […] Even at very low concentrations of MOI 0.01 (MOI: multiplicity of viral infection, ratio of viral particles per cancer cell), HSV were highly effective against MPM cells that are resistant to radiation, gemcitabine and cisplatin.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16495068&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16495068&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Patients with histologically proven mesothelioma of clinical stages T1-3, N0-2, M0 and considered to be completely resectable received neoadjuvant chemotherapy (cisplatin+gemcitabine or cisplatin+pemetrexed) followed by extrapleural pneumonectomy and postoperative radiotherapy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16542214&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16542214&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Treatment with cisplatin, but not gemcitabine, significantly inhibited the production of pleural effusions, but it was not effective for thoracic tumors, consistent with chemotherapy refractory characteristics of MPM in patients.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16542747&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16542747&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We performed a multicenter phase II trial to evaluate the impact on the activity, efficacy, symptom control and safety of using two active regimens in a sequential schedule (cisplatin/gemcitabine followed by mitoxantrone/methotrexate/mitomycin) as first-line chemotherapy for unresectable malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM). […] A total of 54 patients received cisplatin 75 mg/m(2) on day 1 and gemcitabine 1,200 mg/m(2) on days 1 and 8, every 3 weeks for four courses (CG regimen) followed by mitoxantrone 10 mg/m(2) on day 1, methotrexate 35 mg/m(2) on day 1 and mitomycin 7 mg/m(2) on day 1, every 3 weeks with mitomycin in alternate cycles for four courses (MMM regimen).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16616827&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16616827&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Other cytotoxic agents that have shown to be active in this setting include vinorelbine and gemcitabine, either alone or combined with platinum compounds.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16778277&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16778277&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Nineteen patients with a diagnosis of MPM who were scheduled to receive chemotherapy with gemcitabine were enrolled in the study.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16828196&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16828196&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
An impressive activity of gemcitabine and cisplatin combination in malignant mesothelioma has been shown. […] The aim of this study is to investigate the efficacy and toxicity of divided dose of cisplatin combined with gemcitabine in chemo-naïve patients with malignant mesothelioma. […] Cisplatin 35 mg/m(2) and gemcitabine 800 mg/m(2) were administered on days 1 and 8 as intravenous infusion in a 3-week cycle, up to maximum 6 cycles. […] Divided dose of cisplatin combined with gemcitabine, at the current dosage and schedule, appears to be an active regimen in chemotherapy-naïve patients with malignant mesothelioma, and well-tolerated.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17087330&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;17087330&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
As the disease was not changed after combination chemotherapy with three cycles of cisplatin and gemcitabine, we performed left extrapleural pneumonectomy, including resection of the pericardium and diaphragm for MPM, and aortopexy for right aortic arch.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17144577&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;17144577&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Chemotherapy with gemcitabine and vinorelbine could not control the progression.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17174436&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;17174436&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Chemotherapy protocols included a combination of cisplatin, mitomycin C and recombinant interferon alpha 2a (CM-In), or cisplatin, mitomycin C and ifosfamide (CMI), or cisplatin and gemcitabine (CG).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17188885&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;17188885&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
From 1999 to 2004, 49 patients with IMIG stage II-III MPM underwent a multimodality treatment including: intrapleural pre-operative interleukin 2 (IL-2, 18x10(6) UI/day per 3 days), pleurectomy/decortication, intrapleural post-operative epidoxorubicin (25mg/m2 per 3 days), IL-2 (18x10(6) UI/day per 3 days), adjuvant radiotherapy (30Gy), systemic chemotherapy (cisplatin 80 mg/m2 day 1, gemcitabine 1250 mg/m2 day 1 and 8 up to 6 courses) and long-term sub-cutaneous IL-2 (3x10(6) UI/day 3 days per week).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17311837&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;17311837&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Of the chemotherapeutic agents tested in combination with imatinib, a synergistic effect was obtained with gemcitabine and pemetrexed.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17403553&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;17403553&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Induction chemotherapy consisted of Carboplatin (AUC 5mg/mL/min on Day 1) and Gemcitabine (1000mg/m(2) on Days 1, 8, 15) for three to four cycles. […] In MPM, the combined modality approach using the Carboplatin/Gemcitabine combination as induction chemotherapy is feasible, with good results in terms of survival and morbidity.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17409872&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;17409872&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Induction therapy was four cycles of gemcitabine and cisplatin. […] Induction chemotherapy with gemcitabine and cisplatin followed by EPP and adjuvant RT for locally advanced MPM is feasible and leads to a better median overall survival than that previously reported with EPP and RT alone.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17410047&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;17410047&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
From 1999 to 2004, 49 patients with International Mesothelioma Interest Group stage II-III MPM underwent four-modality treatment with intrapleural preoperative interleukin-2 (18 x 10(6) UI/day for 3 days), pleurectomy/decortication, intrapleural postoperative epidoxorubicin (25 mg/m2 for 3 days), interleukin-2 (18 x 10(6) UI/day for 3 days), adjuvant radiotherapy (30 Gy), systemic chemotherapy (cisplatin 80 mg/m2 day 1, gemcitabine 1250 mg/m2 days 1 and 8 for up to six courses) and long-term subcutaneous interleukin-2 (3 x 10(6) UI/day on 3 days per week).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17429100&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;17429100&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Neo-adjuvant chemotherapy consisted of three cycles of cisplatin and gemcitabine followed by EPP.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18006112&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18006112&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The purpose of this open-label phase II SWOG study was to evaluate the activity of gemcitabine (Gemzar; Eli Lilly, Indiana, USA) and cisplatin combination therapy, in patients with unresectable malignant mesothelioma of the pleura. […] Treatment consisted of gemcitabine 1000mg/m(2) and cisplatin 30mg/m(2) on days 1, 8 and 15 of a 28-day cycle, until progression of disease or two cycles beyond complete response. […] Cisplatin-gemcitabine combination chemotherapy has modest activity with an acceptable toxicity profile, as first line treatment for patients with malignant mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18063861&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18063861&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In phase II studies exploring this multitargeted antifolate in advanced gastrointestinal tumors, pemetrexed showed an interesting degree of clinical activity, encouraging further trials evaluating the synergism with other drugs such as oxaliplatin, irinotecan and gemcitabine.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18286536&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18286536&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Gemcitabine and vinorelbine have shown activity in the first-line setting. […] The objective of this study was to evaluate the activity and toxicity of the gemcitabine-vinorelbine combination in pemetrexed-pretreated patients with MPM. […] Gemcitabine 1000 mg/m(2) and vinorelbine 25 mg/m(2) were administered intravenously on Days 1 and 8 every 3 weeks. […] The gemcitabine and vinorelbine combination was moderately active and had an acceptable toxicity profile in pemetrexed-pretreated patients with MPM.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18349397&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18349397&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Pemetrexed and gemcitabine have single-agent activity in malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM). […] The combination of pemetrexed/gemcitabine has not previously been studied in MPM to our knowledge. […] Cohort 1 received gemcitabine 1,250 mg/m(2) on days 1 and 8, with pemetrexed 500 mg/m(2) on day 8, and cohort 2 received gemcitabine 1,250 mg/m(2) on days 1 and 8, with pemetrexed 500 mg/m(2) on day 1. […] The combination of pemetrexed and gemcitabine resulted in moderate clinical activity in MPM.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18523361&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18523361&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We report the case of a 56-year-old patient with malignant pleural mesothelioma of epithelial type, who responded to second-line chemotherapy with lipoplatin plus gemcitabine. […] Treatment with lipoplatin-gemcitabine was decided on in November 2006, and the patient showed important improvement in the clinical status and peritoneal effusion.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18560222&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18560222&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
With the aim of finding an optimal schedule for the combination therapy of MTA and gemcitabine (GEM), we investigated their interaction against an MPM cell line, 211H, and the NSCLC cell lines A549 and H1299.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18640937&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18640937&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Pemetrexed and gemcitabine are synergistic in preclinical models, but the activity of this combination in MPeM is unknown. […] This clinical study assessed safety and efficacy of pemetrexed plus gemcitabine in chemotherapy-naïve patients with MPeM. […] Treatment consisted of gemcitabine 1,250 mg/m(2) on days 1 and 8, and pemetrexed 500 mg/m(2) on day 8, administered immediately before gemcitabine. […] The combination of pemetrexed plus gemcitabine was active in patients with MPeM with a notably high incidence of neutropenia.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18839036&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18839036&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
To evaluate the efficacy, safety, and clinical benefit of combined gemcitabine and carboplatin in patients with previously untreated malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM). […] They were assigned to receive combined gemcitabine (1250mg/m2) on days, 1 and 8 and carboplatin (AUC 6) on day 1. […] The combination of gemcitabine and carboplatin is a safe and tolerable treatment with reasonable response rate, OS, and PFS compared with the historical phase II single agents and combined chemotherapy studies in patients with MPM.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18978569&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18978569&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The Nordic Mesothelioma groups decided in the year 2000 to investigate a combination of liposomized doxorubicin, carboplatin, and gemcitabine for this disease in a phase II study.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19004520&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;19004520&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
However, the combination of cisplatin and gemcitabine was incorporated into clinical practice following publication of promising phase II trial results in 1999. […] The clinical records of individuals referred to the BC Cancer Agency were reviewed, and those treated with a platinum analog plus gemcitabine or pemetrexed as first-line therapy were included in survival analyses. […] During the selected period, 81 patients were treated first-line with a platinum analog plus gemcitabine (n=40) or pemetrexed (n=41). […] No difference is seen combining platinum analogs with gemcitabine or pemetrexed.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19091133&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;19091133&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The aim of this study was to investigate the efficacy and safety of oxaliplatin +/- gemcitabine in patients with diffuse malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM) pretreated with pemetrexed. […] Oxaliplatin 80 mg/m2 was administered as monotherapy or in combination with gemcitabine 1000 mg/m2 given on day 1 and 8. […] The majority of the patients received the combination oxaliplatin and gemcitabine (n = 25 vs. […] The median overall survival (OS) was 71.7 weeks (30.6-243.3 weeks), whereas survival from the start of oxaliplatin/gemcitabine-treatment was 24.3 weeks (5.4-97.3 weeks). […] Pemetrexed-pretreated patients with progressive MPM may benefit from a consecutive chemotherapy with oxaliplatin and gemcitabine without significant toxicity.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19131921&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;19131921&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
CD-DST using 26 fresh specimens obtained by biopsy or surgery on MPM patients investigated in vitro responses to cisplatin (CDDP), carboplatin (CBDCA), doxorubicin (ADR), etoposide (VP-16), 5-fluoruracil (5-FU), gemcitabine (GEM), vinorelbine (VNR), irinotecan (SN-38), and docetaxel (TXT).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19224855&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;19224855&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Chemotherapy regimens included cisplatin/vinorelbine (n = 26), cisplatin/pemetrexed (n = 24), cisplatin/raltitrexed (n = 6), or cisplatin/gemcitabine (n = 4).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19514493&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;19514493&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
One patient had long survived (41.6 months) with gemcitabine-based chemotherapy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19514499&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;19514499&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The patient received first-line chemotherapy with carboplatin plus gemcitabine, and underwent pleurodesis with carboplatin. […] After 16 months, recurrence of the tumor with pleural effusion was observed, and single agent vinorelbine as second-line treatment (6 cycles) and single agent gemcitabine as third-line treatment (6 cycles) were administered sequentially.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19568885&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;19568885&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Other combinations, including gemcitabine in combination with cisplatin, have also shown encouraging response rates.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19577816&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;19577816&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The next step was to test pemetrexed plus cisplatin versus gemcitabine plus cisplatin, as first-line therapy in advanced NSCLC patients, in a phase III, non-inferiority, randomized trial.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19588835&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;19588835&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
She was referred to our hospital for surgery, and was undergone an extrapleural pneumonectomy followed by postoperative treatment with cisplatin puls gemcitabine.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19661370&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;19661370&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The cisplatin-pemetrexed and cisplatin-gemcitabine combinations are considered the standard treatment for malignant pleural mesothelioma. […] The purpose of this study was to examine the efficacy of gemcitabine plus docetaxel in the first-line setting, as this combination has not been investigated in mesothelioma before. […] They received 80 mg/m(2) of docetaxel and 1,000 mg/m(2) of gemcitabine on days 1 and 14 of a 28-day cycle. […] The administration of gemcitabine and doctaxel appears to be promising first-line therapy for patients with mesothelioma, as it is well tolerated and appears to improve survival.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19736192&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;19736192&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Other active agents include raltitrexed, gemcitabine, and vinorelbine.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20142722&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;20142722&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The combinations of cisplatin-pemetrexed and cisplatin-gemcitabine are considered the standard systemic therapy for malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM), which is a rapidly progressive tumor. […] The purpose of the present study is to evaluate the efficacy, safety, and clinical benefit of the gemcitabine plus docetaxel regimen in the second-line treatment of this disease. […] A total of 37 patients with MPM were treated with the combination of docetaxel (80 mg/m) and gemcitabine (1000 mg/m) on day 1 and 14 of a 28-day cycle. […] The biweekly administration of docetaxel and gemcitabine, along with granulocyte colony-stimulating factor support, constitutes a safe, tolerable, and convenient regimen for the treatment of MPM, suggesting that this combination may be a viable option, especially in previously treated patients.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20332689&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;20332689&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Although vinorelbine, gemcitabine and S-1 were administered subsequently because of the re-growth of the lesions, they were enlarged.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20369238&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;20369238&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The present study addresses the optimization of gemcitabine-cisplatin protocols currently adopted in the clinical management of malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM), using cell lines derived from different histological subtypes of MPM as an in vitro model. […] Four-hour pre-treatment with gemcitabine followed by 68-h exposure to cisplatin was found to exert synergistic activity in both epithelioid and sarcomatoid MPM subtypes, inducing a strong S-phase arrest that correlated with accumulation of double-strand breaks (DSBs). […] The antiproliferative effects of the gemcitabine/cisplatin combination in mesothelioma cells can be maximized by pre-treatment with gemcitabine, suggesting that this drug increases cisplatin-induced DSBs by inhibiting DNA adduct repair.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20534685&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;20534685&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The chemotherapeutic agent added to platinum was gemcitabine in one patient, cyclophosphamide-doxorubicin in three patients and pemetrexed in 10 patients.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20603247&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;20603247&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We report a case of relapsed malignant pleural mesothelioma in which the patient failed to respond to pemetrexed-based chemotherapy but was successfully treated with gemcitabine and vinorelbine. […] Then, 1000 mg/m(2) gemcitabine and 25 mg/m(2) vinorelbine were administered every 2 weeks. […] She was treated with 12 cycles of gemcitabine plus vinorelbine, and 8.5 months of progression-free survival was observed. […] Gemcitabine plus vinorelbine chemotherapy may be a candidate regimen for salvage chemotherapy against malignant pleural mesotheliomas.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20653100&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;20653100&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Each specimen was tested with 3 drugs: cisplatin, gemcitabine, and vinorelbine. […] A significant proportion of tumors had extreme/intermediate drug resistance to cisplatin (27%), gemcitabine (31%), or vinorelbine (59%). […] A significant proportion of mesothelioma tumors exhibited extreme/intermediate resistance to cisplatin, gemcitabine, or vinorelbine.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20933167&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;20933167&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The SLC was a pemetrexed therapy in 21 patients and a new regime in 20 patients (gemcitabine alone or with oxaliplatin).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21123992&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;21123992&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
He had undergone several treatments such as left pneumonectomy, pleurectomy, chemotherapy with cis-diamminedichloroplatinum and gemcitabine hydrochloride, and irradiation.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21296448&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;21296448&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We analyzed the feasibility of gemcitabine/platinum chemotherapy in pretreated MPM patients. […] Chemotherapy was gemcitabine 1000 mg/m(2) days 1, 8 associated to the alternative platinum compound respect to 1st line, i.e. cisplatin 75 mg/m(2) or carboplatin AUC 5 day 1 every 3 weeks, for 3-6 cycles. […] The combination of gemcitabine with carboplatin/cisplatin was administered as second line treatment in 13 (76%) patients, as third line in 4 (24%) patients. […] Gemcitabine-platinum regimens are able to control symptoms and disease progression with a modest toxicity profile.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21368492&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;21368492&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Chemotherapy with carboplatin, gemcitabine and radiation therapy was performed, but the patient died from deterioration of his systemic condition.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21388071&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;21388071&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
She showed an impressive response to this first-line chemotherapy and, after disease progression, to further chemotherapy with gemcitabine and vinorelbine.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21503595&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;21503595&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Several studies have reported the use of gemcitabine and cisplatin as an induction chemotherapy in combination with extrapleural pneumonectomy (EPP) and thoracic radiation in a combined-modality approach for resectable MPM.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21553148&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;21553148&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Another phase II trial did not observe any significant clinical benefit of adding of bevacizumab to gemcitabine and cisplatin.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21620489&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;21620489&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Phase II/III studies have identified pemetrexed, a multitarget folate pathway inhibitor in combination with platinum derivatives, and the cisplatin/gemcitabine association as front-line chemotherapy for hMPM.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21787763&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;21787763&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Moreover, the treatment of IST-Mes2 with TKIs (gefitinib and imatinib mesylate) in combination with cisplatin and gemcitabine did not show additivity.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22027538&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;22027538&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
After a favorable experience with gemcitabine at a low dose in a prolonged infusion in combination with cisplatin for advanced non-small-cell lung cancer, here, we present the results from a phase II trial for patients with malignant pleural mesothelioma. […] Treatment consisted of gemcitabine 250 mg/m in a 6-h infusion on days 1 and 8 and cisplatin at 75 mg/m on day 2 of a 3-week cycle for four cycles, followed by two additional cycles without cisplatin.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22345416&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;22345416&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Dual-agent neoadjuvant chemotherapy (cisplatin plus gemcitabine or pemetrexed) followed by radical surgery with or without radiotherapy has been reported to yield median survival of up to 23-29 months in small clinical trials, but larger randomized controlled studies are needed to better define the role of neoadjuvant therapy in MPM management. […] Other chemotherapeutic agents that have been used against MPM, with variable results, include gemcitabine, vinorelbine, taxanes, anthracyclines, and molecular-targeted agents.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22459200&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;22459200&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Platinum-based chemotherapy plus gemcitabine or pemetrexed for 3-4 cycles followed by surgery and postoperative high-dose radiotherapy showed the best results in terms of overall and progression free survival.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22584322&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;22584322&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
A gemcitabine(GEM)plus cisplatin(CDDP)regimen had been selected as a conventional treatment, but subsequently, pemetrexed(MTA)was covered by health insurance for pleural malignant mesothelioma in 2007, and the MTA plus CDDP regimen became the standard treatment.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22665541&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;22665541&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Gemcitabine plus cisplatin is active in malignant mesothelioma (MM), although single-arm phase II trials have reported variable outcomes. […] We added the anti-VEGF antibody bevacizumab to gemcitabine/cisplatin in a multicenter, double-blind, placebo-controlled randomized phase II trial in patients with previously untreated, unresectable MM. […] Patients received gemcitabine 1,250 mg/m(2) on days 1 and 8 every 21 days, cisplatin 75 mg/m(2) every 21 days, and bevacizumab 15 mg/kg or placebo every 21 days for six cycles, and then bevacizumab or placebo every 21 days until progression. […] The addition of bevacizumab to gemcitabine/cisplatin in this trial did not significantly improve PFS or OS in patients with advanced MM.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22722923&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;22722923&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The median survival in patients who were administered adjuvant therapy after surgery was 24 months, while the median survival in patients who had only surgery was 6 months (p = 0.029). 106 patients were administered pemetrexed-platinum combination and 35 patients were administered gemcitabine-platinum combination as front-line chemotherapy. […] Median survival, 1- and 2-year survival rates in patients who received platinum analogues and pemetrexed or gemcitabine combinations were found statistically similar (p = 0.15). […] Survival rates in patients who received combining platinum analogues with pemetrexed or gemcitabine as front-line chemotherapy were found similar.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22982660&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;22982660&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Therefore, the aim of our study was to evaluate the influence of genetic variability in DNA repair genes on treatment outcome in patients with malignant mesothelioma (MM) treated with gemcitabine-platinum combination chemotherapy. […] Our results support the hypothesis that DNA repair gene polymorphisms, particularly XRCC1 Arg399Gln, may modify the response to gemcitabine-platinum combination chemotherapy and, for the first time, show this effect in patients with MM.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23040690&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;23040690&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The addition of endostar to the gemcitabine-cisplatin regimen gave a prompt and significant improvement of clinical symptoms and disappearance of ascites.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23077450&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;23077450&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
During the last decade, several trials confirmed the benefit of systemic treatment with drugs such as doublets with cisplatina and gemcitabine or pemetrexed for carefully selected patients in good performance status. […] While a variety of older drugs were used in the first period, the most common regimen in the second period (applied to 91 patients) was doublet of low-dose gemcitabine in prolonged infusion and cisplatin. […] Modern chemotherapy, and in particular treatment with low-dose gemcitabine in prolonged infusion and cisplatin significantly prolonged median survival of patients with malignant pleural mesothelioma in Slovenia.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23135895&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;23135895&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Neoadjuvant chemotherapy consisted of a combination of platinum based agents (n = 19) with gemcitabine (n = 15) or pemetrexed (n = 4).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23151824&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;23151824&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Transarterial chemoperfusion was performed by using mitomycin C, cisplatin, and gemcitabine.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23174177&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;23174177&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The role of chemotherapeutic agents currently most commonly used in clinical practice, including cisplatin, gemcitabine, and pemetrexed, was assessed with and without simultaneous heat exposure. […] With combinations of cisplatin/gemcitabine and cisplatin/pemetrexed, the effect was larger, with reduction to 9.6%, 0%, and 0%, respectively (P &amp;lt; .01) (incremental reduction of 16.5%, 0%, and 0%, respectively, due to hyperthermia).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23329519&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;23329519&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Mean survival time for cisplatin + gemcitabine was found to be 14.49 months and for cisplatin + pemetrexed, 18.34 months.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23408040&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;23408040&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The aim of this prospective, phase II clinical study is to evaluate the activity of gemcitabine and cisplatin in comparison to pemetrexed and carboplatin in patients with malignant pleural mesothelioma. […] One group included 21 cases who received cisplatin and gemcitabine. […] For the gemcitabine cisplatin group, the cumulative survival proportion at 1.5 years was 41 % (p = 0.0599). […] Cheaper combinations as gemcitabine and cisplatin may be considered sufficient to treat cases with advanced mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23526965&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;23526965&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Here we evaluated a new combined therapy consisting of ascorbate/epigallocatechin-3-gallate/gemcitabine mixture (called AND, for Active Nutrients/Drug).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23621229&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;23621229&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Combination chemotherapy included cisplatin-gemcitabine, cisplatin-navelbine and cisplatin (or carboplatin) with premetrexed.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23898070&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;23898070&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Intrinsic or acquired resistance of pancreatic cancer to gemcitabine (2’-deoxy-2’-difluorodeoxycytidine) is an important factor in the failure of gemcitabine treatment. […] Proteomic analysis of gemcitabine-sensitive KLM1 pancreatic cancer cells and -resistant KLM1-R cells identified heat-shock protein-27(HSP27) as a biomarker protein which is involved in gemcitabine resistance. […] However, a knock-down experiment showed that HSP27 was not the only protein implicated with gemcitabine-resistance. […] Finding further candidate proteins is necessary for achieving effective gemcitabine therapy for patients with pancreatic cancer. […] In the present study, the expression of DDX39 in gemcitabine-sensitive KLM1 and -resistant KLM1-R cells was compared. […] It was found that DDX39 was significantly up-regulated in gemcitabine-resistant KLM1-R cells compared to sensitive KLM1 cells. […] These results suggest that DDX39 is a possible candidate biomarker for predicting the response of patients with pancreatic cancer to treatment with gemcitabine.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24023280&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;24023280&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Cisplatin in combination with pemetrexed or raltitrexed increased survival in MPM, whereas vinorelbine and gemcitabine have led to good response rates. […] This may also apply for gemcitabine and vinorelbine, since in contrast to pemetrexed, both agents can be obtained from generic manufacturers. […] To provide a more cost-effective treatment approach for advanced MPM, further research should include randomized controlled trials comparing the recommended pemetrexed-cisplatin directly with platinum doublets with raltitrexed, gemcitabine, or vinorelbine.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24148817&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;24148817&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Growth inhibition caused by miR-16 correlated with downregulation of target genes including Bcl-2 and CCND1, and miR-16 re-expression sensitised MPM cells to pemetrexed and gemcitabine.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24158772&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;24158772&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Between March 2008 and October 2011, 17 consecutive Japanese patients pretreated with at least one regimen of platinum plus pemetrexed chemotherapy received gemcitabine and vinorelbine. […] Combination chemotherapy using gemcitabine with vinorelbine was shown to have moderate activity in Japanese MPM patients pretreated with platinum plus pemetrexed chemotherapy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24615668&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;24615668&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Monotherapy with pemetrexed, vinorelbine or gemcitabine may provide some survival benefit compared to treatment aiming at symptom control only.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24636265&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;24636265&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
However, no clinical trials have compared the efficacy of cisplatin plus pemetrexed and cisplatin plus gemcitabine, which may be comparable based on previous phase II study results. […] This study aimed at evaluating the efficacy of cisplatin plus pemetrexed and comparing it with that of cisplatin plus gemcitabine in Japanese MPM patients. […] From July 2002 to December 2011, 13 and 17 consecutive patients with inoperable MPM were treated with cisplatin plus gemcitabine and cisplatin plus pemetrexed, respectively, at the Shizuoka Cancer Center. […] The response rates were 15% and 35% in the cisplatin plus gemcitabine and cisplatin plus pemetrexed groups, respectively (P=0.4069), while disease control rates were 77%, and 82%, respectively (P=0.9999). […] Progression-free survival was significantly higher with cisplatin plus pemetrexed (median, 215.5 days) than with cisplatin plus gemcitabine (median, 142.5 days) (P=0.0146; hazard ratio [HR], 0.3552). […] Overall survival showed a tendency towards being superior with cisplatin plus pemetrexed (median, 597.5 days) compared with cisplatin plus gemcitabine (median, 306.5 days) (P=0.1725, HR, 0.5516). […] Hematological toxicities, especially thrombocytopenia and neutropenia, tended to be more frequent and severe in the cisplatin plus gemcitabine group.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24649221&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;24649221&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Methotrexate and gemcitabine have exhibited single-agent activity in MPM. […] A total of 21 patients with MPM received a 30-min infusion of 100 mg/m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; methotrexate and, 30 min later, a 30-min infusion of 800 mg/m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; gemcitabine. […] Our results suggest that methotrexate and gemcitabine combination therapy is feasible and effective in the treatment of MPM.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24659659&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;24659659&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
No statistically significant difference was observed between the patients who received pemetrexed/cisplatin (N=54) and gemcitabine/cisplatin (N=28) in terms of PFS and OS (p=0.145, p=0.244, respectively). […] Survival rates in patients who received a combination of platinum analogues with pemetrexed or gemcitabine as front-line chemotherapy were similar.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24687408&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;24687408&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Low-dose, prolonged infusion of gemcitabine has effects similar to standard doses in several cancers. […] We evaluated the toxicity and efficacy of low-dose gemcitabine in prolonged infusion plus cisplatin in patients with advanced pleural mesothelioma. […] Patients with mesothelioma received gemcitabine (250 mg/m(2)) in a 6-h infusion plus cisplatin (35 mg/m(2)) on days 1 and 8 every three weeks. […] Low-dose, prolonged gemcitabine infusion plus cisplatin has acceptable toxicity and high efficacy with improved quality of life, representing an affordable regimen for the low-income population.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24690410&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;24690410&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
No drugs have been shown to improve survival as second-line therapy, yet vinorelbine and gemcitabine are prescribed based on the results of small phase II trials. […] To augment the existing limited data, we examined our institutional experience with vinorelbine and gemcitabine in patients with previously treated MPM. […] We reviewed charts of patients with MPM treated with vinorelbine and/or gemcitabine as second- or third-line therapy between 2003 and 2010. […] Sixty patients were identified: 33 treated with vinorelbine, 15 gemcitabine, and 12 both agents. […] Of 56 patients evaluable radiologically, there was 1 partial response (gemcitabine) giving a response rate of 2% (95% CI: 0-10%). […] Median progression free survival was 1.7 months for vinorelbine and 1.6 months for gemcitabine. […] Response to second- or third-line vinorelbine or gemcitabine is rare.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24842043&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;24842043&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
OS of our patients was better than that found in the literature, seeming to be positively affected by early stages, better ECOG PS, age below 65 years, left side involvement, and having second-line chemotherapy with cisplatin-gemcitabine or 3M.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24958517&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;24958517&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In the present study, we aimed to evaluate the effectiveness of second-line gemcitabine-based chemotherapy regimens on overall survival (OS) in malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM) patients receiving first-line pemetrexed-based regimens. […] A total of 73 patients with MPM from Akdeniz University, Acibadem Kayseri Hospital, Kayseri Training and Research Hospital, and Erciyes University were analyzed and evaluated retrospectively as two groups: second-line gemcitabine-based chemotherapy and no second-line chemotherapy. […] The median OS of patients who received second-line gemcitabine-based chemotherapy was 11.3 (5.1-17.5) months, while it was 9.9 (2.1-17.7) months in the patients who did not receive chemotherapy in the second-line setting (p = 0.056). […] When we evaluated the survival rate at the 6th, 12th, 18th, 24th, and 36th month, the OS rate of the 36th month was significantly higher in patients who received gemcitabine-based second-line chemotherapy (p = 0.041). […] When evaluating the OS from diagnosis to death, the median OS values were 20.8 (17.5-24.1) months for first-line pemetrexed-based regimens then second-line gemcitabine alone and 13.1 (9.0-17.1) months supportive care after first-line pemetrexed-based regimens (p = 0.005). […] According to our results, we may consider gemcitabine-based regimens as second-line chemotherapy after treatment with pemetrexed plus platinum in patients with MPM.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25572813&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;25572813&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
However, combination of carboplatin, liposomised doxorubicin (Caelyx) and gemcitabine (CCG regimen) has revealed noteworthy activity when used as first-line treatment. […] Carboplatin (AUC 5), Caelyx (30 mg/m(2)) and Gemcitabine (1,000 mg/m(2)) day 1, together with Gemcitabine (800 mg/m(2)) day 8, were given in up to six cycles.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25653696&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;25653696&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Afterwards, he received a single PDT treatment and then later took chemotherapy using gemcitabine/cisplatin.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25670260&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;25670260&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Upon restaging, the patient’s tumor was again determined to be unresectable; therefore, palliative chemotherapy treatments were initiated, which included gemcitabine and erlotinib. […] After two gemcitabine cycles, he was admitted to the hospital because of loss of motor function due to spinal cord hemisection.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25840756&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;25840756&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Tumor tissue of a malignant pleural mesothelioma cohort (n = 107) treated with platinum/gemcitabine (n = 46) or platinum/pemetrexed (n = 61) induction chemotherapy followed by extrapleural pneumonectomy was assembled on a tissue microarray. […] When specifically analyzed in the subgroup of patients receiving platinum/gemcitabine followed by extrapleural pneumonectomy, high nuclear ribonucleotide reductase M1 was associated with prolonged freedom from recurrence (P = .03) and overall survival (P = .02).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26108172&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;26108172&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Fever on posttreatment days 3 and 4 was most commonly observed in patients treated with gemcitabine (20 %) or docetaxel (18 %).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26156324&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;26156324&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We aimed to evaluate the efficiency and safety of cis/carboplatin plus gemcitabine, which was previously used for mesothelioma but with no recorded proof of its efficiency, compared with cis/carboplatin plus pemetrexed, which is known to be effective in mesothelioma, in comparable historical groups of malignant pleural mesothelioma. […] One hundred and sixteen patients received cis/carboplatin plus pemetrexed (group 1), while 30 patients received cis/carboplatin plus gemcitabine (group 2) between June 1999 and June 2012. […] The study indicates that platinum-based gemcitabine is effective and a safe schema in malignant pleural mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26317916&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;26317916&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Induction chemotherapy consisted of cisplatin/gemcitabine (cis/gem) or cisplatin/pemetrexed (cis/pem), followed by extrapleural pneumonectomy (EPP).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26366804&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;26366804&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In the absence of a clinical trial, gemcitabine and/or vinorelbine-based regimens could be considered.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26421614&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;26421614&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
CT included platinum/gemcitabine (Pla/Gem) or platinum/pemetrexed (Pla/Pem).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26715491&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;26715491&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Chemotherapy regimens included Cisplatin/Pemetrexed, Carboplatin/Pemetrexed and Cisplatin/Gemcitabine, followed by EPP. 62 patients completed the adjuvant radiotherapy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26839699&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;26839699&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
One cycle of carboplatin plus pemetrexed and two cycles of gemcitabine were administered but failed to inhibit tumor progression.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26968202&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;26968202&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Forty subjects were treated: 18 received first-line pemetrexed-based chemotherapy, 22 received second-line chemotherapy with pemetrexed (n = 7) or gemcitabine (n = 15).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27594045&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;27594045&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
This study was designed to evaluate the growth inhibitory effect of OTX015 on patient-derived MPM473, MPM487 and MPM60 mesothelioma cell lines and its antitumor activity in three patient-derived xenograft models, MPM473, MPM487 and MPM484, comparing it with cisplatin, gemcitabine and pemetrexed, three agents which are currently used to treat MPM in the clinic. […] It was the most effective drug in MPM473 xenografts and showed a similar level of activity as the most efficient treatment in the other two MPM models (gemcitabine in MPM487 and cisplatin in MPM484).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27599565&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;27599565&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Three patients were treated with chemotherapy (two with cisplatin/pemetrexed and one with cisplatin/gemcitabine) and one patient underwent surgery.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27822122&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;27822122&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Among those prescribed Ca/Ci + Pe as first-line therapy, retreatment with Ca/Ci + Pe (28%) or treatment with gemcitabine (30%) were the most common second-line therapies.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27853379&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;27853379&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The median age of patients was 55 years and 45.6% of them received platinum in combination with pemetrexed, while 54.4% received platinum in combination with gemcitabine.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27906635&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;27906635&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM) is a very hypoxic malignancy, and hypoxia has been associated with resistance towards gemcitabine. […] Therefore we investigated the combination of a new LDH-A inhibitor (NHI-1) with gemcitabine in MPM cell lines. […] Under hypoxia (O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tension of 1%) the cell growth inhibitory effects of gemcitabine, were reduced, as demonstrated by a 5- to 10-fold increase in IC&lt;sub&gt;50&lt;/sub&gt;s. […] Flow cytometry demonstrated that hypoxia caused a G1 arrest, whereas the combination of NHI-1 significantly increased gemcitabine-induced cell death. […] In conclusion, our data show that hypoxia increased MPM resistance to gemcitabine. […] However, cell death induction and modulation of the key transporter in gemcitabine uptake may contribute to the synergistic interaction of gemcitabine with the LDH-A inhibitor NHI-1 and support further studies for the rational development of this combination.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29116477&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;29116477&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
4EGI-1 showed enhanced cytotoxicity in combination with pemetrexed or gemcitabine.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29753120&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;29753120&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The primary objective of this single-institution phase I clinical trial was to establish the maximum tolerated dose of gemcitabine added to cisplatin and delivered as heated intraoperative chemotherapy after resection of malignant pleural mesothelioma. […] Previously established intracavitary dosing of cisplatin (range 175-225 mg/m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;) with systemic cytoprotection was used in combination with escalating doses of gemcitabine, following a 3-plus-3 design from 100 mg/m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; in 100-mg increments. […] Dose-limiting toxicity (grade 3 leukopenia) was observed in two patients who were receiving 1100 mg/m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; of gemcitabine, thus establishing the maximum tolerated dose at 1000 mg/m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;, in combination with 175 mg/m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; of cisplatin. […] Combination cisplatin and gemcitabine heated intraoperative chemotherapy can be administered safely and feasibly in the context of complete surgical resection of malignant pleural mesothelioma by EPP or P/D.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29753703&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;29753703&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Best investigator choice was decided before random assignment and could be single-agent gemcitabine (1000-1250 mg/m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; intravenously), vinorelbine (25 mg/m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; intravenously or 60 mg/m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; orally), doxorubicin (60-75 mg/m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; intravenously), or best supportive care only.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30157247&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30157247&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Cisplatin, pemetrexed, gemcitabine, vinorelbine, and BAMLET, did not demonstrate a therapeutic window for mesothelioma compared with immortalised non-cancer mesothelial cells.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30407323&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30407323&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Apatinib as a third-line treatment after failure from pemetrexed/cisplatin (PC) as the first-line chemotherapy and gemcitabine/cisplatin (GP) as the second-line chemotherapy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30809599&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30809599&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Platinum(II) complexes such as cisplatin and carboplatin are clinically approved for the therapy of mesothelioma often in combination with antimetabolites such as pemetrexed or gemcitabine.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30809600&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30809600&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Gemcitabine and pemetrexed are clinically approved antimetabolites for the therapy of mesothelioma diseases. […] An overview of the interplay between gemcitabine/pemetrexed antimetabolites and non-coding RNAs in mesothelioma is provided. […] Further to this, various non-coding RNA-modulating agents are discussed which displayed positive effects on gemcitabine or pemetrexed treatment of mesothelioma diseases.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31619462&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;31619462&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Gemcitabine and hydroxyurea were more cytotoxic in &lt;i&gt;BAP1&lt;/i&gt;-proficient cell line-derived spheroids compared with &lt;i&gt;BAP1&lt;/i&gt; deficient. […] Upregulation of RRM2 upon gemcitabine and hydroxyurea treatment was more profound in &lt;i&gt;BAP1&lt;/i&gt; mut/del cell lines.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31832406&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;31832406&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Cancer cells isolated secondarily in an &lt;i&gt;in vitro&lt;/i&gt; proliferation assay using CD-DST exhibited low sensitivity to pemetrexed and high sensitivity to gemcitabine. […] Treatment with gemcitabine maintained stable disease for 4 mo.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32088605&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;32088605&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The patient underwent pleural decortication but rapidly progressed and thus started chemotherapy with carboplatin and gemcitabine.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32102735&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;32102735&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In pre-clinical models, the combination of gemcitabine (GEM) and imatinib mesylate (IM), compared with GEM alone, led to a further tumor growth inhibition and improved survival.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32154179&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;32154179&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
However, single agent pembrolizumab was not superior to chemotherapy (gemcitabine or vinorelbine) in the recent published PROMISE-Meso trial in pre-treated patients.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32493992&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;32493992&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Novel LDH-A inhibitors enhanced spheroid disintegration and displayed synergistic effects with pemetrexed in MPM and gemcitabine in DMPM cells. […] Studies with bioluminescent hypoxic orthotopic and subcutaneous DMPM athymic-mice models revealed the marked antitumour activity of the LDH-A inhibitor NHI-Glc-2, alone or combined with gemcitabine.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
