<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mesothelioma</title>
    <link>/mesothelioma/genepanel/7054/</link>
      <atom:link href="/mesothelioma/genepanel/7054/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>mesothelioma</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>BioHub - UFPE</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/mesothelioma/images/icon_hu3365e08ad5ef6cb6d886bc511b9ad2b3_313689_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>mesothelioma</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/genepanel/7054/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>TH</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/genepanel/7054/info/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/mesothelioma/genepanel/7054/info/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tyrosine hydroxylase&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;font-size:16px&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ENTREZID: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/7054&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;7054&lt;/a&gt; | Type: Protein Coding |
Map: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/genome/gdv/browser/gene/?id=7054&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; 11p15.5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
OMIM: &lt;a href=&#39;https://omim.org/entry/605407&#39; target=&#39;_blank&#39;&gt;605407&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#39;https://omim.org/entry/191290&#39; target=&#39;_blank&#39;&gt;191290&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;justify&#34; style=&#34;font-size:16px&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Summary Entrez&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;The protein encoded by this gene is involved in the conversion of tyrosine to dopamine. It is the rate-limiting enzyme in the synthesis of catecholamines, hence plays a key role in the physiology of adrenergic neurons. Mutations in this gene have been associated with autosomal recessive Segawa syndrome. Alternatively spliced transcript variants encoding different isoforms have been noted for this gene. [provided by RefSeq, Jul 2008] &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TH</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/genepanel/7054/gene_expression/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/mesothelioma/genepanel/7054/gene_expression/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/mesothelioma/mesotheliomarmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tyrosine hydroxylase&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;gene-expression&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Gene Expression&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;font-size:12px&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Table 1.&lt;/strong&gt; TH expression overview from &lt;em&gt;human protein atlas database&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;table table-striped&#34; style=&#34;width: auto !important; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
ENSEMBL
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
Tissue
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
Protein
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
mRNA
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
ENSG00000180176
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
soft tissue
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Low
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
NA
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
ENSG00000180176
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
adrenal gland
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Not detected
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
259.8
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
ENSG00000180176
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
adrenal gland
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
High
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
259.8
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
ENSG00000180176
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
adipose tissue
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
NA
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
3.2
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TH</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/genepanel/7054/gene_context/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/mesothelioma/genepanel/7054/gene_context/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/mesothelioma/mesotheliomarmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tyrosine hydroxylase&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;gene-context-sentence&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Gene Context Sentence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;font-size:12px&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Table 2.&lt;/strong&gt; Analysis of context sentence of TH gene in 8 abstracts.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;table table-striped&#34; style=&#34;width: auto !important; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
PMID
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
Gene Context Sentence
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;/mesothelioma/publication/17289801&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;17289801&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Soluble mesothelin-related peptides (SMRP)have been reported to be potential biomarkers for malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM). […] The MESOMARK assay is a 2-step immunoenzymatic assay in an ELISA format with a 6-point calibration curve (0-32 nmol/L). […] We measured SMRP by this assay in 409 apparently healthy individuals (reference interval study), 177 patients with nonmalignant conditions, and 500 cancer patients, including 88 with MPM. […] The limit of detection was 0.16 nmol/L. […] The mean dilution recovery for 5 samples was 109% (range, 99%-113%). […] No interference was seen from added bilirubin (200 mg/L), hemoglobin (500 mg/L), triglycerides (30 g/L), chemotherapeutic agents, or other tested substances. […] Recombinant mesothelin was stable in serum upon freeze/thaw at -70 degrees C and upon storage for at least 7 days at 2-8 degrees C. […] The 99(th) percentile of the reference group was 1.5 nmol/L [95% confidence interval (CI), 1.2-1.6 nmol/L; n = 409], and mean SMRP was significantly higher in sera from patients with MPM (7.5 nmol/L; 95% CI, 2.8-12.1 nmol/L; n = 88). […] Concentrations in other nonmalignant and malignant conditions were similar to those in healthy controls. […] The MESOMARK assay is analytically robust and may be useful for the detection and management of mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;/mesothelioma/publication/18443531&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18443531&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Mesothelioma is characterized by aggressive follow-up, difficult diagnosis and treatment fatal issue. […] In one side the restricted possibility for operative treatment and the other side the resistance of tumors for chemotherapy are the mean reasons for bad results in patients with malignant pleural mesothelioma. […] We have aim to make a retrospective study of patients with malignant pleural mesothelioma in 3-th and 4-th stage, undergoing operation in our clinic and see VATS effectiveness. […] In the clinic of thoracic surgery in University Hospital “St.George” - Plovdiv we made retrospective study in 21 patients undergoing operation in the occasion of advanced pleural mesothelioma. […] It was thoroughly men (14) in age between 45-72 years (58.6). […] In 18 (85%) patients the disease was proven intraoperative or on the final histological result after operation. […] Before operation in this patients in help of diagnosis, we have information by image examination (radiography, CT of thorax and if it necessary to mark pleural effusion - sonography of pleural cavity ) abdominal sonohography or CT of abdomen for exclusion of distant metastasis, fibrobronchoscopy (FBS) for confirmation or exclusion of endobronchial cancer and transthoracic aspiration biopsy (TTAB). […] We describe improvement in the most of patients. […] In this situation we made Bulao drainage. […] Death issue in early postoperative period we have in 1 patient with increased breath insufficiency despite evacuation of pleural effusion and unfolded lung. […] Early diagnosis of malignant pleural mesothelioma is difficult, in some times impossible. […] After histological verification the diagnosis is proven. […] The difficulty comes by insufficient cytologic and histologic verification before operation and also insufficiency of image examination. […] Because of the chemotherapy is insufficient, surgical treatment (radical or not) in huge number of cases help improvement of patient’s condition. […] Surgical treatment is decisive for diagnosis and treatment of malignant pleural mesothelioma even in advanced cases and have evident positive effects. […] Surgical methods improve patient’s condition, even in inoperable cases. […] VATS surgery is modern method for diagnosis and treatment and if it necessary we can continue by conventional operation for definitive treatment of mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;/mesothelioma/publication/27942413&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;27942413&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Patients with non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) associated with carcinomatous pleuritis are currently classified as having stage IV disease per the 7&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; edition of the tumor-node-metastasis (TNM) system, which means that the disease is deemed incurable. […] In fact, the 5-year survival rate of these patients was only 2% in a large global cohort collected by the International Association for the Study of Lung Cancer. […] However, patients with carcinomatous pleuritis have heterogeneous conditions. […] Some have minimal pleural effusion, which is first detected at thoracotomy; some have numerous pleural nodules without any effusion; and others have massive effusion and nodules with symptoms. […] Several investigators have reported the contribution of surgical intervention to favorable outcomes of patients with carcinomatous pleuritis first detected at thoracotomy. […] These reports show a relatively higher 5-year survival rate of 15% to 37%. […] The extrapleural pneumonectomy (EPP) is a radical surgical procedure that is commonly employed in the treatment of malignant pleural mesothelioma. […] Two authors reported that they have successfully performed EPPs for the treatment of patients with carcinomatous pleuritis. […] Their 5-year survival rates were estimated to be 22% and 61%, a significantly improved outcome. […] Although the development of chemotherapeutic agents, including molecular targeted drugs, might have the potential to prolong the survival of patients with advanced lung cancer, surgical interventions including EPP might have a role in improving the survival of patients with carcinomatous pleuritis of minimal disease and those without massive effusion or numerous pleural nodules.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;/mesothelioma/publication/28498408&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;28498408&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We have previously reported that chronic, recurrent and low-dose exposure to asbestos fibers causes a reduction in antitumor immunity. […] Investigation of natural killer (NK) cells using an in vitro cell line model and comprising in vitro activation using freshly isolated NK cells co-cultured with chrysotile fibers, as well as NK cells derived from asbestos-exposed patients with pleural plaque (PP) or malignant mesothelioma (MM), revealed decreased expression of NK cell activating receptors such as NKG2D, 2B4 and NKp46. […] An in vitro differentiation and clonal expansion model for CD8+ cytotoxic T lymphocytes (CTLs) showed reduced cytotoxicity with decreased levels of cytotoxic molecules such as granzyme B and perforin, as well as suppressed proliferation of CTLs. […] Additionally, analysis of T helper cells showed that surface CXCR3, chemokine receptor, and the productive potential of interferon (IFN)γ were reduced following asbestos exposure in an in vitro cell line model and in peripheral CD4+ cells of asbestos-exposed patients. […] Moreover, experiments revealed that asbestos exposure enhanced regulatory T cell (Treg) function. […] This study also focused on CXCR3 expression and the Th-17 cell fraction. […] Following activation with T-cell receptor and co-culture with various concentrations of chrysotile fibers using freshly isolated CD4+ surface CXCR3 positive and negative fractions, the intracellular expression of CXCR3, IFNγ and IL-17 remained unchanged when co-cultured with chrysotile. […] However, subsequent re-stimulation with phorbol 12-myristate 13-acetate (PMA) and ionomycin resulted in enhanced IL-17 production and expression, particularly in CD4+ surface CXCR3 positive cells. […] These results indicated that the balance and polarization between Treg and Th-17 fractions play an important role with respect to the immunological effects of asbestos and the associated reduction in antitumor immunity.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;/mesothelioma/publication/30642542&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30642542&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Here we summarize the most recent update of mesothelioma research in basic science presented at the 14&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; iMig2018 international conference. […] The symposium of basic science track mainly focused on the drivers of mesothelioma initiation and progression, molecular pathogenesis, and perspectives on potential therapeutic approaches. […] This review covers several promising fields including strategies efficiently inhibiting YAP/TAZ functions or their critical downstream targets, heparanase inhibitors, RAN depletion, and MIF/CD74 inhibitors that may be developed as novel therapeutic approaches. […] In addition, targeting mesothelioma stem cells by depleting M2-polarized macrophages in tumor microenvironment or blocking Tnfsf18 (GITRL)-GITR signalling might be translated into therapeutic modalities in mesothelioma treatment.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;/mesothelioma/publication/31084758&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;31084758&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
To examine the performance of &lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;F-FDG PET/MRI in the loco-regional staging of malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM). […] Consecutive subjects with MPM undergoing pre-operative staging with &lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;F-FDG PET/CT who underwent a same day integrated &lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;F-FDG PET/MRI were prospectively studied. […] Clinical TNM staging (AJCC 7&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; edition) was performed separately and in consensus by two readers on the &lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;F-FDG PET/MRI studies, and compared with staging by &lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;F-FDG PET/CT, and with final pathological stage, determined by a combination of intra-operative and histological findings. 10 subjects (9 male, mean age 68 years) with biopsy-proven MPM (9 epithelioid tumours, 1 biphasic) were included. […] One subject underwent neo-adjuvant chemotherapy between imaging and surgery and was excluded from the clinical versus pathological stage analysis. […] Pathological staging was concordant with staging by &lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;F-FDG PET/MRI in 67% (n = 6) of subjects, and with &lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;F-FDG PET/CT staging in 33% (n = 3). […] Pathological T stage was concordant with &lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;F-FDG PET/MRI in 78% (n = 7), and with &lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;F-FDG PET/CT in 33% (n = 3) of subjects. […] Pathological N stage was concordant with both &lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;F-FDG PET/MRI and &lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;F-FDG PET/CT in 78% (n = 7) of cases. […] There was good inter-observer agreement for overall PET/MRI staging (weighted kappa 0.63) with moderate inter-reader agreement for T staging (weighted kappa 0.59). […] All 6 subjects with prior talc pleurodesis demonstrated mismatch between elevated FDG uptake and restricted diffusion in areas of visible talc deposition. […] Clinical MPM staging by &lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;F-FDG PET/MRI is feasible, and potentially provides more accurate loco-regional staging than PET/CT, particularly in T staging.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;/mesothelioma/publication/32082839&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;32082839&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In this article, we present a 59-year-old male patient who was admitted to our hospital with right pleural effusion and right-sided chest pain and diagnosed as malignant pleural mesothelioma with thoracentesis and pleural biopsy. […] After the patient was determined to be operable, right parietal pleurectomy + pericardial resection + diaphragmatic resection were performed and four cycles of cisplatin and pemetrexed combination as adjuvant treatment were added. […] The patient was followed-up without any problem for three and a half years. […] At this time, left-sided chest pain and leftsided effusion were noticed. […] Tumor was negative in thoracentesis and pleural biopsy. […] Then, video-assisted thoracoscopic surgery was applied, which resulted in Stage 1a malignant pleural mesothelioma. […] Thoracoscopic parietal pleurectomy was performed with success. […] Four cycles of pemetrexed single-agent therapy was performed as an adjuvant treatment. […] The patient died of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease and heart failure in 57&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; month of the first and 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; month of the second operation while he was tumor free. […] To the best of our knowledge, this case is the first operated bilateral metachronous primary malignant pleural mesothelioma in the literature.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;/mesothelioma/publication/7226012&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;7226012&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Tissue cultures from a series of spindle cell soft tissue sarcomas allowed th identification of five cases in which the neoplastic cells grew as polygonal elements, forming plaques in the same way as epithelial tumors. […] The similarity of this behavior in vitro to that of normal pleura and synovium, and to monophasic malignant pleural mesothelioma, allowed these tumors to be classified as monophasic synovial sarcomas. […] None of the five tumors showed specific light-optical features, being composed of fusiform cells with a tendency to form slits in two cases. […] No true epithelial differentiation was found. […] The topographic distribution and the response to therapy of the neoplasms were also similar to that found in the usual biphasic tumors.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TH</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/genepanel/7054/clinvar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/mesothelioma/genepanel/7054/clinvar/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tyrosine hydroxylase&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;clinvar-summary&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;ClinVar Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;font-size:16px&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
Under development
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TH</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/genepanel/7054/geo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/mesothelioma/genepanel/7054/geo/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tyrosine hydroxylase&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;geo-dataset-summary&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;GEO dataset Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;font-size:16px&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
Under development
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
