<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mesothelioma</title>
    <link>/mesothelioma/drugpanel/cyclophosphamide/</link>
      <atom:link href="/mesothelioma/drugpanel/cyclophosphamide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>mesothelioma</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>BioHub - UFPE</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/mesothelioma/images/icon_hu7e12209333f22d741aca7d462871821f_9877_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>mesothelioma</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/drugpanel/cyclophosphamide/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>CYCLOPHOSPHAMIDE</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/drugpanel/cyclophosphamide/info/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/mesothelioma/drugpanel/cyclophosphamide/info/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/mesothelioma/mesotheliomarmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;font-size:16px&#34;&gt;
DrugBank ID: &lt;a href=&#39;https://www.drugbank.ca/drugs/db00531&#39; target=&#39;_blank&#39;&gt;db00531&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
DrugCentral: &lt;a href=&#34;http://drugcentral.org/?q=cyclophosphamide&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;cyclophosphamide&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
Synonymous :(+-)-cyclophosphamide | (rs)-cyclophosphamide | 2-[bis(2-chloroethylamino)]-tetrahydro-2h-1,3,2-oxazaphosphorine-2-oxide | anhydrous cyclophosphamide | bis(2-chloroethyl)phosphoramide cyclic propanolamide ester | ciclofosfamida | ciclofosfamide | cyclophosphamid | cyclophosphamide | cyclophosphamide anhydrous | cyclophosphamidum | cytophosphane | n,n-bis(2-chloroethyl)tetrahydro-2h-1,3,2-oxazaphosphorin-2-amine 2-oxide
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;drug-sentece-context&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Drug Sentece Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;font-size:12px&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Table 1.&lt;/strong&gt; Analysis of context sentence of &lt;em&gt;cyclophosphamide&lt;/em&gt; gene in 29 abstracts.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;table table-striped&#34; style=&#34;width: auto !important; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
pmid
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
sentence
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12405438&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;12405438&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
After decortication, chemotherapy with ICE (ifosfamide, carboplatin, etoposide) - VAC (vincristine, adriamycin, cyclophosphamide) combination was started.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12447185&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;12447185&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
When given, chemotherapy consisted of 2 to 3 cycles of cyclophosphamide, doxorubicin (Adriamycin), and cisplatin initiated 1 to 2 months after completion of radiation.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1260651&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;1260651&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Six patients were treated with either adriamycin or a multiple drug regimen consisting of cyclophosphamide, vincristine, methotrexate, and 5-fluorouracil (COMF).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1429086&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;1429086&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The treatment programs, which can consecutively, were: I, 20 Gy (10 x 2 Gy) to the hemithorax + CYVADIC (cyclophosphamide 500 mg/m2 d 1, vincristine 1 mg/m2 d 1 and 5, adriamycin 40 mg/m2 d 1 and dacarbazine 200 mg/m2 d 1 and 5, several cycles before and after irradiation); II, 55 Gy (25 x 2.2 Gy) to the hemithorax + 15 Gy (6 x 2.5 Gy) to the tumor + CYVADIC (2 cycles before, 1 cycle during, and 2 cycles after irradiation); III, Mitoxantrone (14 mg/m2 q 28 d, &amp;lt; or = 6 cycles) followed by 70 Gy (56 x 1.25 Gy, twice a day); IV, 4-Epirubicin (110-130 mg/m2 q 28 d, &amp;lt; or = 6 cycles) followed by 35 Gy (28 x 1.25 Gy twice a day) to the hemithorax + 36 Gy (9 x 4 Gy every 2 days) to the tumor; V, Etoposide (150 mg/m2 1, 3, 5 q 28 d) followed by 38.5 Gy (11 x 3.5 Gy) to the hemithorax.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16101199&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16101199&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Combination chemotherapy included cisplatin-gemcitabine, cisplatin (or carboplatin) with premetrexed and doxorubicin-cyclophosphamide.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16130821&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16130821&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
This study investigated the benefit of single therapy with cyclophosphamide or hyperthermia or the combination of both on cells of a human pleural mesothelioma cell line, xenotransplanted subcutaneously in the paw of mice. […] The greatest benefit was achieved using combined thermochemotherapy consisting of cyclophosphamide plus hyperthermia: 50% of this group had partial remissions, and 67% responded to this therapy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1898706&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;1898706&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The authors report a patient with inoperable MPM who achieved complete remission with combination chemotherapy of cyclophosphamide, doxorubicin, and cisplatin. 5-fluorouracil and mitomycin C (FM) induced another remission after recurrence of the tumor.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1917165&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;1917165&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Nutrient starvation in aging medium, exposure to activated cyclophosphamide (even at high concentrations) or cisplatin caused only negligible MDR induction. […] After exposure to vindesine for 6 weeks, tumor colonies exhibited highly enhanced resistance to Vinca alkaloids, doxorubicin, etoposide and dacarbacine, whereas their sensitivity to mitomycin, activated cyclophosphamide or cisplatin remained unchanged.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20534685&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;20534685&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The chemotherapeutic agent added to platinum was gemcitabine in one patient, cyclophosphamide-doxorubicin in three patients and pemetrexed in 10 patients.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2072707&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2072707&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Postoperatively 26 patients received cyclophosphamide, doxorubicin, and cis-platinum chemotherapy with or without radiotherapy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21642867&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;21642867&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Tumor growth delay was achieved by cisplatin followed by PC61 or cyclophosphamide. […] Nevertheless, cell killing induced by cyclophosphamide combined with cisplatin was due to cytotoxicity rather than specific immune response.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25374217&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;25374217&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The aim of this study was to evaluate the efficacy of oral cyclophosphamide and etoposide for patients who underwent standard treatment for advanced MM. […] This study included 22 malignant pleural mesothelioma patients who were treated with oral cyclophosphamide and etoposide (EE).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26652184&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;26652184&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In our murine model, we found that reduction of regulatory T cells with metronomic cyclophosphamide increased the efficacy of immunotherapy. […] To assess the decrease in number of peripheral blood regulatory T cells during combination therapy of low-dose cyclophosphamide and dendritic cell immunotherapy and determine the induction of immunologic responses with this treatment in patients with mesothelioma. […] Ten patients with malignant pleural mesothelioma received metronomic cyclophosphamide and dendritic cell-based immunotherapy. […] Administration of dendritic cells pulsed with autologous tumor lysate combined with cyclophosphamide in patients with mesothelioma was safe, the only side effect being moderate fever. […] Dendritic cell vaccination combined with cyclophosphamide resulted in radiographic disease control in 8 of the 10 patients. […] Low-dose cyclophosphamide reduced the percentage of regulatory T cells of total CD4 cells in peripheral blood from 9.43 (range, 4.34-26.10) to 4.51 (range, 0.27-10.30) after 7 days of cyclophosphamide treatment (P = 0.02).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30524884&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30524884&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Recently, the combination of autologous tumor lysate-pulsed dendritic cells (DC) and metronomic cyclophosphamide (mCTX) was reported as a feasible and well-tolerated treatment in malignant pleural mesothelioma patients and further as a method to reduce circulating Tregs. &lt;b&gt;Objectives&lt;/b&gt;: The aim of this study was to establish the immunological effects of mCTX alone and in combination with DC-based immunotherapy on circulating Treg and other T cell subsets in mesothelioma patients. &lt;b&gt;Methods&lt;/b&gt;: Ten patients received mCTX and DC-based immunotherapy after chemotherapy (n = 5) or chemotherapy and debulking surgery (n = 5).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31420241&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;31420241&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Patients received 1-3 × 10&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt; or 1-3 × 10&lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt; CART-meso cells/m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; with or without 1.5 g/m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; cyclophosphamide. […] Lentiviral-transduced CART-meso cells were well tolerated; one dose-limiting toxicity (grade 4, sepsis) occurred at 1-3 × 10&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;/m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; CART-meso without cyclophosphamide. […] Cyclophosphamide pre-treatment enhanced CART-meso expansion but did not improve persistence beyond 28 days.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/3166920&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;3166920&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Thirteen patients with malignant mesothelioma of the pleura have been treated with 24-hour cyclophosphamide infusion (2.5 g/m2) therapy. […] High dose cyclophosphamide offers no advantage over standard dose therapy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/3317170&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;3317170&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
CYVADIC (cyclophosphamide + vincristine + adriamycin + dacarbazine = DTIC) is frequently used in the treatment of patients with soft tissue sarcomas or malignant mesotheliomas.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/3543239&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;3543239&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The purpose of the study was to evaluate cyclophosphamide (500 mg/m2 day 1), imidazole carboxamide (250 mg/m2 days 1 through 5), and doxorubicin (Adriamycin; Adria Laboratories, Columbus, OH) (50 mg/m2 day 1) v cyclophosphamide (500 mg/m2) and doxorubicin (50 mg/m2) in a randomized prospective clinical trial involving 76 fully evaluable patients with advanced stages II to IV malignant mesothelioma. […] We conclude, based on the minimal benefit observed, that the combination of cyclophosphamide and doxorubicin with or without imidazole carboxamide does not warrant further investigation in patients with advanced-stage malignant mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/3619593&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;3619593&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The average survival of our own cases, controlled by autopsy, was 16.4 months (n = 36) for symptomatically treated patients and 16.1 months (n = 26) for those treated with Cyclophosphamide and other cytotoxic drugs.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/3753125&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;3753125&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The proteinuria did not respond to treatment with prednisone and cyclophosphamide.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/3907825&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;3907825&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The effect of doxorubicin and cyclophosphamide in the treatment of diffuse, malignant pleural mesothelioma was evaluated in a randomized study. […] The treatment consisted of doxorubicin at a dose of 60 mg/m2 every 3 weeks, to a total dose of 550 mg/m2, or cyclophosphamide at a dose of 1500 mg/m2 every 3 weeks for 1 year. […] During treatment with doxorubicin, none of the patients developed cardiotoxicity, while one patient developed hemorrhagic cystitis during treatment with cyclophosphamide. […] Thus, the trial showed no antineoplastic activity of either doxorubicin or cyclophosphamide in the treatment of malignant pleural mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/6426072&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;6426072&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Chemotherapy with doxorubicin, vincristine, and cyclophosphamide (12 patients, with preceding surgery in eight) was without objective benefit.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/6790917&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;6790917&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
One patient had a complete response to a combination of Adriamycin, cyclophosphamide, and vincristine and has remained free of disease for 5 1/2 years.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8462329&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;8462329&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
This technique used in a multimodality approach with CAP chemotherapy (cyclophosphamide 600 mg/m2, doxorubicin 60 mg/m2, cisplatin 75 mg/m2) 5 cycles at 3-week intervals, and radiotherapy (55 Gy radiation to sites of previous bulky disease or residual disease) to treat 44 patients with malignant pleural mesothelioma resulted in improved operative mortality and decreased length of hospital stay.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8501504&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;8501504&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Patients with no medical contraindication and potentially resectable mesothelioma on computed tomography (CT) (magnetic resonance imaging [MRI] when it became available) received extrapleural pneumonectomy, cyclophosphamide, doxorubicin, and cisplatin (CAP) chemotherapy, and radiotherapy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8622005&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;8622005&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Agents that produce response rates in 10% to 20% of patients include doxorubicin, epirubicin, mitomycin, cyclophosphamide, ifosfamide, cisplatin, and carboplatin.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8635025&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;8635025&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
This study was designed to determine the efficacy and side effects of a combination of cyclophosphamide (C), doxorubicin (D), and cisplatin (P) in patients with inoperable, unresectable, or metastatic malignant pleural mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9033296&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;9033296&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Thirty-five of the surviving patients received adjuvant chemotherapy (32/35 received cyclophosphamide, doxorubicin, and cisplatin) followed by hemithorax radiation therapy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9427783&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;9427783&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Chemotherapy for Group A was CDDP 100 mg/m2 Dl with Viblastine 6 mg/m2 Dl, 8 (24 pts) for Group B ADM 40 mg/m2 D I with Vincristine (VCR) 2 mg Dl and DTIC 200 mg/m2 Dl-3 (5 pts) or instead of DTIC Cyclophosphamide 600 mg/m2 Dl instead (pts 4).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
