<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mesothelioma</title>
    <link>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/fibroblasts/</link>
      <atom:link href="/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/fibroblasts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>mesothelioma</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>BioHub - UFPE</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/mesothelioma/images/icon_hu7e12209333f22d741aca7d462871821f_9877_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>mesothelioma</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/fibroblasts/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>fibroblasts</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/fibroblasts/info/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/fibroblasts/info/</guid>
      <description> 

&lt;script src=&#34;/mesothelioma/mesotheliomarmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;div id=&#34;cell-sentence-context&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cell Sentence Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;font-size:12px&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Table 1.&lt;/strong&gt; Analysis of context sentence of &lt;em&gt;fibroblasts&lt;/em&gt; tissue in 31 abstracts.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;table table-striped&#34; style=&#34;width: auto !important; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
PMID
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
Senteces
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10885426&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;10885426&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The authors also assessed expression of TF and TFPI messenger ribonucleic acid (mRNA) as well as TFPI activity and antigen by human pleural mesothelial cells, malignant mesothelioma cells (MS-1 cell line) and human lung fibroblasts. […] TFPI mRNA, activity and antigen were expressed by pleural mesothelial cells, MS-1 cells and lung fibroblasts.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11857086&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;11857086&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Next, we found that SV40, a DNA tumor virus present in approximately 50% of mesothelioma biopsies in the USA, induced telomerase activity in primary human mesothelial cells, but not in primary fibroblasts. […] SV40 infection of human fibroblasts did not cause detectable telomerase activity.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15006637&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15006637&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Therefore, we treated human lung fibroblasts, human lung alveolar epithelial cancer cell line A549 and monocyte-macrophage cell line J774 with fluoro-edenite or crocidolite; the latter used as a highly toxic amphibole asbestos reference. […] However, the observed functional modifications induced by fluoro-edenite are generally less dramatic than those induced by crocidolite and more evident on human lung alveolar epithelial cancer cell line A549 with respect to those obtained on human lung fibroblasts or monocyte-macrophage cell line J774.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16785767&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16785767&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
While all 18 analysed epithelioid mesotheliomas displayed a strong membranous immunostaining, 18 sarcomatoid mesotheliomas showed no, or a merely faint, cytoplasmic signal, comparable with fibroblasts in chronic pleuritis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17560792&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;17560792&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Light delivery associated with 0.04microg/ml mTHPC resulted in a significantly higher apoptosis rate in the presence of TAT-RasGAP(317-326) than without in H-meso-1 cells (p&amp;lt;0.05) but not in fibroblasts. […] In contrast, 1.0microg/ml mTHPC and light resulted in a significantly higher apoptosis rate in both H-meso-1 cells and fibroblasts as compared to controls (p&amp;lt;0.05) but the addition of TAT-RasGAP(317-326) did not lead to a further significant increase of the apoptosis rate of both H-meso-1 cells and fibroblasts as compared to mTHPC and light delivery alone. […] TAT-RasGAP(317-326) selectively enhanced the effect of mTHPC and light delivery on H-meso-1 cells but not on fibroblasts.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18757427&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18757427&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Four tandem repeats of the CRI1 promoter (CRI1(-138 4x)) caused significantly high promoter activity in malignant pleural mesothelioma cells but little promoter activity in normal mesothelial cells and normal fibroblasts.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19443527&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;19443527&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Previously, it was reported that all-trans-retinoic acid (ATRA) inhibited the production and function of IL-6 and transforming growth factor (TGF)-beta1 in experiments using lung fibroblasts. […] We investigated whether ATRA had an inhibitory effect on the cell growth of MPM, the origin of which was mesenchymal cells similar to lung fibroblasts, using a subcutaneous xenograft mouse model.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20185425&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;20185425&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Here, we investigated the association of Ang-1 with the development of MPM cells, which originate from mesenchymal cells similar to lung fibroblasts, and demonstrated that Ang-1 stimulated the growth and migration of MPM cells in vitro.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21763682&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;21763682&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We assessed the interaction between MPM cells and their microenvironments, focusing on tumor-associated fibroblasts. […] Histological analyses of clinical specimens from 51 MPM patients revealed considerable tumor-associated fibroblasts infiltration and expression of HGF, together with FGF-2 or PDGF-AA, in tumors. […] These findings indicate that MPM instigates tumor-associated fibroblasts, promoting tumor progression via a malignant cytokine network.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22286268&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;22286268&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Following intrapleural application of the sclerosing agent, diffuse inflammation, pleural coagulation-fibrinolysis imbalance (favoring the formation of fibrin adhesions), recruitment and subsequent proliferation of fibroblasts, and collagen production are findings in the pleural space.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22627953&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;22627953&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Solitary fibrous tumor of pleura (SFTP) is a rare mesenchymal neoplasm that most commonly involves the pleura, is probably derived from fibroblasts, and has no relationship to malignant mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23617783&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;23617783&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
MPM involves the malignant transformation of mesothelial cells, which originate from mesenchymal cells similar to lung fibroblasts.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23937772&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;23937772&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Fibroblast activation protein (FAP) is predominantly expressed on the surface of reactive tumor-associated fibroblasts as well as on particular cancer types. […] Additionally, FAP-specific re-directed T cells lysed FAP positive mesothelioma cells and inflammatory fibroblasts in an antigen-specific manner in vitro.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25824152&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;25824152&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Finally, miR-223 levels increased while STMN1 was reduced following the re-expression of the JNK isoforms in JNK-null murine embryonic fibroblasts, and STMN1 was reduced in MPM cell lines following the activation of JNK signaling. miR-223 regulates STMN1 in MPM, and both are in turn regulated by the JNK signaling pathway.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26839306&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;26839306&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Immunohistochemical analyses revealed that vismodegib treatment primarily downregulated GLI1 and HHIP in the stromal compartment along with a reduced expression of previously described fibroblast Hh-responsive genes such as Fibronectin (Fn1) and Vegfa Primary cells isolated from the rat model cultured in 3% O2 continued to express Dhh but did not respond to vismodegib in vitro However, culture supernatant from these cells stimulated Gli1, Ptch1, and Fn1 expression in mouse embryonic fibroblasts, which was suppressed by vismodegib.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26889976&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;26889976&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In MPM tumour samples, SPARC was present in the tumour cells and stromal fibroblasts. […] Secreted protein acidic and rich in cysteine was present in both tumour cells and stromal fibroblasts; and our in vitro and in vivo experiments suggest that stromal fibroblasts are a potential source of circulating SPARC.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27509983&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;27509983&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We recently reported that the calpain inhibitor, calpeptin exerted inhibitory effects on pulmonary fibrosis by inhibiting the proliferation of lung fibroblasts. […] In the present study, we examined the preventive effects of calpeptin on the cell growth of MPM, the origin of which is mesenchymal cells, similar to lung fibroblasts.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28289860&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;28289860&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Here, we show that PD-L1 is expressed on tumor cell samples from malignant effusions, on lung cancer cell lines, and, interestingly, on MRC-5 lung fibroblasts.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28395242&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;28395242&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Furthermore, an in vitro model of exposed fluoro-edenite fibroblasts was used to perform functional experiments to better understand the modulation of Fibulin-3 expression. […] The Fibulin-3 protein level was significantly expressed in primary human lung fibroblasts exposed to 50 and 100µg/ml of fluoro-edenite fibers for 72h, compared to the unexposed controls.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28476806&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;28476806&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The interaction between fibroblasts and malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM) cells is not well understood. […] Lung fibroblasts (HFL1, MRC5 and IMR90) and MPM cells (H28, H226 and H2052) were cultured under serum-free conditions and the resulting culture media were collected. […] Fibronectin and hepatocyte growth factor (HGF) were produced by lung fibroblasts.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30157247&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30157247&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Most of the non-cancer primary human fibroblasts were more resistant to BAMLET than were human mesothelioma cells.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30700254&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30700254&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We investigated the response of three MPM cell lines and lung fibroblasts serving as a control to treatment with pemetrexed, cisplatin and olaparib.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31929796&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;31929796&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
For this exploratory study, we screened MPM cell lines (NCI-H2452, NCI-H2052, and MSTO-211H) differing in response to cisplatin and benign control fibroblasts (MRC-5) for overall phosphorylation patterns as well as kinase activity with respect to cellular response to cisplatin-based therapeutics.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32312030&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;32312030&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Protein levels expression of HO-1 and MIF were also evaluated in human primary lung fibroblasts after exposure to FE fibers in vitro.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32705221&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;32705221&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We often encounter mesothelioma cases with a profound desmoplastic reaction, suggesting the involvement of cancer‑associated fibroblasts (CAFs) in mesothelioma progression. […] We previously showed that connective tissue growth factor (CTGF), a secreted protein, is produced by both mesothelioma cells and fibroblasts and promotes the invasion of mesothelioma cells in vitro.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/573917&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;573917&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
They were sometimes isolated, had the general aspect of fibroblasts but possessed typical microvilli.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/7102900&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;7102900&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Desmoplasia in diffuse mesotheliomas is often the result of tumor cells assuming the functional capacity of fibroblasts and has frequently been confused with reactive fibrosis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8692714&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;8692714&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The tissues of the pulmonary parenchyma and of the pleura are negative for calretinin except for the rare fibroblasts and some skeletal muscle fibres situated in the interstices of, or near the epithelial tumour mass.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8707414&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;8707414&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Cell lines established from human malignant mesotheliomas, but not from normal mesothelial cells, have been shown to possess hyaluronan receptors, and to secrete factors that stimulate hyaluronan production by fibroblasts and normal mesothelial cells.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9014859&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;9014859&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Stromal fibroblasts also showed immunoreactivity for HGF/SF in 6/8 cases of mesothelioma but in only 3/12 adenocarcinomas, 1/10 squamous cell carcinomas, and 1/4 small cell anaplastic carcinomas.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9609725&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;9609725&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Phorbol 12-myristate 13-acetate, lipopolysaccharide, transforming growth factor-beta, tumor necrosis factor-alpha, or cycloheximide induced uPAR and uPAR mRNA expression in cultured rabbit pleural mesothelial cells and lung fibroblasts and concurrently reduced the uPAR mRNA-uPAR mRNABP interaction. […] In rabbit lung fibroblasts and mesothelial cells, expression of uPAR involves posttranscriptional regulation whereby the uPAR mRNABP appears to interact with a specific coding region cis-element to decrease the stability of uPAR mRNA.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
