<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mesothelioma</title>
    <link>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/lymph_node/</link>
      <atom:link href="/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/lymph_node/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>mesothelioma</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>BioHub - UFPE</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/mesothelioma/images/icon_hu3365e08ad5ef6cb6d886bc511b9ad2b3_313689_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>mesothelioma</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/lymph_node/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>lymph node</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/lymph_node/info/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/lymph_node/info/</guid>
      <description> 

&lt;script src=&#34;/mesothelioma/mesotheliomarmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;div id=&#34;tissue-sentence-context&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tissue Sentence Context&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;font-size:12px&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Table 1.&lt;/strong&gt; Analysis of context sentence of &lt;em&gt;lymph node&lt;/em&gt; tissue in 109 abstracts.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;table table-striped&#34; style=&#34;width: auto !important; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
PMID
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
Senteces
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10373665&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;10373665&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Extrathoracic lymph node metastases in pleural mesothelioma are rare. […] A case of pleural mesothelioma diagnosed by supraclavicular lymph node biopsy is described.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10375104&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;10375104&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The TSP-1 expression levels in tumors with lymph node metastases were significantly lower than in those without lymph node metastases (P = 0.0305).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10667164&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;10667164&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In this instance, diagnosis was not made until a metastatic deposit was identified microscopically in the enlarged lymph node. […] Cytologic examination of material obtained by fine needle aspiration from his cervical lymph node revealed malignant mesothelioma. […] This was a particularly rare presentation and, as far as we are aware, was the first case in which mesothelioma was diagnosed by fine needle aspiration of a cervical lymph node. […] It serves to remind the pathologist that when confronted with a lymph node involved by tumor, the possibility of mesothelioma should be included in the differential diagnosis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11127563&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;11127563&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
First, mediastinal lymph node dissection was performed and we identified that there was no lymph node metastasis by frozen section diagnosis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11213409&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;11213409&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We evaluated the following CT findings: nodular, plaque or uniform pleural thickening; pleural calcifications; pleural thickening less or greater than 1 cm; pleural margins (regular, polycyclic, spiculated); localization (uni/bilateral hemithorax); distribution (upper, medium or lower region); pulmonary, mediastinal and diaphragmatic involvement; fissural involvement; pleural effusion; lymph node enlargement; lung mass with the comet-tail sign; lung volume (normal, reduced, increased). […] Lymph nodes were enlarged in 66.6% of the cases. […] Malignant pleural mesothelioma is strongly associated with previous occupational exposure and presents typical CT findings only in an advanced stage (irregular and nodular pleural thickening, pleural effusion, mediastinal and pulmonary contraction for tumor encasement, parenchymal and lymph node metastases), but the differential diagnosis with pleural metastatic disease can be difficult.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11251277&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;11251277&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Ten patients were at Stage II and all received a PPPD; 16 patients were at Stage III (under-staged pre-operatively): of these, nine patients presented extrapleural lymph node metastases (N2) and all received a PPPD, seven patients presented with chest wall or mediastinal invasion (T4) with macroscopic residual tumour, and all received a de-bulking P/D.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12142203&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;12142203&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Survival was surprisingly, not affected by lymph node involvement (P=0.08) or pathological type of MPM (P=0.07).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12194801&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;12194801&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
For the management of localized disease, we suggest the following protocol: initial staging of suspected cases with computed tomographic scan of the abdomen and pelvis; radical inguinal orchiectomy or hemiscrotectomy; retroperitoneal lymph node dissection in cases with positive nodes on scan or biopsy; and inguinal node dissection in cases requiring hemiscrotectomy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12365220&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;12365220&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Radiologic studies revealed a pleural effusion and paraaortic lymph node swelling.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12482127&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;12482127&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Pleural and axillary lymph node biopsies were consistent with mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12579319&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;12579319&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
78.3 and 69.6%) in NSCLC mediastinal lymph node staging. […] TF SPECT appears a highly accurate diagnostic method in the detection of intrathoracic malignant lesions, in lungs and pleura, as well as in NSCLC mediastinal lymph node staging and in monitoring treatment effectiveness, playing a complementary role to CT in selected cases.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12822605&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;12822605&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
For this approach it is imperative to select patients without mediastinal lymph node involvement. […] In this study cervical mediastinoscopy (CM) is compared with computer tomography (CT) scanning for its diagnostic accuracy in assessing mediastinal lymph nodes during preoperative workup. […] At CM the lymph node samples were taken from stations Naruke 2, 3, 4, and 7. […] Computer tomography scanning revealed pathologic enlarged lymph nodes with a shortest diameter of at least 10 mm in 17 of 43 patients (39%). […] There was histopathologic evidence of lymph node metastases at CM in 11 of these patients (26%). […] Our data confirm results of previous studies reporting that mediastinal lymph node involvement is a frequent event in MPM.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/14707923&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;14707923&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
False negative results for the detection of lymph node invasion occurred in three patients and were in relation with their infracentimetric size and the difficulty to distinguish on [18F]-FDG images mediastinal lymph nodes from widespread pleural and pulmonary extension of cancer.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1501211&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;1501211&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Necropsy findings included pleural thickening, and enlargement of the renal and anterior mediastinal lymph nodes. […] The microscopic features were typical of primary desmoplastic diffuse mesothelioma of the peritoneum and pleura with secondary lymph node metastasis (renal and anterior mediastinal).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15026591&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15026591&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Fluorine-18 fluorodeoxyglucose (FDG) positron emission tomography (PET) has an increasing role in detection of diseased lymph nodes that appear normal at CT alone, particularly when FDG PET images are fused with CT images. […] Therefore, at all levels of cancer imaging, it is essential to identify the relevant lymph node regions and their relations to the primary tumor.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15037261&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15037261&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Histological evidence of extra pleural lymph node metastases was correlated with survival. […] Lymph node size at intraoperative lymphadenectomy was correlated with the presence of metastatic tumour. […] Postoperatively the 17 patients with metastases to the extra pleural lymph nodes had significantly shorter survival (median 4.4 months, 95% CI 3.2-5.4) than those without (median survival 16.3 months, 95% CI 11.6-21.0) P=0.012 Kaplan-Meier analysis. […] Seventy-seven extra pleural lymph nodes without metastases were measured with a mean long axis diameter of 16.9 mm (range 4-55); 22 positive nodes had a mean long axis diameter of 15.2 mm (range 6-30).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15186594&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15186594&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
These data suggest that PET is useful in the evaluation of MPM, giving additional data that can clarify doubtful CT findings, especially regarding lymph node involvement and distant lesions.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15559064&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15559064&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
An encouraging 45% 5-year survival rate has been reported for patients with early-stage disease who undergo EPP and have the favorable features of epithelial histology and the absence of mediastinal lymph node involvement.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16007670&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16007670&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
To our knowledge, there have only been two reported cases in the literature where fine-needle aspiration (FNA) of a lymph node was the primary mode of diagnosis of malignant mesothelioma. […] We describe a 40-yr-old male in whom the primary diagnosis of malignant mesothelioma was made by FNA of a supraclavicular lymph node. […] Most patients with clinically documented lymph node metastases of malignant mesothelioma have had a previously established diagnosis of mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16035560&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16035560&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Whereas, findings for metastatic pleural disease were mediastinal/hilar lymph node enlargement and lung parenchymal involvement (P &amp;lt; .05).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16343925&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16343925&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The prognosis depends on the stage of the tumor at the time of diagnosis, its histological type, lymph node status, and resection margins. […] Multiple modality approach has demonstrated favorable outcome, particularly in patients with epithelial histology, negative resection margins and presence of no metastases to extrapleural lymph nodes.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16704740&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16704740&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Pleural effusions as well as lymph node metastases were observed only at later times.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17000285&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;17000285&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Recent studies suggest that standard uptake value on fluorodeoxyglucose positron emission tomography scan can predict mediastinal lymph node status in malignant pleural mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17198794&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;17198794&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The impact of lymph node metastasis on the site of recurrence and the role of mediastinoscopy in the selection of patients for extrapleural pneumonectomy, however, remain unclear. […] Survival was significantly worse for patients with N2 disease than for those with no lymph node metastasis (median survival 10 months vs 29 months, respectively, P = .005).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17659810&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;17659810&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Examination of associations between methylation levels of the 28 loci and clinical parameters suggest associations of the methylation status of metallothionein genes with gender, histology, asbestos exposure, and lymph node involvement, and the methylation status of leucine zipper tumor suppressor 1 (LZTS1) and SLC6A20 with survival.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17954021&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;17954021&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
CT tends to underestimate early chest wall invasion and peritoneal involvement and has well-known limitations in the evaluation of lymph node metastases.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18064685&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18064685&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Patients with malignant pleural mesothelioma and negative N2 stage lymph nodes may benefit from extrapleural pneumonectomy with adjuvant therapy. […] Six patients (mean age, 62 yr; median age, 63 yr; range, 52-70 yr; 5 men; 1 woman) underwent EUS-FNA for staging of N2 lymph nodes from July 2000 to July 2006. […] Eight sites were aspirated: four subcarinal lymph nodes, three aorto-pulmonary window lymph nodes, and one paraesophageal mass. […] A positive N2 lymph node by EUS-FNA may be a contraindication to definitive surgery in patients with malignant mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18077985&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18077985&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We report a follicular variant of papillary thyroid carcinoma (FVPTC), diagnosed on fine needle aspiration cytology (FNAC) of thyroid and lymph nodes and subsequently proved to have metastasized to the pleural cavity. […] FNAC of the thyroid swelling and the lymph nodes showed features of FVPTC with cervical lymph node metastasis. […] In our case, initial diagnosis of FVPTC could be made only on correlating FNA features of thyroid aspirate with those of lymph node aspirate.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18188517&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18188517&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Most common tumor entities were prostate cancer (n = 28), breast cancer (n = 17), gastrointestinal tumors (n = 19), pharyngeal carcinoma (n = 14), lymphoma (n = 13), metastatic disease (bone n = 14, liver n = 6, lung n = 4, lymph node n = 2), sarcoma (n = 8), malignant pleural mesothelioma (n = 5), ovarian cancer treated with whole abdominal irradiation (n = 4), lung cancer (n = 3), skin malignancies (n = 3), chordoma (n = 2), meningioma (n = 2), one ependymoma and one medulloblastoma treated with craniospinal axis irradiation (n = 2), and others (n = 4).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18248818&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18248818&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
One hundred and five patients were stage T4 and 92 patients presented with regional and mediastinal lymph node metastasis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18301236&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18301236&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM) is a rare cancer that metastasizes to mediastinal lymph nodes (MLNs). […] Subsequent fine needle aspiration of an enlarged cervical lymph node found an atypical mesothelial proliferation, and metastatic mesothelioma was strongly suspected. […] The mediastinal and cervical lymph node biopsies were reinterpreted as positive for MPM.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18338546&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18338546&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In particular it has been shown to be useful in the evaluation of the extent of pleural disease, in the establishment of lymph node involvement, in the evaluation of tumour invasion into the lung and thoracic wall, in the diagnosis of extrathoracic metastases, in the assessment of the response to treatment, and in planning radiotherapy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18449002&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18449002&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Eight patients had extrapleural lymph node involvement (internal mammary [n = 3], subcarinal [n = 2], pulmonary ligament [n = 1], diaphragmatic [n = 1], subaortic [n = 1]). […] There was better survival in patients without lymph node metastasis (24 versus 13 months median survival, p = 0.052). […] Trimodality treatment in malignant pleural mesothelioma seems to prolong survival in patients without lymph node metastasis. […] Novel techniques are needed for preoperative assessment of extrapleural lymph nodes.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18450462&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18450462&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In the preoperative workup for radical surgery for malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM), mediastinal lymph node staging, diagnostic pleural biopsies and effusion control with talc pleurodesis are required.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18829506&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18829506&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Because mediastinal lymph node (MLN) metastases are a negative prognostic factor, preoperative staging is of paramount importance. […] Thoracotomy with complete lymph node dissection was done in 17 (81%).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18854655&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18854655&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
AILT diagnosis was confirmed by thoracoscopic mediastinal lymph node and bone marrow biopsy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19260537&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;19260537&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Chest and abdominal CT after left chest drainage revealed left pleural thickening, mediastinal lymph node swelling, multiple lung nodules, osteolytic change of the left 4th rib, and multiple liver tumors.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19262009&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;19262009&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We reviewed FDG-PET/CT findings of primary tumors, recurrent tumors, lymph nodes, metastasis. […] Two of the 3 patients diagnosed as N0 by PET and operated on had negative lymph nodes confirmed pathologically. […] In 3 patients, hilar or mediastinal lymph nodes were difficult to distinguish from irregular pleural thickening. […] One patient had a FDG positive lymph node in the ipsilateral supraclavicular region confirmed as metastasis (N3). […] One patient had a FDG positive lymph node in the para-aortic region. […] FDG-PET/CT is useful for detecting distant metastasis and for evaluating activity in supraclavicular or abdominal lymph nodes.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19301253&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;19301253&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The right supraclavicular lymph node biopsy revealed a poorly differentiated carcinoma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19462642&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;19462642&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
A transcoelomic and local invasive growth pattern as well as lymph node metastases were noticed.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1953539&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;1953539&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Cytology and electronmicroscopy on material obtained by fine needle aspiration from his cervical lymph node revealed malignant mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19627545&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;19627545&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Reported herein is a case of malignant pleural mesothelioma, initially diagnosed on cervical lymph node biopsy. […] A neck mass was apparent and was identified pathologically as a lymph node metastasis of malignant mesothelioma. […] Two conclusions emerge from this report: (i) cervical lymph node metastasis of pleural mesothelioma, although rare, should be included in differential diagnosis; and (ii) positron emission tomography/CT is useful for establishing a diagnosis of mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19698846&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;19698846&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The prognostic factors included age, gender, side of disease, asbestos exposure, histology, positron emission tomography, date of surgery, neoadjuvant chemotherapy, completeness of cytoreduction, lymph node involvement, perioperative morbidity, adjuvant radiotherapy, and pemetrexed-based chemotherapy. […] Forty-four patients had no lymph node involvement. […] Asbestos exposure, negative lymph node involvement, and receipt of adjuvant radiation or postoperative pemetrexed-based chemotherapy were associated with improved survival on both univariate and multivariate analyses.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20021613&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;20021613&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Lymphatic involvement (confirmed on immunohistochemistry with D2-40 antibody) and lymph node metastasis were found in both of the invasive micropapillary-positive tumor patients, whereas they were noted in only one of 10 (10%, P &amp;lt; 0.046) and three of nine (30%) invasive micropapillary-negative patients.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20108310&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;20108310&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Comparisons of survival among patients with and without each tumor or lymph node feature guided adjustments to the American Joint Commission on Cancer (AJCC)/International Union Against Cancer (UICC) classification criteria.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20155346&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;20155346&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
With a diagnosis of primary lung cancer, right upper lobectomy and wedge resection of the right lower lobe with systematic lymph node dissection was performed using video-assisted thoracoscopic surgery.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20190476&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;20190476&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
A 74-year old man was admitted to our hospital with right diffuse pleural thickening and effusion and with subcarinal lymph node swelling. […] The effusion obtained by thoracentesis showed no malignant cells, although positron emission tomography showed abnormal uptake in the right pleural thickening and subcarinal lymph node. […] Histopathological examination of the lymph node specimens obtained by endobronchial ultrasound-guided transbronchial needle aspiration showed a sheet of epithelioid-like large atypical cells.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20371957&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;20371957&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Tumor recurrence was detected in the stomach due to vomiting of blood, and also spread to the mediastinal lymph node, and bone 3 months postoperatively.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20396658&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;20396658&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
It rarely metastasizes in peripheral lymph nodes. […] Here is a case report of malignant pleural mesothelioma without asbestos exposure with cervical lymph node metastasis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2047635&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2047635&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The suspected diagnosis of a malignant mesothelioma was confirmed by needle biopsy of a paraaortic lymph node.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21044972&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;21044972&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Lymph node metastases were detected with higher accuracy (80% vs. […] CT had a lower success rate (92% vs. 100%) than thoracoscopic pleural biopsy but was equivalent to MRI in terms of detection of lymph node metastases (P=0.85) and visceral pleural tumour (P=0.64).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21642867&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;21642867&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The proportion of CD4+ CD25+Foxp3+ Tregs, CD4+, and CD8+ T cells in the tumor, spleen, draining lymph node, and peripheral blood from tumor-bearing mice was determined by using flow cytometry, and gene expression of activated T-cell-related cytokines was quantified by enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay and reverse-transcribed polymerase chain reaction.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22024889&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;22024889&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
PET/CT also indicated metastasis in the lymph node in 7 patients (23%) and in the systemic lesions in 8 patients (26%) with MPM.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2246537&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2246537&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
On suspicion of lung tumor, right upper lobectomy and lymph node cleaning were performed.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22576637&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;22576637&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Extrapleural dissemination of tumor was found in 87.7% of cases and lymph node involvement in 53.3%.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22920171&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;22920171&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
After histological findings of the malignant mesothelioma of tunica vaginalis testis, he underwent left-side orchiectomy, followed by inguinal and pelvic lymph node dissection.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23135895&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;23135895&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
There were no significant differences regarding age, tumour stage, cell type or lymph node involvement.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23168556&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;23168556&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We discuss 2 cases in which the diagnosis of malignant pleural mesothelioma was made through flexible fiberoptic bronchoscopy with endobronchial ultrasound-guided mediastinal lymph node biopsy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23242984&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;23242984&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Histology, lymph node metastases, laterality and age had no significant impact on survival.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23434448&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;23434448&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The improved interval to recurrence and overall survival for the hyperthermic intraoperative cisplatin chemotherapy group were particularly evident among the subgroups of patients who had not received hemithoracic radiotherapy and who had pathologic stage N1 or N2 lymph node metastases.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2389813&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2389813&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The involved lymph nodes were cervical in four cases, mediastinal in one, and inguinal in one. […] When confronted with a lymph node involved by metastatic tumor, pathologists should be aware that malignant mesothelioma can present initially in the form of lymphadenopathy and include this possibility in the differential diagnosis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24142233&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;24142233&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We evaluated the role, as a prognostic factor, of the metastatic lymph node ratio (LNR), corresponding to the number of involved nodes out of the total number of removed nodes. […] Information regarding lymph node involvement was assessed from the final pathology reports. […] OS was not related to the number of involved or total removed lymph nodes. […] Metastatic LNR is a more reliable prognostic factor than the number of involved lymph nodes or the total number of removed nodes.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24281913&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;24281913&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
There were more positive lymph node cases in the infiltration group than in the non-infiltration group (p = 0.02).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24414726&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;24414726&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The extrapleural pneumonectomy technique consists of five basic steps: (1) Incision and exposure of the parietal pleura: (2) Dissection of the tumor and parietal pleura from the chest wall, diaphragm, and mediastinum: (3) Division and control of the pulmonary vessels and bronchus followed by lymph node dissection: (4) En bloc resection of the lung, pleura, pericardium, and diaphragm; (5) Reconstruction of the diaphragm and pericardium.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24482386&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;24482386&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
On univariate analysis, age at operation over 60 years (P = 0.044), pT4 stage (P = 0.041), any lymph node metastases (P = 0.002), biphasic cell type (P = 0.00) and no administration of chemotherapy (P = 0.00) were associated with decreased survival.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24515241&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;24515241&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Ultrasound-guided fine-needle aspiration (FNA) and core biopsies of the lymph node were diagnostic for pleural mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24583437&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;24583437&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In particular, tissue acquisition in cases of “dry” MPM (focal pleural thickening without pleural effusion or mediastinal lymph node involvement) is usually performed via a thoracoscopic pleural biopsy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25203873&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;25203873&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Outcome by pathologic lymph node status (N, median overall survival) was N0: 224, 26 months; N1: 118, 17 months; N2: 181, 13 months; N3: 5, 7 months; Nx: 1, not evaluable. […] This study confirms that lymph node status is significantly correlated with overall survival in patients with epithelioid MPM undergoing EPP and suggests that those with simultaneous involvement of N1 and N2 stations are at increased risk.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25310424&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;25310424&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
A staging system that focuses on the extent of primary tumor (T), lymph node involvement (N), and metastatic disease (M) has been devised by the International Mesothelioma Interest Group and emphasizes factors related to overall survival.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25453845&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;25453845&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The use of one-step nucleic acid amplification (OSNA), which allows for the rapid intraoperative detection of lymph node (LN) metastasis, is becoming more widely accepted in breast cancer.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26272336&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;26272336&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Pathological features such as depth of invasion, lymphocytic host response, mitotic count, nuclear grade, lymphovascular invasion, lymph node metastasis and stromal desmoplasia were analysed.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26281327&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;26281327&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
AMACR-positive and negative groups were similar for age, sex, smoking history, tumor diameter, lymph node involvement, differentiation, T-N factor, and stage.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26451268&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;26451268&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
A 60-year-old male patient presented to our clinic with shortness of breath and displayed bilateral pleural effusion and diffuse mediastinal lymph nodes in his computed chest tomography images. […] Perioperative samples were collected from the mediastinal lymph node. […] Mediastinal lymph nodes compressed the ductus thoracicus, resulting with chylothorax. […] The present case, with malignant mesothelioma, bilateral chylothorax, and mediastinal lymph node without any pleural involvement during initial diagnosis, is rare and will hence contribute to the literature.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26538423&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;26538423&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The allocation was stratified by centre, histology (sarcomatoid vs epithelioid or mixed), mediastinal lymph node involvement (N0-1 vs N2), and T stage (T1-2 vs T3).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26646473&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;26646473&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Chest, abdomen and pelvic computed tomography (CT) demonstrated only borderline lymphadenopathy in the left para-aortic lymph node chain that was hypermetabolic on positron emission tomography. […] Sampled left para-aortic lymph nodes were positive.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26770440&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;26770440&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Among 6 patients, pleural effusion (n = 4), mediastinal lymph node enlargement (n = 3), invasion and destruction of local ribs (n = 2).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27390546&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;27390546&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
76.6%, OR 0.445), hilar lymph node metastasis (5.8% vs. […] 20.3%, OR 0.243), mediastinal lymph node metastasis (10.7% vs.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27597274&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;27597274&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
However delaying chemotherapy until evidence of disease progression in patients with non-epithelioid disease had a detrimental effect on overall survival (OS), and on progression free survival (PFS) in lymph node positive patients (15.6 vs. […] Further analysis of 169 patients receiving platinum/pemetrexed as first line treatment, showed similar results; there was no effect of the timing of chemotherapy on OS or PFS (p=0.80 and p=0.53 respectively) and an improved OS in patients with non-epithelioid disease, and improved PFS in those with lymph node metastases, if chemotherapy was given in the immediate adjuvant setting (p=0.001 and 0.038) when therapy was not delayed until disease progression.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27670823&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;27670823&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
However, it has significant limitations, particularly with respect to clinical staging and to the categories for lymph node staging.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27698933&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;27698933&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
All statistical analyses were calculated with the R i386 statistical programming environment. &lt;i&gt;CDC25A&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;PARP1&lt;/i&gt; gene expression were correlated with lymph node spread, &lt;i&gt;BRCA1&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;TP73&lt;/i&gt; expression levels with higher IMIG stage. &lt;i&gt;NTHL1&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;XRCC3&lt;/i&gt; expression was associated with TNM stage. &lt;i&gt;CHECK1&lt;/i&gt; as well as &lt;i&gt;XRCC2&lt;/i&gt; expression levels were correlated with tumour progression in the overall cohort of patients. &lt;i&gt;CDKN2A&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;MLH1&lt;/i&gt; gene expression influenced overall survival in this collective.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27825687&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;27825687&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
For the 19 patients without lymph node metastases (74% stage III/IV, median tumor volume 325 mL), the median overall and disease-free survivals were 7.3 years and 2.3 years, respectively.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28130567&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;28130567&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Computed tomography and magnetic resonance imaging have an advantage in depicting the thickened pericardium, mediastinal lymph node, tumor, and the extension of adjacent structures.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28638620&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;28638620&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Our case demonstrates the utility of thoracic magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) and the difficulties associated with pleural cytology and cervical lymph node biopsy in the establishment of a diagnosis of mesothelioma. […] It is a reminder that mesothelioma can metastasize to mediastinal and cervical lymph nodes, can occur in young people, and may present as a chylothorax.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29050965&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;29050965&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Kaplan-Meier method was derived to examine the prognostic effects of tumor, lymph node, metastasis and histology features.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29059099&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;29059099&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Histological analysis of malignancy progression through immunohistochemical staining of the pleural, lymph node, and skin tissue revealed gradual loss of calretinin and gain of desmin, supporting a transformation from epithelioid to sarcomatoid tissue.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29118480&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;29118480&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Here, we report a case of malignant mesothelioma of pleura in a 65-year-old quarry worker where the initial diagnosis was offered by fine needle aspiration of an enlarged supraclavicular lymph node.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29179896&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;29179896&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Assessment of tumor extension and lymph node involvement is essential in imaging evaluation as locally advanced tumors are amenable to resection.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2918112&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2918112&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Distant metastases were found in the bronchial lymph node and bone marrow.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29355487&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;29355487&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
A 64-year-old man presented with a large amount of right-sided pleural fluid on imaging, together with calcified pleural plaques and an enlarged nodular structure in the prevascular mediastinum, presumably an enlarged lymph node.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29616420&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;29616420&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Many mesotheliomas without lymph node metastasis have been classified as stage IB in the eighth edition classification.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30121394&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30121394&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Surgical staging, including determination of the histologic subtype and lymph node status, as well as clinical staging with positron-emission tomography-computer tomography scan and determination of cardiopulmonary reserve are crucial.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30293912&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30293912&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
A lymph node biopsy was performed through mediastinoscopy in one case and yelded the diagnosis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30402386&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30402386&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
A fine needle aspirate of the lymph node and transbronchial biopsy specimen (TBBX) of the left lung infiltrate showed extensive reactive appearing mesothelial cells but none that appeared malignant. […] Repeat analysis of TBBX and lymph node specimens showed extensive reactive appearing mesothelial cells.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30407323&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30407323&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Positron emission tomography-computed tomography (PET/CT) examination showed “dirty” pleural and parietal pleural involvement as well as mediastinal and pulmonary hilar lymph node enlargement.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30533375&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30533375&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Chest computed tomography revealed a right mediastinal mass combined with an enlarged ipsilateral lymph node and left pleural effusion.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30719319&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30719319&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We first interpreted it as suspicious of primary lung adenocarcinoma with direct invasion to the right hilar lymph node. […] A right middle and lower lobectomy with partial resection of upper lobe was performed, and gross examination showed a hilar tumor lesion, involving the middle/lower lobe to hilar lymph node and looking whitish to yellow-grayish, partly adjacent to the right pulmonary artery.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30951250&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30951250&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In a training cohort of 828 cases, independent prognostic factors, including age, gender, histological type, differentiation, N stage, chemotherapy, type of surgery, and lymph node dissection, were identified.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30963005&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30963005&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Given poor survival of patients with malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM) and extrapleural nodal metastasis, pre-operative mediastinal lymph node (LN) staging has been advocated.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31064187&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;31064187&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
PET/CT scan revealed metastatic tumour spread with right-sided pleural thickening, multiple pulmonary tumour foci, mediastinal, cervical, abdominal para-aortic and pelvic lymph node involvement and skeletal metastasis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31634442&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;31634442&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Posterior intercostal lymph nodes, previously undescribed for cancer staging, are part of the lymphatic drainage of the pleural space. […] This study assessed the impact of posterior intercostal lymph nodes on survival in patients undergoing extended pleurectomy/decortication for malignant pleural mesothelioma. […] As part of the thoracic lymphadenectomy, posterior intercostal lymph nodes were accessed by incising the endothoracic fascia at the level of the rib heads. […] In 6 of 56 patients (11%), posterior intercostal lymph nodes were the only positive nodes, and overall, 48.2% had posterior intercostal lymph node metastases. […] Patients with N2 disease had significantly poorer prognosis if the posterior intercostal lymph nodes were involved: PFS (7.3 vs 14.9 months, P = .002) and OS (14.4 vs 26.1 months, P = .028). […] Metastases to posterior intercostal lymph nodes independently more than doubled the risk of progression and death and were the only site of nodal metastases in 11% of patients.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32042427&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;32042427&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Positron emission tomography staging demonstrated metastatic lung and lymph node involvement precluding surgical therapy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32057688&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;32057688&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Lymph node (LN) involvement is a poor prognostic factor for malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/3802946&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;3802946&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Diffuse malignant mesothelioma was diagnosed by axillary lymph node biopsy in a patient with brief asbestos exposure and extensive pleural masses. […] The clinical, radiographic and pathologic findings of this case are reported and lymph node involvement in DMM is briefly discussed.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/7771878&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;7771878&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The other biopsies, bronchial, lymph node, pleural and bone marrow also provided valuable diagnostic information.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8056229&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;8056229&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Of the latter, causes of ascites had already been identified in 13 (72.2%), including chronic renal failure in 7, systemic lupus erythematosus in 2, constrictive pericarditis in 2, chronic pancreatitis with chylous ascites in 1, and retroperitoneal lymph node metastasis with chylous ascites in 1.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9291544&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;9291544&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
A woman who at the age of 47 years underwent extrapleural pneumonectomy for malignant pleural mesothelioma with metastasis to an infradiaphragmatic lymph node is alive and well 63 months later.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9341263&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;9341263&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Left pleuropneumonectomy with mediastinal lymph node dissection was performed. […] Pleuropneumonectomy and systematic lymph node dissection of the pulmonary hilum and mediastinum were believed to be necessary for the surgical treatments.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9563782&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;9563782&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We report six cases of hyperplastic mesothelial cells located in the sinuses of lymph nodes. […] All patients but one had a concurrent serosal fluid collection (two pericardial, two pleural, one abdominal) at the time of the lymph node biopsy. […] Four cases were associated with vascular prominence of the involved nodal sinuses, a feature that may reflect the cause of the underlying effusion or support the transient persistence of benign mesothelial cells in lymph nodes. […] The differential diagnosis includes metastatic carcinoma, keratin-positive dendritic cells native to lymph nodes, and metastatic malignant mesothelioma. […] Because the latter shares both clinical and morphological features with cases of benign mesothelial cells in lymph nodes, we believe that this distinction may not always be possible in a given biopsy specimen and therefore that careful clinical follow-up is required in such cases.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9743156&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;9743156&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Hypermetabolic lymph node involvement was noted on FDG-PET images in 12 patients, 9 of which appeared normal on CT scans.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
