<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mesothelioma</title>
    <link>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/ovary/</link>
      <atom:link href="/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/ovary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>mesothelioma</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>BioHub - UFPE</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/mesothelioma/images/icon_hu3365e08ad5ef6cb6d886bc511b9ad2b3_313689_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>mesothelioma</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/ovary/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>ovary</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/ovary/info/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/ovary/info/</guid>
      <description> 

&lt;script src=&#34;/mesothelioma/mesotheliomarmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;div id=&#34;tissue-sentence-context&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tissue Sentence Context&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;font-size:12px&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Table 1.&lt;/strong&gt; Analysis of context sentence of &lt;em&gt;ovary&lt;/em&gt; tissue in 42 abstracts.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;table table-striped&#34; style=&#34;width: auto !important; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
PMID
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
Senteces
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10931239&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;10931239&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Primary mesotheliomas of the tunica vaginalis and ovary comprised 0. 09% (10 cases) and 0.03% (three cases) of mesothelioma deaths, respectively.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11954027&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;11954027&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In assessment of effusion specimens with metastatic carcinoma, nuclear reactivity for WT1 is highly suggestive of an ovary primary tumor
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12216539&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;12216539&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The first manifestation of malignancy may be an effusion of the pleural, pericardial, or peritoneal cavity, especially in carcinoma of the ovary, or lung, and malignant mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12662014&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;12662014&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Certain cancers such as cancers of the breast, ovary, lung, and stomach have a predilection for the pleural mesothelium.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1376598&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;1376598&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Histological differentiation between papillary mesotheliomas, primary ovarian tumors, borderline tumors of the ovary with peritoneal deposits and primary peritoneal carcinoma may be difficult.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1418272&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;1418272&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The malignant effusions in 19 patients were secondary to carcinoma of the breast (5), lung (5), ovary (1), endometrium (1), mucinous carcinoma of the colon (1), unknown primary (1), extraovarian papillary carcinoma (1), mesothelioma (2) and large cell lymphoma (2).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15098252&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15098252&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Although to the authors’ knowledge their presence in certain neoplasms (e.g., those of the thyroid, ovary, lung, brain, etc.) is established, their significance in BCF has not been well defined. […] All 11 cases of pleural and pericardial effusions with PBs were malignant (carcinomas of the thyroid, lung, and ovary) compared with 62 of 112 peritoneal fluid samples (55.4%) (carcinoma of the ovary and uterus and mesothelioma).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1569770&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;1569770&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Eighteen patients had lung carcinoma, two had mesothelioma, and one each had carcinoma of the ovary, breast, or anorectum, multiple myeloma, schwannoma, or Hodgkin’s lymphoma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17536770&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;17536770&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
MN/CA9 gene expression was detected in 53/59 (89.8%) pleural effusions from cancer patients (15/16 for breast cancers, 10/11 for lung cancers, 4/4 for ovary cancers, 2/3 for colon-rectal cancers, 5/6 for cancers of unknown site, 7/8 for mesothelioma and 10/11 for other cancers).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17916095&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;17916095&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The adenocarcinomas included metastatic carcinomas from the breast (12), lung (19), stomach (3), colon (1), pancreas (2), ovary (6) endometrium (1) and 23 histologically confirmed metastases from unknown primary sites. […] Six (9%) adenocarcinomas were positive, including metastases from the lung (1), breast (1), ovary (2) and unknown primary site (2).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18202798&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18202798&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We selected 16 cases of reactive mesothelio, 7 of normal mesothelio, 14 of lung adenocarcinoma, 9 from the ovary, 4 from the gastrointestinal tract and 3 from the breast.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18298385&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18298385&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Tumor cells in effusions most frequently originate from primary carcinomas of the ovary, breast, and lung, and from malignant mesothelioma, a native tumor of this anatomic site.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18480485&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18480485&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The imaging features of primary serous papillary carcinoma of the peritoneum resemble those of peritoneal carcinomatosis; however, the ovary is usually of normal size.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20146302&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;20146302&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The one positive case of ovarian adenocarcinoma showed a weak membranous podoplanin immunostaining.On the basis of our results and published data, we believe that membranous podoplanin immunoreactivity, in conjunction with calretinin, would be more specific than CK5/6 and WT-1 in differentiating epithelioid malignant mesothelioma from adenocarcinoma of the lung, breast, and ovary.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23174177&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;23174177&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Growth of a variety of in vitro established cell lines, including a hyperthermia-sensitive Chinese hamster ovary (CHO)-K1 cell line, a normal lung fibroblast line (MRC-5), a lung cancer line (A549), and 3 human mesothelioma cell lines (NCI-H28, NCI-H2052, and MSTO-211H), was assessed using a novel tetrazolium compound (3-(4,5-dimethylthiazol-2-yl)-5-(3-carboxymethoxyphenyl)-2-(4-sulfophenyl)-2H-tetrazolium, inner salt [MTS]) and an electron coupling reagent (phenazine methosulfate), which measures the absorbance at 490 nm of a formazan product reduced from MTS by living cells (MTS metabolic assay), or a standard dilution clonogenic assay, which enumerates colony-forming units of more than 50 cells.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2328062&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2328062&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
To evaluate the usefulness of immunohistochemistry in the diagnostic distinction between pleural mesothelioma and metastatic adenocarcinoma to the pleura, the authors studied formalin-fixed paraffin-embedded tissue sections from 14 pleural mesotheliomas and 20 primary adenocarcinomas of the lung, stomach, ovary and breast by using 16 commercially available antibodies to cytokeratin (KL1), vimentin, EMA, CEA, CA19.9, CA125, Egp 34 (detected by HEA 125), secretory component, S100 protein, SP1-béta 1, Leu M1, alpha-1-AT, alpha-1-ACT, lysozyme, desmin and factor VIII. […] Interestingly, two adenocarcinomas (of the ovary and the stomach) that failed to stain for CEA, were immunoreactive to anti-CA 19.9 antibody.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23475537&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;23475537&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration is most commonly associated with malignancies of the ovary, breast and lung.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23636867&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;23636867&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
All malignant cases were metastatic adenocarcinomas except for three high grade neuroendocrine carcinomas (two lungs and one ovary), one cervical squamous cell carcinoma, and one epithelioid endometrial stromal sarcoma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2423390&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2423390&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We have found that metastatic adenocarcinoma cells from breast, ovary, endometrium, cervix, colon and stomach, as well as squamous cell carcinomas and malignant mesothelioma stain specifically with antibodies to cytokeratin while mesenchymally derived tumors such as malignant lymphomas, malignant melanomas, and fibrosarcomas, are positive for vimentin only.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24968910&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;24968910&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The diseases which international scientific literature indicates as associated with asbestos exposure were taken into consideration: mesothelioma of pleura, peritoneum, pericardium and tunica vaginalis testis, malignant neoplasm of larynx, malignant neoplasm of trachea, bronchus and lung, malignant neoplasm of ovary, pneumoconiosis; moreover, in order to describe the health profile of the study population, large groups of diseases were taken into consideration.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25599121&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;25599121&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
No immigrant groups had an increased risk of breast, uterus, ovary, and prostate cancers or nervous system tumors.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26022455&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;26022455&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
BAP1 stain also showed utility in the differential of mesothelioma from most common pleural and peritoneal mimickers, such as lung and ovary carcinomas, with specificity and sensitivity of 99/70% and 100/70%, respectively.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26023052&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;26023052&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The additional histopathological detection of TISMO fibers in the liver, spleen, kidneys, ovary, heart, bone marrow, and brain of TISMO-infused mice indicated migration of the fibers out from the thoracic cavity.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26645426&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;26645426&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In PC, tumor origins were ovary in 10, digestive system in 21, breast in one.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26822071&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;26822071&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Finally, new cancers (larynx and ovary) were recently added to the list of asbestos-induced tumors.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26932246&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;26932246&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Other rare neoplasms composed of clear cells must be considered in the differential diagnosis such as yolk sac tumour of the ovary, clear cell subtype of endometrial carcinoma and, less frequently, malignant peritoneal mesothelioma as well as metastatic renal cell carcinoma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2707793&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2707793&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The tumors were located in the mesosalpinx, left pelvis, omentum, and/or surface of the ovary.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27813512&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;27813512&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
All 11 of these cases demonstrated loss of BAP1 nuclear staining by immunohistochemistry, whereas two tumors without BAP1 alteration and all 42 cases of histologic mimics in peritoneum (8 multilocular peritoneal inclusion cyst, 6 well-differentiated papillary mesothelioma of the peritoneum, 16 adenomatoid tumor, and 12 low-grade serous carcinoma of the ovary) demonstrated intact BAP1 nuclear staining.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28775133&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;28775133&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Asbestos is a known human carcinogen, with evidence for malignant mesothelioma (MM), cancers of lung, ovary, larynx and possibly other organs. […] The study confirmed the increased risk for cancer of the lung, ovary, pleura and peritoneum but not of the larynx and the digestive tract.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/3041546&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;3041546&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
A panel of 13 mouse monoclonal antibodies (mAb) and 1 rabbit polyclonal antibody was tested for reactivity with tumor cells in 26 effusions obtained from patients with carcinoma of ovary, breast, or mesothelioma, using an immunoperoxidase staining reaction.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30880313&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30880313&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Furthermore, 8, 23, and 30 strains also produced cytotoxic metabolites against SKOV-3 (human ovary adenocarcinoma) , MESO-1 (human malignant pleural mesothelioma) , and Jurkat cells (immortalized human T lymphocyte) .
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30911616&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30911616&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Accumulation of a malignant effusion in the pleura, peritoneum or pericardium is often the first diagnostic material for both primary malignant mesothelioma and a broad spectrum of metastatic adenocarcinoma originating from lung-, breast-, ovary- and gastro-intestinal organs as well as lymphoma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/3093540&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;3093540&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
All the tumours derived from coelomic surfaces (mesotheliomas of pleura, peritoneum, and ovary, and adenomatoid tumour of epididymis) reacted with the antibody.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31391078&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;31391078&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Considering asbestos related diseases (ARDs), statistically significant excesses were observed for MN of peritoneum (SMR: men 14.19; women 15.14), pleura (SMR: 22.35 and 48.10), lung (SMR: 1.67 and 1.67), ovary (in the highest exposure class SMR 2.45), and asbestosis (SMR: 507 and 1023).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/3311665&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;3311665&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
These showed metastatic carcinoma in 38 cases (ovary, 14; lung, 8; breast, 7; GI, 4; endometrium, 4; bladder, 1) and mesothelial processes in 13 (hyperplasia, 9; mesothelioma, 4).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/3461648&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;3461648&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Since exfoliated cells of malignant mesotheliomas were thought to have nuclear profile contours with greater irregularity than the similar profiles in metastatic adenocarcinoma cells in pleural effusions, this and other nuclear parameters were measured in ultrastructurally examined preparations from three cases of reactive mesothelial hyperplasia, seven examples of diffuse mesothelioma and three cases of metastatic adenocarcinoma (with primaries in the ovary, esophagus and prostate).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/4067615&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;4067615&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The primary malignancy included lung in 15 patients, breast in two patients, and carcinoma of the stomach, ovary, pleural mesothelioma, chronic granulocytic leukemia, and adenocarcinoma of unknown primary in one patient each.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/7728570&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;7728570&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Twelve of the patients had carcinoma of the breast, five carcinoma of the lung, and four carcinoma of the ovary.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8187591&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;8187591&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Of 40 metastatic AC originating from breast, gastrointestinal tract, ovary, endometrium, and kidney, 80% were Ber-EP4+.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8328242&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;8328242&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In females, however, cancers of the ovary were discovered only cytologically in about two-thirds of cases.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8536224&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;8536224&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Pleural and ascitic fluids (PAF) are complications of both nonmalignant and malignant conditions, such as congestive heart failure and chronic infections, as well as neoplasias, such as mesothelioma, lymphoma, and adenocarcinomas of the lung, ovary, endometrium, breast, colon, stomach, and pancreas.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9072005&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;9072005&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
WT1 immunoreactivity was absent in all primary tumours of lung and in pleural metastases from adenocarcinomas of breast and colon; immunoreactivity was present in pleural metastases from renal carcinomas, melanomas, and papillary carcinomas of the ovary.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
