<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mesothelioma</title>
    <link>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/prostate/</link>
      <atom:link href="/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/prostate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>mesothelioma</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>BioHub - UFPE</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/mesothelioma/images/icon_hu3365e08ad5ef6cb6d886bc511b9ad2b3_313689_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>mesothelioma</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/prostate/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>prostate</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/prostate/info/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/prostate/info/</guid>
      <description> 

&lt;script src=&#34;/mesothelioma/mesotheliomarmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;div id=&#34;tissue-sentence-context&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tissue Sentence Context&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;font-size:12px&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Table 1.&lt;/strong&gt; Analysis of context sentence of &lt;em&gt;prostate&lt;/em&gt; tissue in 34 abstracts.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;table table-striped&#34; style=&#34;width: auto !important; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
PMID
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
Senteces
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11517828&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;11517828&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
A rare case of malignant mesothelioma of the tunica vaginalis testis, observed in a patient affected by prostate neoplasm is reported. […] A radical retropubic prostatectomy was performed. […] A radical prostatectomy was carried out and histology showed an adenocarcinoma, Gleason score 7 pT3bN0M0.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11826504&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;11826504&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
They include treatment of solid tumors with cycloplatam alone in urinary bladder tumors, cervical carcinoma and malignant pleurites of various etiology as well as in combination with other cytostatics (carcinoma of the prostate, pleural mesothelioma and urinary bladder tumors).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16162739&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16162739&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Twenty-eight patients had other types of tumors, including renal cell carcinoma, ovarian carcinoma, GI tumors, prostate, malignant lymphoma, and unknown primary cancer.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16174663&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16174663&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We observed a lower mortality rate of prostate cancer [standardized mortality ratio = 0.79, 95% confidence interval (CI) 0.43-1.32], but a higher incidence rate of prostate cancer [standardized incidence ratio (SIR) = 1.22, 95% CI 1.00-1.48]. […] The higher incidence rates of prostate cancer are not readily explainable but may reflect increased screening among current employees and recent retirees.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16612848&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16612848&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The primary tumor was: lung-63 (46%), breast-26 (19%), mesothelioma-21 (15.5%), stomach-3, ovarian-3, prostate-3, colon-2, lymphoma-1, leukemia-2, plasmocytoma-1 and unknown primary tumor in 11 cases (8%).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17455866&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;17455866&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The most frequent additional malignancies were prostate adenocarcinoma (7 cases), non-Hodgkin lymphoma or chronic lymphocytic leukaemia (5 cases), bladder carcinoma (4 cases), kidney carcinoma (4 cases), large bowel carcinoma (4 cases), and liver cell carcinoma (4 cases).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18188517&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18188517&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Most common tumor entities were prostate cancer (n = 28), breast cancer (n = 17), gastrointestinal tumors (n = 19), pharyngeal carcinoma (n = 14), lymphoma (n = 13), metastatic disease (bone n = 14, liver n = 6, lung n = 4, lymph node n = 2), sarcoma (n = 8), malignant pleural mesothelioma (n = 5), ovarian cancer treated with whole abdominal irradiation (n = 4), lung cancer (n = 3), skin malignancies (n = 3), chordoma (n = 2), meningioma (n = 2), one ependymoma and one medulloblastoma treated with craniospinal axis irradiation (n = 2), and others (n = 4).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18922905&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18922905&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Our previous study suggested that REIC/Dkk-3-induced apoptosis mainly resulted from phosphorylation of c-Jun-NH(2) kinase (JNK) in prostate cancer cells.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20104527&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;20104527&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Several tumours are arginine auxotrophic, due to variable loss of ASS1, including hepatocellular carcinoma, malignant melanoma, malignant pleural mesothelioma, prostate and renal cancer.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20122610&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;20122610&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The significant factors of the EM in the univariate analysis were the presence of high-risk tumors (lung, stomach, soft tissue, bladder, esophagus, prostate, cervix, and lymphoma), the low Karnofsky performance score (KPS) (p&amp;lt;0.0001), the low pH value of the fluid (p=0.05), and the low concentration of glucose (p=0.01), total protein (p&amp;lt;0.0001), and albumin (p&amp;lt;0.0001) in the fluid.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20657552&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;20657552&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Increased expression of CD146, a cell adhesion molecule, has been reported to be closely associated with an advanced stage of malignant melanoma, prostate cancer, and ovarian cancer.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21226671&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;21226671&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Ongoing clinical trials evaluate dasatinib in the treatment of several solid tumours, including gastrointestinal stromal tumours (GIST), prostate cancer, malignant pleural mesothelioma, sarcomas, NSCLC, colorectal cancer, glioblastoma and other haematologic malignancies as multiple myeloma. […] In respect of these encouraging studies investigating dasatinib in the treatment of patients with GIST, prostate cancer, multiple myeloma and sarcomas, ongoing phase III clinical trials warrant the drug evaluation as recommended agent for the treatment of these diseases, also in association with chemotherapy or other targeted therapies.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21636653&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;21636653&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The diagnoses in group II included lung cancer (20), breast cancer (11), colon cancer (5), prostate cancer (2), B-cell lymphoma (2), and mesothelioma (1).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21816418&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;21816418&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Although still controversial, statins may decrease the risk of certain cancers such as colon cancer, lung cancer, and prostate cancer.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21997759&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;21997759&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In this review we summarize recent clinicopathological studies that have investigated periostin expression in lung, kidney, prostate, liver cancer, and malignant pleural mesothelioma and discuss the role of periostin isoforms in tumorigenesis and their potential as targets for stroma-targeted anticancer therapy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22380362&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;22380362&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Three-field plans for a nasopharynx case, two-field plans for a prostate case, and two-field plans for a malignant pleural mesothelioma case are considered in our analysis. […] For the prostate patient, the best grid is 4, 4, 5, 5, and 5 mm for σ = 3, 4, 5, 6, and 8 mm, respectively. […] Beams with σ &amp;gt; 3 mm did not satisfy our first clinical requirement that 95% of the prescribed dose is delivered to more than 95% of prostate and proximal seminal vesicles PTV. […] For the clinical cases, protocol and optimization used in this analysis, acceptable σs are ≤ 4 mm for the head and neck tumor, ≤ 3 mm for the prostate tumor and ≤ 6 mm for the malignant pleural mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22814683&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;22814683&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The birthplaces of patients with MM or PPs (cases) and patients with prostate or breast cancer (control subjects), diagnosed between 2000 and 2010 and identified through a mandatory cancer registry or from hospital records (PPs), were located on a geologic map, and the nearest distance to ophiolites was measured. […] Patients with MM (n = 100) or PPs (n = 133) were born significantly nearer to ophiolites (median distance, 4.5 km for men, 0 km for women) than were patients with prostate cancer (n = 161) or breast cancer (n = 139) (median distance, 20 km for both). […] ORs were 1.6 (men) ( P &amp;lt; .001) and 2.0 (women) ( P &amp;lt; .001) for every 5-km decrease in the distance of birthplace to ophiolites for MM, compared with prostate and breast cancer, respectively.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23791657&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;23791657&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In the panel of miR-183 family members’ expression analysis, colorectal cancer and prostate cancer ranked at the top among consistently reported cancer types with up-regulated feature.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25532843&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;25532843&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
HUHS1015 induces cell death in a wide variety of human cancer cell lines originated from malignant pleural mesothelioma, lung cancer, hepatoma, gastric cancer, colorectal cancer, bladder cancer, prostate cancer, and renal cancer.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25599121&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;25599121&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
No immigrant groups had an increased risk of breast, uterus, ovary, and prostate cancers or nervous system tumors. […] The HRs for prostate cancer were 0.6 in Turks, Middle Easterners, Asians, and Chileans. […] Middle Easterners, Asians, and Chileans, with the lowest risk of prostate cancer, also had the most favorable survival, suggesting a biological mechanism for this finding.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27040844&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;27040844&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Three patients also had a history of prior malignancy (1 with testicular seminoma and bladder carcinoma and 2 with prostate carcinoma).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27133741&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;27133741&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Previous reports in gliomas, colon, breast and prostate cancer suggest that PTEN/PI3K pathway may be important for the induction of PD-L1 expression.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27391431&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;27391431&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
HMGB1 overexpression was significantly associated with poorer OS (HR: 1.99; 95% CI, 1.71-2.31) and PFS (HR: 2.26; 95% CI, 1.65-3.10) irrespective of cancer types including gastric cancer, colorectal cancer, hepatocellular carcinoma, pancreatic cancer, nasopharyngeal carcinoma, head and neck squamous-cell carcinoma, esophageal cancer, malignant pleural mesothelioma, bladder cancer, prostate cancer, and cervical carcinoma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29260910&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;29260910&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The rs9939609 polymorphism in the FTO gene has recently been implicated as a risk factor for some types of cancer, such as breast, pancreatic, and prostate cancers.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30157910&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30157910&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
These have been investigated in the past in various cancers such as breast, prostate and colon.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30678439&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30678439&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Twenty-nine cases (43.5%) were classified as carcinoma not otherwise specified.Pulmonary small cell carcinoma/squamous cell carcinoma and metastatic colon, prostate, and liver carcinoma were notidentified among the cases.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30975761&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30975761&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
For patients with breast, ovarian, or prostate cancers, overall survival is associated with increased sensitivity to platinum chemotherapy due to loss-of-function mutations in DNA repair genes.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31032152&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;31032152&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Our case involves a 75-year-old Caucasian male with a past medical history of essential hypertension, remote prostate cancer status post prostatectomy, and lifetime nontobacco use presenting with progressive shortness of breath over one month.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31316876&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;31316876&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Pleural mesothelioma and carcinoma prostate as metachronous double malignancy is extremely rare co-occurrence. […] A 67-year-old male, diagnosed case of carcinoma prostate with bone metastasis, was treated with chemotherapy and hormone therapy. […] He remained asymptomatic for two years with serum prostate-specific antigen (PSA) values within normal limits. […] After two years of diagnosis of carcinoma prostate, he developed left lung pleural sarcomatoid mesothelioma as a second metachronous tumor. […] Malignant pleural mesothelioma as a metachronous second tumor in a case of carcinoma prostate is rarely reported in the literature. […] The long-life expectancy, old age, late effects of the treatment, genetic predisposition and lifestyle factors of patients with carcinoma prostate expose them to the possibility of developing second primary tumor.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31977466&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;31977466&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We present the case of a 69-year-old man with history of prostate carcinoma treated with prostatectomy and subsequently with external beam radiotherapy and hormone therapy because of biochemical recurrences. […] Our case report raises the association between prostate cancer patients treated with external beam radiotherapy and the development of pleural mesothelioma despite having no history of exposure to asbestos.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/3461648&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;3461648&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Since exfoliated cells of malignant mesotheliomas were thought to have nuclear profile contours with greater irregularity than the similar profiles in metastatic adenocarcinoma cells in pleural effusions, this and other nuclear parameters were measured in ultrastructurally examined preparations from three cases of reactive mesothelial hyperplasia, seven examples of diffuse mesothelioma and three cases of metastatic adenocarcinoma (with primaries in the ovary, esophagus and prostate).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/428920&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;428920&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
These were metastases from carcinoma of the prostate (two cases), melanoma (two cases), bronchial carcinoma (one case) and pleural mesothelioma (one case).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/7573365&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;7573365&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We demonstrate potential applications of these novel approaches by evaluating: 1) significance of normal karyotypes in malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors; 2) p15/p16 copy number in prostate cancer; and 3) clonal chromosome 3p deletion in cytological preparations of pleural fluid from patients with mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8230825&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;8230825&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The primary tumor site could be identified in 20 patients (74%), consisting of 9 patients with lung cancer, 3 with prostate cancer, 3 with hepatoma, 2 with renal cancer, and one each with thyroid cancer, adrenal cancer, and pleural malignant mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
