<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mesothelioma</title>
    <link>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/bone_marrow/</link>
      <atom:link href="/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/bone_marrow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>mesothelioma</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>BioHub - UFPE</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/mesothelioma/images/icon_hu7e12209333f22d741aca7d462871821f_9877_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>mesothelioma</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/bone_marrow/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>bone marrow</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/bone_marrow/info/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/bone_marrow/info/</guid>
      <description> 

&lt;script src=&#34;/mesothelioma/mesotheliomarmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;div id=&#34;tissue-sentence-context&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tissue Sentence Context&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;font-size:12px&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Table 1.&lt;/strong&gt; Analysis of context sentence of &lt;em&gt;bone marrow&lt;/em&gt; tissue in 22 abstracts.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;table table-striped&#34; style=&#34;width: auto !important; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
PMID
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
Senteces
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10434546&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;10434546&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
A diagnosis of multiple myeloma was made on the basis of blood tests and bone marrow aspiration biopsy findings.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/11888966&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;11888966&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
No treatment-related mortality, renal dysfunction, bone marrow suppression, or infection occurred.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15816607&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15816607&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Tissues from bone marrow (involved with B-PLL) and from a peritoneal nodule (involved with mesothelioma) were examined for SV40 DNA using polymerase chain reaction (PCR): no SV40 DNA was detected.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16996165&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16996165&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Although many adverse events of pemetrexed, such as bone marrow suppression, have been reported, edema of the eyelid has been previously reported in only one case (0.2%, n=519), according to the Pemetrexed Clinical Investigator’s Brochure, April 2005 version.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17465208&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;17465208&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
It has been reported that a dose of 600 mg/m2 of pemetrexed showed toxicity to bone marrow and the gastrointestinal system. […] The aim of this investigation was to evaluate raloxifene (RAL) in combination with 5-fluorouracil (5-FU)/pemetrered multitargeted antifolate (MTA) to determine the most effective regimens and cellular mechanism of action to mitigate pemetrexed cytotoxicity in human bone marrow cells. […] The growth rate in MCF-7 in early RAL was 69 +/- 8.65% and late RAL was 36 +/- 4.6% of the control whereas in bone marrow early RAL was 78 +/- 8.65% and late RAL was 52 +/- 5.49% of the control. […] The late RAL exhibits significant protection against MTA cytotoxicity in bone marrow. […] This study suggests that sequence-dependent administration of RAL (5FU/MTA/RAL), in combination with 5-FU/MTA, protects against MTA toxicity in human bone marrow while maintaining the maximum inhibitory effect of pemetrexed in breast cancer.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18854655&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18854655&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Angioimmunoblastic T-cell lymphoma (AILT) is characterised by systemic disease usually presenting with generalised peripheral lymphadenopathy, hepatosplenomegaly, and bone marrow infiltration. […] AILT diagnosis was confirmed by thoracoscopic mediastinal lymph node and bone marrow biopsy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23684920&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;23684920&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Bone involvement usually means locally invasive disease and rarely bone marrow metastases. […] In this report we presented two patients with a mesothelioma and bone marrow metastases.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24567297&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;24567297&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Bone marrow-derived mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) home to and incorporate into tumour stroma, making them good candidates to deliver anticancer therapies.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25849448&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;25849448&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Immunohistochemical analysis showed tumor cells diffusely positive for cytokeratin 8/18 and calretinin and focally positive for cytokeratin 5/6 and Wilms’ tumor 1, e-cadherin, and human bone marrow endothelial-1.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26023052&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;26023052&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The additional histopathological detection of TISMO fibers in the liver, spleen, kidneys, ovary, heart, bone marrow, and brain of TISMO-infused mice indicated migration of the fibers out from the thoracic cavity.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26440572&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;26440572&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The aim of this study was to investigate the relationship between volume-based quantitative PET parameters and survival in patients with malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM) and to evaluate the potential value of bone marrow (BM) uptake in predicting prognosis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26635184&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;26635184&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Here we show that bone marrow-derived fibrocyte-like cells, defined as alpha-1 type I collagen-positive and CXCR4-positive cells, contribute to the acquired resistance to bevacizumab.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28153512&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;28153512&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Bone marrow mesenchymal stromal cells (BM-MSCs) were loaded with pemetrexed (PMX) and paclitaxel (PTX) according to a standardized procedure.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28870611&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;28870611&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In this first-in-man, open-label, dose-escalation phase 1 trial at three major cancer centres in Sydney (NSW, Australia), we recruited adults (aged ≥18 years) with a confirmed diagnosis of malignant pleural mesothelioma, measurable disease, radiological signs of progression after previous chemotherapy, Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group performance status of 0 or 1, life expectancy of 3 months or more, immunohistochemical evidence of tumour EGFR expression, and adequate bone marrow, liver, and renal function.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2912545&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2912545&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
As some tumors metastasize frequently to marrow we modified the clonogenic assay for human tumor cell growth by culturing tumor cells in the presence of human bone marrow stromal cells. […] In a bilayer soft agar assay, human tumor cells which had been passaged in nude mice were plated in the agar overlayer on an underlayer containing a suspension of trypsinized human bone marrow stromal cells. […] Growth of five fresh human tumor samples was similarly stimulated by the presence of human bone marrow stromal cells.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2918112&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2918112&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Distant metastases were found in the bronchial lymph node and bone marrow.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29607973&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;29607973&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
A 64-year-old man with the bone marrow metastasis due to malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM) was diagnosed with anemia, leukoerythroblastosis, thrombocytopenia, and lower back pain. […] A bone marrow biopsy demonstrated infiltrative malignant mesothelioma lesions in the bone marrow. […] The patient died within 15 days of the detection of the bone marrow involvement. […] Physicians should consider performing a bone marrow biopsy to diagnose bone marrow metastasis and treat patients with palliative chemotherapy at an earlier phase of the disease. […] To our knowledge, this is the first report of an MPM patient having bone marrow metastasis with anemia, leukoerythroblastosis, and thrombocytopenia.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/3317170&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;3317170&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
As a modification of the protocol originally published by Gottlieb, the interval between two cycles was extended to 4 weeks for better bone marrow regeneration and vincristine was given only once instead of twice per cycle.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/6269342&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;6269342&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Benign histiocytes in bronchial washings, neuroblastoma cells in a smear of bone marrow aspirate and lymphocytic lymphoma cells in spinal fluid had ruffled surfaces.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/7559738&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;7559738&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The carcinogenicity of thorium dioxide sol (Thorotrast), an X-ray contrast medium used in 1930-1955, in the liver and bone marrow has been established and agrees well with the effects of a high dosage of alpha radiation in the organs.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/7771878&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;7771878&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The other biopsies, bronchial, lymph node, pleural and bone marrow also provided valuable diagnostic information.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8133966&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;8133966&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
General autopsy showed wide-spread malignant pleural mesothelioma with metastases to the lung, liver and bone marrow.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
