<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mesothelioma</title>
    <link>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/epidermal/</link>
      <atom:link href="/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/epidermal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>mesothelioma</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>BioHub - UFPE</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/mesothelioma/images/icon_hu7e12209333f22d741aca7d462871821f_9877_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>mesothelioma</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/epidermal/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>epidermal</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/epidermal/info/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/mesothelioma/tissuepanel/epidermal/info/</guid>
      <description> 

&lt;script src=&#34;/mesothelioma/mesotheliomarmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;div id=&#34;cell-sentence-context&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cell Sentence Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;font-size:12px&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Table 1.&lt;/strong&gt; Analysis of context sentence of &lt;em&gt;epidermal&lt;/em&gt; tissue in 64 abstracts.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;table table-striped&#34; style=&#34;width: auto !important; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
PMID
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
Senteces
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10471051&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;10471051&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The oncogene product epidermal growth factor receptor (EGF-R), the tumour suppressor gene product p53 and anti-p53 antibodies are detectable in the serum of certain cancer patients.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12234991&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;12234991&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Approximately 70% of MPMs have high levels of expression of the epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR), and a subset of cell lines derived from MPM patients express both EGFR and transforming growth factor alpha, suggesting an autocrine role for EGFR in MPM. […] ZD1839 significantly inhibited epidermal growth factor-dependent cell signaling including phosphorylation of AKT and extracellular signal-regulated kinases 1 and 2 in all MPM cell lines.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12571809&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;12571809&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Novel targeted agents are also being tested in clinical trials among mesothelioma patients and include drugs inhibiting the vascular endothelial growth factor and its receptor, the epidermal growth factor receptor, and platelet-derived growth factor receptor.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/14976533&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;14976533&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We examined 24 peritoneal and nine pleural malignant mesotheliomas with a battery of immunohistochemical markers (cytokeratin AE1/3, calretinin, c-kit/CD117, desmin, epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR), estrogen receptors (ER), progesterone receptors (PR), MIB-1, and cleaved caspase-3) in an attempt to distinguish any differences in this tumor arising in these two distinct locations. […] The increased expression of EGFR in the peritoneal lesions may be of clinical significance with the recent emergence of epidermal growth factor receptor-targeted therapies.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15261433&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15261433&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Angiogenesis, tumour necrosis (TN), epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) expression, cyclooxygenase-2 (COX-2) and matrix metalloproteinases (MMPs) have been linked with poor prognosis in some types of solid tumour and their relevance as prognostic factors in malignant mesothelioma is examined in this paper.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15654178&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15654178&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
New directions in therapy include aggressive multimodality programs for potentially resectable patients and targeted therapies, including antifolates, antiangiogenesis agents, and drugs directed at epidermal growth factor receptor for the majority of patients presenting with unresectable disease.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15756029&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15756029&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Approximately 70% of malignant pleural mesotheliomas (MPM) overexpress epidermal growth factor receptors (EGFR) and a subset express both EGFR and transforming growth factor alpha (TGF-alpha), suggesting an autocrine role for EGFR in MPM.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15788680&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15788680&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The Cancer and Leukemia Group B conducted a phase II study of gefitinib, an inhibitor of the epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) tyrosine kinase, in patients with previously untreated malignant mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15835625&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15835625&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Inhibitors of angiogenesis and of epidermal growth factor are being tested, but they have shown only limited activity until now.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15867774&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;15867774&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Epidermal growth factor receptor expression has been observed on malignant pleural mesothelioma cells. […] Epidermal growth factor receptor-mediated signaling promotes tumorigenesis and metastasis of cancer cells. […] The purpose of this study is to evaluate the ability of the epidermal growth factor receptor tyrosine kinase inhibitor PD153035 to abrogate the expression of prometastasis phenotypes in malignant pleural mesothelioma cells in vitro. […] Epidermal growth factor receptor expression of malignant pleural mesothelioma cells and primary normal cells was quantitated by means of flow cytometry. […] Vascular epidermal growth factor levels in conditioned media were measured by using enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay. […] Epidermal growth factor receptor expression was detected on all 6 cultured malignant pleural mesothelioma cells, with 4 of 6 having normal receptor expression and 2 of 6 overexpressing the receptor. […] PD153035 suppressed cell motility and cell invasion through a Matrigel membrane, regardless of the baseline epidermal growth factor receptor expression. […] Decreased vascular epidermal growth factor production and significant inhibition of growth only occurred in malignant pleural mesothelioma cells that overexpress epidermal growth factor receptor. […] Epidermal growth factor receptor tyrosine kinase inhibitor PD153035 significantly inhibited motility and invasion in malignant pleural mesothelioma cells in vitro, regardless of their epidermal growth factor receptor expression levels. […] Inhibition of epidermal growth factor receptor-dependent signaling might be a useful strategy to diminish malignant pleural mesothelioma recurrence after aggressive cytoreductive surgery.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16020981&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16020981&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The majority of malignant pleural mesotheliomas (MPMs) aberrantly express the epidermal growth factor receptor (ErbB1).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16291431&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16291431&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Inhibitors of the epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) are one of many promising targeted therapies for non-small-cell lung cancer (NSCLC).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16384623&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16384623&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) is overexpressed in many epithelial malignancies, against which some antitumoral drugs have been developed.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17049671&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;17049671&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
This work evaluated expression in MM of Epidermal Growth Factor Receptor (EGFR) by immunohistochemistry in 168 tumour sections and its correlations with clinicopathological and biological factors.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17493236&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;17493236&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Yet neither the spectrum of tissue expression nor the signalling pathways of OPN in MM and pulmonary adenocarcinoma have been characterized, although in vitro evidence links OPN to the epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) pathway.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17557954&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;17557954&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM) expresses high levels of epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR), and preclinical studies have identified antitumor activity of EGFR tyrosine kinase inhibitors (TKIs) in MPM. […] Archived patient tumors were analyzed for immunohistochemical expression of EGFR, phospho-EGFR, human epidermal growth factor receptor 2 (HER2), phospho-extracellular signal-regulated kinase (ERK), and phosphatase and tensin homolog (PTEN) and phosphorylation of members of the phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase/Akt signaling pathway.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18048409&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18048409&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In this study, we assessed the expression of ILK in samples of human MPM, and compared it with the expression of epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18086752&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18086752&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) was expressed stronger in LTS whereas platelet derived growth factor receptor (PDGFR) signalling was more abundant in STS.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18392851&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18392851&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) is overexpressed in a variety of epithelial malignancies.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/1926758&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;1926758&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
An immunohistochemical study of the epidermal growth factor (EGF) receptor in non-neoplastic pleural mesothelium (35 cases) and in human malignant mesothelioma (36 cases) was made, using a murine monoclonal antibody OM-11-951.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19380521&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;19380521&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
To determine whether the lack of response of MET inhibitors was due to cooperation with other RTKs, we determined activation status of MET and other RTKs, including epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) family of 20 MPM cell lines, and tested whether dual RTK inhibition is an effective therapeutic strategy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19708533&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;19708533&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In this study, we compared Epidermal Growth Factor Receptor (EGFR) aberrations in malignant mesotheliomas to those in lung cancers, to determine whether gefitinib may be useful for treatment of a malignant mesothelioma.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19736192&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;19736192&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Novel agents in clinical trials include inhibitors of the epidermal growth factor receptor, vascular endothelial growth factor, mesothelin, and histone deacetylases.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19781955&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;19781955&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Herein, we correlated proteins of a putative MPM-EMT axis, including periostin, epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR), integrin beta1, phosphatase and tensin homologue (PTEN), integrin-linked kinase (ILK), p21 and p27, with clinico-pathologic parameters, in particular overall survival (OS).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19815709&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;19815709&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
A human mesothelial cell line (LP9/TERT-1) and isolated human pleural mesothelial cells showed rapid and protracted asbestos-induced cAMP response element binding protein (CREB1) phosphorylation, which was inhibited in LP9/TERT-1 cells by small molecule inhibitors of epidermal growth factor receptor phosphorylation and protein kinase A. […] These data indicate that CREB1 and its target genes are up-regulated in asbestos-exposed human mesothelial cells through an epidermal growth factor receptor/protein kinase A pathway.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19909234&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;19909234&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF) and platelet derived growth factor (PDGF) are autocrine growth factors in MPM and epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) appears highly expressed in this tumour.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20347505&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;20347505&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) is overexpressed in a variety of epithelial malignancies including lung cancer in which EGFR aberrations not only predict response to EGFR tyrosine kinase inhibitors but also indicate tumor progression.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21183281&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;21183281&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The epidermal growth factor receptor is frequently over-expressed in malignant pleural mesothelioma samples and therefore may be a potential therapeutic target.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21263312&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;21263312&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Although tyrosine kinase inhibitors directed against the epidermal growth factor and the platelet-derived growth factor receptors did not show significant clinical activity in phase II studies, some other targeted therapies seemed promising, notably histone deacetylase inhibitors and antiangiogenic agents.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21437912&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;21437912&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
To evaluate epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) phenotypic expression and related gene status in malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM) and to correlate the results with patients’ prognosis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21454801&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;21454801&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We hypothesized that normal human mesothelial cells acquire resistance to asbestos-induced toxicity via induction of one or more epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR)-linked survival pathways (phosphoinositol-3-kinase/AKT/mammalian target of rapamycin and extracellular signal-regulated kinase [ERK] 1/2) during simian virus 40 (SV40) transformation and carcinogenesis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21774103&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;21774103&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
MET and epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) mutations were screened by sequencing.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21787763&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;21787763&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Up-regulation of epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) plays an important role in MPM development and EGFR-tyrosine kinase inhibitors (TKIs) may represent novel therapeutic options.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/21970874&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;21970874&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Vandetanib significantly downregulated epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR)/Erk/Akt phosphorylation as well as E2F-1 mRNA and TS mRNA/protein levels.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22092406&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;22092406&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
CK5/6 and epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) immunostaining were performed on the calretinin-positive subset.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22199264&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;22199264&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Tumor sections were stained by immunohistochemistry for LAT1, glucose transporter 1 (GLUT1), GLUT3, hypoxia inducible factor-1α (HIF-1α), hexokinase I, vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF), microvessel density (MVD) by determination of CD34, epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR), phosphatase and tensin analog (PTEN), p-AKT, p-manmalian target of rapamycin (mTOR), p-S6K, p53 and BCL-2.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22330319&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;22330319&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Tumour sections were stained by immunohistochemistry for glucose transporter 1 (Glut1); glucose transporter 3 (Glut3); hypoxia-inducible factor-1 alpha (HIF-1α); hexokinase I; vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF); microvessels (CD34); epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR); cell proliferation (Ki-67 labelling index); Akt/mTOR signalling pathway (PTEN, p-Akt, p-mTOR and p-S6K); cell cycle control (p53 and pRb); apoptosis marker (bcl-2).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22412050&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;22412050&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) gene mutation at the kinase domain and EGFR gene amplification are reported to be predictors of the response to EGFR tyrosine kinase inhibitors in lung cancer cases.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22449226&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;22449226&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
An evaluation of epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) phenotypic expression in malignant pleural and peritoneal mesothelioma was undertaken, using immunohistochemical (IHC) and fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH) analysis.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22622048&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;22622048&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Epidermal growth factor (EGF), hepatocyte growth factor (HGF), vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF) and insulin-like growth factor (IGF) have been shown as targets for therapy based on promising preclinical data.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22866124&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;22866124&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
However, more specific diseases were tentatively identified as alopecias, urticarial vasculitis, acute generalized exanthematous pustulosis, toxic epidermal necrolysis, radiation recall dermatitis and pityriasis lichenoides.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22922885&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;22922885&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) is commonly overexpressed in malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23038233&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;23038233&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Toxic epidermal necrolysis (TEN) is an uncommon but life-threatening adverse drug reaction.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23329660&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;23329660&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
To evaluate the potential of anti-human epidermal growth factor receptor (HER)1- and anti-HER2-targeted radiolabeled antibodies and magnetic resonance (MR) imaging for imaging of orthotopic malignant pleural mesothelioma (MPM) in mouse models.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23558893&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;23558893&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
As epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) is involved in the pathogenesis of malignant pleural mesotheliomas (MPMs), the anti-EGFR drugs may be effective in treating MPM patients. […] Epidermal growth factor receptor gene mutations were sought by means of real-time polymerase chain reaction (PCR) and direct sequencing, KRAS gene mutations by mutant-enriched PCR, and PIK3CA and BRAF gene mutations by direct sequencing.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2372497&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2372497&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The expression of epidermal growth factor receptor (EGF-R) in 34 formalin fixed paraffin embedded specimens of malignant mesothelioma was examined using the F4 antibody.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23749888&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;23749888&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Epidermal growth factor receptor tyrosine kinase inhibitor (EGFR-TKI) has limited anticancer efficacy in EGFR-positive esophageal cancer (EsC) and malignant mesothelioma (MPM).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24148817&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;24148817&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Xenograft-bearing mice were treated with miR-16 mimic packaged in minicells targeted with epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR)-specific antibodies.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24233154&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;24233154&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Both malignant tumors expressed high levels of epidermal growth factor receptors (EGFR) detected by immunohistochemistry (IHC), with membranous staining on the majority of malignant cells corresponding to maximum IHC scores of 290 and 300, respectively, for the MM and the ACL.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2428981&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2428981&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
An enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA) for anti-keratin antibodies was prepared by coating microplates with epidermal keratin purified from the stratum corneum from human foot.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27032653&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;27032653&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Serum levels of soluble mesothelin-related peptide (SMRP), thioredoxin-1 (TRX), epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR), fibulin-3, syndecan-1 (SDC-1), and mesothelin were determined.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2790740&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2790740&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Growth kinetic studies in medium supplemented with epidermal growth factor (EGF) showed increased proliferation and a decreased proliferation in medium supplemented with hydrocortisone (HC) or EGF plus HC.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28337371&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;28337371&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
It has been reported that cellular-mesenchymal to epithelial transition factor (MET) and epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) were critical for MPM cell proliferation.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28545562&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;28545562&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
To investigate the mechanisms of sorafenib-mediated antiproliferative activity, TICs were treated with epidermal growth factor (EGF) or basic fibroblast growth factor (bFGF) causing, in MM3 and MM4 cells, MEK, ERK1/2, Akt, and STAT3 phosphorylation.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30226590&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30226590&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Furthermore, inhibition of activated epidermal growth factor (EGFR)-associated survival pathways enhance PDT efficacy.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30354850&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30354850&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Molecular testing must include, at least, mutations of epidermal growth-factor receptor and BRAF V600E, translocations of rat osteosarcoma and anaplastic lymphoma kinase, and expression of programmed death ligand 1.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30450291&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30450291&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
First-generation tyrosine kinase inhibitors against epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) did not show any significant activity in MPM.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30501113&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30501113&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Nimotuzumab (h-R3), an anti-EGFR (epidermal growth factor receptor) humanized antibody, is proposed as a promising agent for the treatment of MPM. […] The aim of this research was to implement a procedure for nimotuzumab radiolabeling to evaluate its biodistribution and affinity for EGF (epidermal growth factor) receptors present in a mesothelioma xenograft.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30916586&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;30916586&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) is known to be highly overexpressed in mesothelioma with reported EGFR overexpression between 44 to 97%.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31082996&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;31082996&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Similarly, in patients with advanced nonsmall cell lung cancer a comprehensive molecular testing on pleural fluid samples, which should include at a minimum epidermal growth factor receptor/v-raf murine sarcoma viral oncogene homolog B/anaplastic lymphoma kinase/reactive oxygen species 1/programmed death-ligand 1 alterations, is highly advocated to identify patients who may benefit from targeted therapies.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31495751&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;31495751&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
In theranostics, a vast amount of data has been reported regarding the epidermal growth factor receptor and related molecules.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32517259&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;32517259&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The multi-targeted inhibition of histone deacetylase (HDAC), HER2 and TGFα receptor (epidermal growth factor receptor/EGFR) improved treatment efficacy in vitro and reduced tumor growth in two MPM mouse models.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9072005&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;9072005&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Coordinate expression of the WT1 protein and its putative transcriptional target genes was determined by correlating WT1 immunostaining with epidermal growth factor receptor (EGF-R) and insulin-like growth factor 1 receptor (IGF-1R) expression on MM and NNM; no significant correlation was found, irrespective of p53 expression status.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9437800&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;9437800&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Similar to human mesothelial cells, growth of the murine cell lines was stimulated by epidermal growth factor.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
