<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mesothelioma</title>
    <link>/mesothelioma/drugpanel/fibronectin/</link>
      <atom:link href="/mesothelioma/drugpanel/fibronectin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>mesothelioma</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>BioHub - UFPE</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/mesothelioma/images/icon_hu3365e08ad5ef6cb6d886bc511b9ad2b3_313689_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>mesothelioma</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/drugpanel/fibronectin/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>FIBRONECTIN</title>
      <link>/mesothelioma/drugpanel/fibronectin/info/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/mesothelioma/drugpanel/fibronectin/info/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/mesothelioma/mesotheliomarmarkdown-libs/kePrint/kePrint.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;font-size:16px&#34;&gt;
DrugBank ID: &lt;a href=&#39;https://www.drugbank.ca/drugs/db15150&#39; target=&#39;_blank&#39;&gt;db15150&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
DrugCentral: &lt;a href=&#34;http://drugcentral.org/?q=fibronectin&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;fibronectin&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
Synonymous : &lt;em&gt;None&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;drug-sentece-context&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Drug Sentece Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;font-size:12px&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Table 1.&lt;/strong&gt; Analysis of context sentence of &lt;em&gt;fibronectin&lt;/em&gt; gene in 29 abstracts.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;table table-striped&#34; style=&#34;width: auto !important; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&#34;&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
pmid
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center;position: sticky; top:0; background-color: #FFFFFF;&#34;&gt;
sentence
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10373640&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;10373640&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Three human pleural malignant mesothelioma cell cultures (MM) of epithelioid (E1), fibrous (F1) and byphasic (B1) histotype were studied in their synthesis of the extracellular matrix (ECM) components laminin (LM), fibronectin (FN), type IV collagen (cIV), and in their chemotactic and haptotactic migration towards the ECM produced proteins.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16240402&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;16240402&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
The frequent expression of the alphaV and beta1 subunits support attachment to fibronectin and vitronectin as the major ECM ligands in body cavities.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24457449&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;24457449&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Positive expression of E-cadherin, γ-catenin, vimentin, fibronectin, Twist and YB-1 was observed in 25, 14, 21, 1, 19 and 18 patients, respectively.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26773069&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;26773069&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We used fibronectin (FN) or homologous cell-derived extracellular martrix (ECM) substratum to investigate the role of AQP1 in these experimental phenotypes, inhibiting AQP1 by 10(-5) M mercury chloride (MC).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26839306&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;26839306&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Immunohistochemical analyses revealed that vismodegib treatment primarily downregulated GLI1 and HHIP in the stromal compartment along with a reduced expression of previously described fibroblast Hh-responsive genes such as Fibronectin (Fn1) and Vegfa Primary cells isolated from the rat model cultured in 3% O2 continued to express Dhh but did not respond to vismodegib in vitro However, culture supernatant from these cells stimulated Gli1, Ptch1, and Fn1 expression in mouse embryonic fibroblasts, which was suppressed by vismodegib.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28476806&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;28476806&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Fibronectin and hepatocyte growth factor (HGF) were produced by lung fibroblasts. […] Exogenous fibronectin and HGF also enhanced the migration and invasion of the three MPM cells, respectively. […] In addition, the production of fibronectin and HGF was stimulated by MPM cell-derived media.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29303405&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;29303405&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Using the ECIS (Electric cell-substrate impedance sensing) system, we found that treatment of both PF compounds suppressed adherence and migration of PDAC cells on fibronectin.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/6421478&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;6421478&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
We have determined the amount of fibronectin in pleural fluids and plasma of 131 patients suffering from pleurisy of malignant and non-malignant etiology. […] We observed a significantly higher concentration of fibronectin in pleural fluids of a few patients with mesothelioma as compared with that found in pleural fluids of patients with pleurisies of different etiology. […] In these patients the pleural fluid fibronectin concentration was higher than that measured in plasma, suggesting local synthesis of fibronectin.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8364933&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;8364933&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
A human malignant pleural mesothelioma cell line (STAV) was studied with respect to production of the extracellular matrix components laminin, type IV collagen, and fibronectin, and interactions with these proteins in vitro. […] Using Western blotting we identified these proteins as laminin, type IV collagen, and fibronectin, respectively. […] By immunocytochemistry laminin, type IV collagen, and fibronectin were detected as a matrix surrounding the cells. […] Plastic culture dishes coated with microgram quantities of laminin, type IV collagen, and fibronectin induced attachment and spreading of STAV cells. […] Laminin, type IV collagen, and fibronectin stimulated directional (chemotactic) migration of STAV cells in Boyden chambers fitted with 8 microns filters.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8944724&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;8944724&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Little is known regarding fibronectin (Fn) function in mesothelial and mesothelioma cells.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9013837&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;9013837&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Notably, all malignant mesotheliomas (MM), including those with distinct glandular structures, expressed the alpha5 beta1 fibronectin receptor, thus paralleling most sarcomas and differing from PADC and most other ADC.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9212227&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;9212227&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
MC consistently adhered better than mesothelioma cells to laminin, tenascin, fibronectin and collagen type IV.
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9401361&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;9401361&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
Fibronectin concentrations both in plasma and pleural effusion were prospectively determined in 60 patients with exudative pleural effusions. […] Fibronectin concentrations in plasma and pleural fluid in 12 patients with infectious and exudative pleural effusions (mean +/- SD) were 240 +/- 103 and 212 +/- 115 micrograms.mL-1, in 17 patients with primary or metastatic lung carcinoma 242 +/- 104 and 210 +/- 82 micrograms.mL-1, in 13 patients with pleural tuberculosis 246 +/- 77 and 231 +/- 133 micrograms.mL-1, and in 18 patients with confirmed malignant pleural mesothelioma 261 +/- 119 and 276 +/- 188 micrograms.mL-1. […] There were no significant differences either in the plasma or serum concentrations of fibronectin between groups (p &amp;gt; 0.05). […] Although pleural fluid fibronectin content appeared to have high specificity (85%), it was found to be an inefficient biological marker for differentiating nonmalignant from malignant pleural effusions due to its low sensitivity (6%).
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
